<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>general on Newsround</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/tags/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Newsround</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://newsround.github.io/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Despite Greenland, France's Macron and NATO's head make nice with Trump behind the scenes - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/despite-greenland-frances-macron-and-natos-he/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/despite-greenland-frances-macron-and-natos-he/</guid><description>President Donald Trump has shared private messages from world leaders about Greenland, revealing softer tones behind public criticism. On Tuesday, Trump published a text from French President Emmanuel Macron, confirmed as genuine by the French leader&amp;rsquo;s office…</description></item><item><title>Letlow launches Trump-backed Senate bid against Cassidy - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/letlow-launches-trump-backed-senate-bid-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/letlow-launches-trump-backed-senate-bid-again/</guid><description>While Sen. Bill Cassidy has maintained he will win, Trump’s endorsement of Letlow is a particular blow.</description></item><item><title>Trump slams UK deal to hand over Chagos Islands after he previously backed it - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-slams-uk-deal-to-hand-over-chagos-islan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-slams-uk-deal-to-hand-over-chagos-islan/</guid><description>The British government is defending its decision to transfer sovereignty of the Chagos Islands to Mauritius after U.S. President Donald Trump criticized the move. Trump called it an act of stupidity on Tuesday, He argued that it weakens national security. He …</description></item><item><title>California wildfire smoke exposure during pregnancy linked to autism risk in children - NBC News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/california-wildfire-smoke-exposure-during-pre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/california-wildfire-smoke-exposure-during-pre/</guid><description>Pregnant women&amp;rsquo;s exposure to wildfire smoke — particularly in the third trimester — may increase the risk of autism in their children, according to new research.</description></item><item><title>DOJ civil rights chief blasts Don Lemon for covering anti-ICE protest inside church, vows charges against protesters - NBC News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/doj-civil-rights-chief-blasts-don-lemon-for-c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/doj-civil-rights-chief-blasts-don-lemon-for-c/</guid><description>The Justice Department &amp;ldquo;will pursue charges&amp;rdquo; related to a protest inside a St.</description></item><item><title>Israeli crews begin bulldozing headquarters of UN agency for Palestinian refugees in East Jerusalem - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/israeli-crews-begin-bulldozing-headquarters-o/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/israeli-crews-begin-bulldozing-headquarters-o/</guid><description>Israeli forces have targeted two United Nations facilities as part of their crackdown on the U.N. agency for Palestinian refugees. On Tuesday, crews bulldozed the United Nations Relief and Works Agency&amp;rsquo;s offices in Sheikh Jarrah and fired tear gas at a vocati…</description></item><item><title>Trump’s a T-Rex and ‘pathetic’ leaders need to confront him, rages California’s Newsom - politico.eu</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-a-t-rex-and-pathetic-leaders-need-to/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-a-t-rex-and-pathetic-leaders-need-to/</guid><description>Leading Democrat launches broadside at politicians who bow to Trump: “You mate with him or he devours you, one or the other, and you need to stand up to it.”</description></item><item><title>100 vehicles pile up in Michigan crash as snowstorm moves across the country - ABC News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/100-vehicles-pile-up-in-michigan-crash-as-sno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/100-vehicles-pile-up-in-michigan-crash-as-sno/</guid><description>More than 100 vehicles smashed into each other or slid off the interstate in Michigan as snow fueled by the Great Lakes blanketed the state</description></item><item><title>Britain approves ‘mega’ Chinese embassy in London despite national security fears - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/britain-approves-mega-chinese-embassy-in-lon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:21:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/britain-approves-mega-chinese-embassy-in-lon/</guid><description>Britain’s government has green-lit plans for China to build a “mega” embassy close to London’s financial district, despite warnings from lawmakers, residents and Chinese dissidents-in-exile that the sprawling complex could pose security risks.</description></item><item><title>Pardoned Jan. 6 rioter Andrew Johnson to face criminal trial for child molestation - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/pardoned-jan-6-rioter-andrew-johnson-to-face-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/pardoned-jan-6-rioter-andrew-johnson-to-face-/</guid><description>Andrew Johnson is the latest in a series of pardoned Jan. 6 riot defendants to face new criminal charges.</description></item><item><title>Private credit is Wall Street's hottest trade. Now it's coming for your 401(k) - Business Insider</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/private-credit-is-wall-streets-hottest-trade-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/private-credit-is-wall-streets-hottest-trade-/</guid><description>Wall Street giants like Apollo and Blackstone are all in on private credit — and it soon may end up in your retirement account.</description></item><item><title>Trump threatens 200% tariff on French wines as Macron reportedly snubs 'Board of Peace' seat - CNBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-threatens-200-tariff-on-french-wines-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:35:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-threatens-200-tariff-on-french-wines-a/</guid><description>Trump also reiterated his plans to control Greenland, saying that European leaders &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rsquo;t push back too much.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>In San Antonio, the nation's largest MLK march takes on added meaning - Texas Public Radio | TPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-san-antonio-the-nations-largest-mlk-march-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:41:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-san-antonio-the-nations-largest-mlk-march-/</guid><description>The nation’s largest Martin Luther King Jr. Day march carries special significance in San Antonio, where a small Black community helped build a tradition that now draws hundreds of thousands each year.</description></item><item><title>ICE Continues to Remove the Worst of the Worst from Minneapolis Streets as DHS Law Enforcement Marks 3,000 Arrests During Operation Metro Surge - Homeland Security (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ice-continues-to-remove-the-worst-of-the-wors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:50:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ice-continues-to-remove-the-worst-of-the-wors/</guid><description>The U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) released the following statement and information regarding U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) arrests of dangerous criminal illegal aliens in Minneapolis, Minnesota over the weekend including murderer…</description></item><item><title>Even some Trump advisers are wary of a military pursuit of Greenland. Is an off-ramp possible? - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/even-some-trump-advisers-are-wary-of-a-milita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:27:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/even-some-trump-advisers-are-wary-of-a-milita/</guid><description>Flying home this month from an extended Christmas vacation in Palm Beach, President Donald Trump was momentarily taken aback when a reporter asked him about the ice-covered island he’s openly trying to annex.</description></item><item><title>'Absolutely Rolled': U.S. Officials Blast Canada's Cheap Chinese EV Deal - InsideEVs</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/absolutely-rolled-us-officials-blast-canadas-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/absolutely-rolled-us-officials-blast-canadas-/</guid><description>China Inc.&amp;rsquo;s biggest move into North America yet has industry officials and politicians on edge. But affordability concerns take center stage.</description></item><item><title>Updates: Denmark, Greenland float NATO mission on island - dw.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/updates-denmark-greenland-float-nato-mission-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/updates-denmark-greenland-float-nato-mission-/</guid><description>Denmark&amp;rsquo;s defense minister said he and Greenland&amp;rsquo;s defense minister raised the possibility of a NATO surveillance mission in Greenland in a meeting with the NATO chief Mark Rutte.</description></item><item><title>Sun releases the largest solar radiation storm ‘in over 20 years,’ forecasters say - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-releases-the-largest-solar-radiation-stor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-releases-the-largest-solar-radiation-stor/</guid><description>A powerful flare has unleashed a severe solar storm that could cause auroras and satellite disruptions on Earth.</description></item><item><title>New surveillance video shows Louvre jewel heist in action - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-surveillance-video-shows-louvre-jewel-hei/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-surveillance-video-shows-louvre-jewel-hei/</guid><description>The video shows burglars slicing into display cases under the eyes of several Louvre Museum staff members who do not intervene.</description></item><item><title>We will be ungovernable: Resistance 2.0 pivots to disruption - Axios</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-will-be-ungovernable-resistance-20-pivots-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-will-be-ungovernable-resistance-20-pivots-/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Our folks want to do more than just mass mobilization,&amp;rdquo; one organizer said.</description></item><item><title>Blast kills seven people at hotel restaurant in Afghanistan’s capital Kabul - Al Jazeera</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/blast-kills-seven-people-at-hotel-restaurant-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/blast-kills-seven-people-at-hotel-restaurant-/</guid><description>Explosion occurs in downtown Shahr-e-Naw neighbourhood, ⁠thought to be one of the most secure areas ‌of Kabul.</description></item><item><title>Judge, wife shot and wounded at home in Lafayette, Indiana - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/judge-wife-shot-and-wounded-at-home-in-lafaye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/judge-wife-shot-and-wounded-at-home-in-lafaye/</guid><description>A judge and his wife were shot and wounded in their home over the weekend in Lafayette, Indiana.</description></item><item><title>In historic first for Virginia, Adam Spanberger becomes first gentleman - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-historic-first-for-virginia-adam-spanberge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:43:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-historic-first-for-virginia-adam-spanberge/</guid><description>The computer engineer and avid bicyclist said he’s happy working behind the scenes to support his wife and Virginia’s new governor, Abigail Spanberger.</description></item><item><title>Trump is going to Davos — here are the big names who aren't - CNBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-is-going-to-davos-here-are-the-big-na/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:29:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-is-going-to-davos-here-are-the-big-na/</guid><description>A who&amp;rsquo;s who of heads of state, top CEOs and tech pioneers are landing in Davos for the 2026 World Economic Forum meeting. But some big names aren&amp;rsquo;t going.</description></item><item><title>Zurich submits improved proposal to acquire 100% of specialist insurer Beazley - Reinsurance News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/zurich-submits-improved-proposal-to-acquire-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:33:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/zurich-submits-improved-proposal-to-acquire-1/</guid><description>Zurich Insurance Group has submitted an improved proposal of 1,280 pence in cash per share to acquire specialist insurer Beazley after the latter&amp;rsquo;s Board</description></item><item><title>2026 NFL Mock Draft: Jets pivot to David Bailey at No. 2, Chiefs bolster their offense with Jeremiyah Love - PFF</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026-nfl-mock-draft-jets-pivot-to-david-baile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026-nfl-mock-draft-jets-pivot-to-david-baile/</guid><description>Oregon quarterback Dante Moore is returning to school, forcing the Jets to change directions at the top of this 2026 NFL mock draft.</description></item><item><title>NYSE Builds Venue for 24/7 Trading of Tokenized Stocks, ETFs - Bloomberg.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nyse-builds-venue-for-24/7-trading-of-tokeniz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:45:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nyse-builds-venue-for-24/7-trading-of-tokeniz/</guid><description>The New York Stock Exchange is building a venue using blockchain technology to allow for trading tokenized stocks and exchange-traded funds around the clock.</description></item><item><title>Trump's long-awaited healthcare plan is a joke - Public Notice | Aaron Rupar</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-long-awaited-healthcare-plan-is-a-joke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:17:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-long-awaited-healthcare-plan-is-a-joke/</guid><description>He can barely bring himself to pretend he cares.</description></item><item><title>Treasury Secretary’s Trump-Defending Logic Gets Turned Into A Punchline - HuffPost</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/treasury-secretarys-trump-defending-logic-ge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:31:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/treasury-secretarys-trump-defending-logic-ge/</guid><description>It went around in circles.</description></item><item><title>Prince Harry vs. the Daily Mail: The British privacy trial starts - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/prince-harry-vs-the-daily-mail-the-british-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:27:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/prince-harry-vs-the-daily-mail-the-british-pr/</guid><description>Prince Harry arrived at London’s High Court on Monday as he takes on the publisher of the Daily Mail over historical unlawful information gathering.</description></item><item><title>Trump tariffs live updates: EU discusses $108 billion in retaliatory tariffs; Danish PM says Europe 'will not be blackmailed' - Yahoo Finance</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-tariffs-live-updates-eu-discusses-108-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:18:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-tariffs-live-updates-eu-discusses-108-/</guid><description>President Trump has said the acquisition of Greenland is crucial for the US but European allies, including Denmark and Greenland, remain staunchly opposed to&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Trump has rolled out many of the Project 2025 policies he once claimed ignorance about - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-has-rolled-out-many-of-the-project-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-has-rolled-out-many-of-the-project-2025/</guid><description>Some of the 2025 policies that have been implemented include cracking down on immigration and dismantling the Department of Education.</description></item><item><title>FBI opened probe on Minneapolis shooting; none exists now, Justice Dept. says - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/fbi-opened-probe-on-minneapolis-shooting-non/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:30:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/fbi-opened-probe-on-minneapolis-shooting-non/</guid><description>After the death of Renée Good in Minneapolis, FBI agents launched a civil rights probe into the shooting. The Justice Department says no such case now exists.</description></item><item><title>The current US political climate is spurring a ‘reclaim’ and rallying on the MLK holiday - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-current-us-political-climate-is-spurring-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-current-us-political-climate-is-spurring-/</guid><description>As communities across the country prepare Monday to host parades, panels and service projects for the 40th anniversary of when the federal government officially began observing Martin Luther King Jr. Day, the current political climate has left some feeling mo…</description></item><item><title>‘A Knight of the Seven Kingdoms’ Creator on George R. R. Martin’s Plans for 15 More Books and That Gross Poop Shot in the Premiere: ‘It’s Not a Fake Up There S—-ing on Screen. That’s His Butt’ - Variety</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-knight-of-the-seven-kingdoms-creator-on-ge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-knight-of-the-seven-kingdoms-creator-on-ge/</guid><description>The &amp;lsquo;A Knight of the Seven Kingdoms&amp;rsquo; creator explains the premiere, that poop joke and using George R. R. Martin&amp;rsquo;s unpublished books.</description></item><item><title>Trump’s Greenland threats push Europe toward divorcing America - politico.eu</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-greenland-threats-push-europe-toward-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trumps-greenland-threats-push-europe-toward-/</guid><description>With NATO thrown into question, some officials see the “coalition of the willing” as the basis for a new alliance without the U.S.</description></item><item><title>Trump tariffs live updates: Trump announces tariffs on European countries until deal is reached for 'purchase of Greenland'; Danish PM says Europe 'will not be blackmailed' - Yahoo Finance</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-tariffs-live-updates-trump-announces-ta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-tariffs-live-updates-trump-announces-ta/</guid><description>President Trump has said the acquisition of Greenland is crucial for the US but European allies, including Denmark and Greenland, remain staunchly opposed to&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Wildfires race across Chile, leaving 18 dead and forcing thousands to flee - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/wildfires-race-across-chile-leaving-18-dead-a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 23:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/wildfires-race-across-chile-leaving-18-dead-a/</guid><description>Authorities in Chile say that wildfires raging across central and southern areas of the country have left at least 18 people dead. The flames have scorched thousands of acres of forest and destroyed scores of homes. The South American country is sweltering un…</description></item><item><title>Erie County issues a travel advisory as major winter storm approaches - WGRZ</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/erie-county-issues-a-travel-advisory-as-major/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/erie-county-issues-a-travel-advisory-as-major/</guid><description>Erie County will be under a Travel Advisory starting at 10 tonight as a long-duration winter storm moves into the region.</description></item><item><title>Center left wins Portugal presidential election first round, setting up showdown with far right - politico.eu</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/center-left-wins-portugal-presidential-electi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/center-left-wins-portugal-presidential-electi/</guid><description>António José Seguro will face far-right leader André Ventura in a runoff ballot Feb. 8.</description></item><item><title>7 police officers killed in attacks in Guatemala after prison crackdown on gangs - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/7-police-officers-killed-in-attacks-in-guatem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:06:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/7-police-officers-killed-in-attacks-in-guatem/</guid><description>The killings occurred a day after gang member inmates took 46 people hostage in three prisons across the country, officials said.</description></item><item><title>Louisiana’s Letlow prepares Senate bid after Trump endorsement - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/louisianas-letlow-prepares-senate-bid-after-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:51:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/louisianas-letlow-prepares-senate-bid-after-/</guid><description>Her entry would be the worst-case scenario for GOP Sen. Bill Cassidy.</description></item><item><title>Minneapolis Mayor Jacob Frey says federal agents are an occupying force - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/minneapolis-mayor-jacob-frey-says-federal-age/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:24:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/minneapolis-mayor-jacob-frey-says-federal-age/</guid><description>Minneapolis Mayor Jacob Frey criticized the administration&amp;rsquo;s immigration operations, calling the surge of federal agents an &amp;ldquo;occupying force that has quite literally invaded our city.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Trump urges lawmaker to challenge GOP senator who voted to convict him - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-urges-lawmaker-to-challenge-gop-senator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-urges-lawmaker-to-challenge-gop-senator/</guid><description>The president endorsed Rep. Julia Letlow of Louisiana, who hasn’t announced a Senate run. Sen. Bill Cassidy voted convict in the impeachment trial over the Jan. 6 riot.</description></item><item><title>Melting ice may raise Greenland’s value. Trump’s fight may be just the start. - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/melting-ice-may-raise-greenlands-value-trump/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/melting-ice-may-raise-greenlands-value-trump/</guid><description>Trump has said he wants the territory because of its strategic location. Maps show how a melting Arctic is affecting geopolitics.</description></item><item><title>Peak travel: Viewing the U.S. from each state's highest point - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/peak-travel-viewing-the-us-from-each-states-h/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:18:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/peak-travel-viewing-the-us-from-each-states-h/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Highpointers&amp;rdquo; are people with a quirky goal: summiting the highest point in each of the 50 states, from Mr. McKinley in Alaska (elevation: 20,310 feet above sea level), to Florida&amp;rsquo;s Britton Hill (elevation: 345 feet).</description></item><item><title>German Soldiers Leave Greenland After 44 Hours, Bild Reports - Bloomberg.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/german-soldiers-leave-greenland-after-44-hour/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/german-soldiers-leave-greenland-after-44-hour/</guid><description>The German military reconnaissance team that arrived in Greenland on Friday is on its way back after a 44-hour deployment on the Arctic island, Bild newspaper reported on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Carney mulling $1B membership to Trump’s ‘Board of Peace’ - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/carney-mulling-1b-membership-to-trumps-boar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/carney-mulling-1b-membership-to-trumps-boar/</guid><description>The Canadian PM said the POTUS invite came &amp;ldquo;a few weeks ago.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>ICE jumps to center of midterm campaigns - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ice-jumps-to-center-of-midterm-campaigns-poli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ice-jumps-to-center-of-midterm-campaigns-poli/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>CBS News poll finds more Americans say ICE being too tough; Republicans feel protesters have gone too far - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cbs-news-poll-finds-more-americans-say-ice-be/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:34:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cbs-news-poll-finds-more-americans-say-ice-be/</guid><description>Looking overseas, there is wide opposition to the idea of taking Greenland by force.</description></item><item><title>Green Day to open 60th Super Bowl with anniversary ceremony celebrating generations of MVPs - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/green-day-to-open-60th-super-bowl-with-annive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/green-day-to-open-60th-super-bowl-with-annive/</guid><description>The NFL has announced that Green Day will kick off the 60th Super Bowl with an opening ceremony at Levi’s Stadium in Santa Clara, California. The performance will celebrate six decades of the league&amp;rsquo;s championship game history. The band will help usher genera…</description></item><item><title>1,500 soldiers on standby for possible Minnesota deployment, source says, as state mobilizes National Guard - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1500-soldiers-on-standby-for-possible-minneso/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1500-soldiers-on-standby-for-possible-minneso/</guid><description>The Pentagon has ordered about 1,500 active-duty soldiers to prepare for possible deployment to Minnesota, according to a Trump administration source, as state officials have also mobilized the National Guard.</description></item><item><title>Seahawks thump 49ers in playoff opener, advance to NFC Championship Game - The Seattle Times</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/seahawks-thump-49ers-in-playoff-opener-advanc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:31:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/seahawks-thump-49ers-in-playoff-opener-advanc/</guid><description>In a game that felt over almost as soon as it started, the Seahawks thumped the 49ers 41-6 in their playoff opener and advance to the NFC Championship Game.</description></item><item><title>‘SNL’ Mocks Trump’s Nobel Prize Envy, Colin Jost’s Unhinged Pete Hegseth Promises ‘USA is Going to F—‘ Countries Around the World - Variety</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/snl-mocks-trumps-nobel-prize-envy-colin-jos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/snl-mocks-trumps-nobel-prize-envy-colin-jos/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;SNL&amp;rsquo; mocked President Trump&amp;rsquo;s egomania around the Nobel Peace Prize and Kristi Noem&amp;rsquo;s response to the ICE shooting in Minneapolis in its cold open.</description></item><item><title>Pennsylvania woman's final moments captured on home security video. Will it help prove she was murdered? - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/pennsylvania-womans-final-moments-captured-on/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/pennsylvania-womans-final-moments-captured-on/</guid><description>Bruno Rocuba claims a freak accident while handling his gun caused the death of his wife, Melissa Rocuba. He was not arrested or charged with any crime. Years later, investigators uncover disturbing new evidence that challenges what really happened that night…</description></item><item><title>Gaza is our show: U.S. pushes its plan over Netanyahu's objections - Axios</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gaza-is-our-show-us-pushes-its-plan-over-neta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:39:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gaza-is-our-show-us-pushes-its-plan-over-neta/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;If he wants us to deal with Gaza, it will have to be our way.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>DHS seeking to deport two men who said fellow ICE detainee was killed - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dhs-seeking-to-deport-two-men-who-said-fellow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:46:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dhs-seeking-to-deport-two-men-who-said-fellow/</guid><description>The two men’s eyewitness accounts of the Jan. 3 death of Geraldo Lunas Campos at a Texas detention camp differ from the Department of Homeland Security’s account of the incident.</description></item><item><title>Scientists find an interstellar 'tunnel' that connects our solar system to other stars - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-an-interstellar-tunnel-that-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:28:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-an-interstellar-tunnel-that-c/</guid><description>Astronomers found an interstellar &amp;ldquo;tunnel&amp;rdquo; - a cosmic channel that connects our solar system to distant stars, according to a recent study.</description></item><item><title>March led by pardoned Jan. 6 rioter in Minneapolis ends in scuffle - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/march-led-by-pardoned-jan-6-rioter-in-minneap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:25:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/march-led-by-pardoned-jan-6-rioter-in-minneap/</guid><description>The right-wing provocateur known for incendiary rhetoric and his 10 or so supporters were outnumbered by a large crowd of counterprotesters in Minneapolis.</description></item><item><title>EU Set to Halt US Trade Deal Over Trump’s New Tariff Threat - Bloomberg.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eu-set-to-halt-us-trade-deal-over-trumps-new/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:10:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eu-set-to-halt-us-trade-deal-over-trumps-new/</guid><description>European Union lawmakers are poised to halt approval of the EU’s trade deal with the US over President Donald Trump’s vow to impose tariffs on countries that supported Greenland in the face of American threats.</description></item><item><title>Starmer brands Trump's plan to apply tariffs over Greenland 'completely wrong' - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starmer-brands-trumps-plan-to-apply-tariffs-o/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starmer-brands-trumps-plan-to-apply-tariffs-o/</guid><description>The US president says the UK, Denmark and other European countries will be charged a &amp;ldquo;10% tariff on any or all goods&amp;rdquo; exported to the US from 1 February.</description></item><item><title>‘Heavy’ snow could impact parts of central Georgia, metro Atlanta mostly spared - AJC.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/heavy-snow-could-impact-parts-of-central-geo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/heavy-snow-could-impact-parts-of-central-geo/</guid><description>The state’s best chance for snow comes overnight Saturday into Sunday afternoon along a diagonal line from Columbus to Macon to Warrenton, the National Weather Service says.</description></item><item><title>Norwegian Acting Legend Liv Ullmann Wades Into Donald Trump Nobel Peace Prize Gift: “He Will Lose It” – European Film Awards - Deadline</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/norwegian-acting-legend-liv-ullmann-wades-int/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/norwegian-acting-legend-liv-ullmann-wades-int/</guid><description>Norwegian Acting Legend Liv Ullmann Wades Into Donald Trump Nobel Peace Prize Gift: &amp;ldquo;He Will Lose It&amp;rdquo; – European Film Awards</description></item><item><title>Five die in Austrian avalanches, rescuers say - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/five-die-in-austrian-avalanches-rescuers-say-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/five-die-in-austrian-avalanches-rescuers-say-/</guid><description>A number of people have died in the Alps over the past week, as heavy snowfall has hit the region.</description></item><item><title>Justice Dept. enters new territory with probe of Minnesota officials - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/justice-dept-enters-new-territory-with-probe-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/justice-dept-enters-new-territory-with-probe-/</guid><description>The agency is targeting critics during a moment of crisis in which protesters are clashing with federal agents on icy city streets.</description></item><item><title>Abigail Spanberger becomes Virginia’s 1st female governor in historic inauguration - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/abigail-spanberger-becomes-virginias-1st-fem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/abigail-spanberger-becomes-virginias-1st-fem/</guid><description>Her swearing-in marks a new political chapter in the commonwealth, with Democrats pulling the levers of power in state government.</description></item><item><title>European Union and Mercosur bloc of South American nations sign landmark free trade agreement - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/european-union-and-mercosur-bloc-of-south-ame/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/european-union-and-mercosur-bloc-of-south-ame/</guid><description>The European Union and the Mercosur bloc of South American countries have formally signed a long-sought landmark free trade agreement. The deal inked on Saturday caps more than a quarter-century of torturous negotiations to strengthen commercial ties in the f…</description></item><item><title>Trump to POLITICO: ‘It’s time to look for new leadership in Iran’ - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-to-politico-its-time-to-look-for-new-l/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:02:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-to-politico-its-time-to-look-for-new-l/</guid><description>Trump, after being read a series of hostile X posts from Iran’s Supreme Leader, said the Ayatollah is guilty of “the complete destruction of his country.”</description></item><item><title>Five graphics that show Greenland’s importance to Trump - DW.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/five-graphics-that-show-greenlands-importanc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:31:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/five-graphics-that-show-greenlands-importanc/</guid><description>Its entire population would fit in a large sports stadium but Greenland’s current presence on the geopolitical stage is huge. DW takes a look at the reasons it&amp;rsquo;s so coveted — from natural resources to climate change.</description></item><item><title>Uganda election result: Yoweri Museveni beats Bobi Wine to win a seventh term - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/uganda-election-result-yoweri-museveni-beats-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/uganda-election-result-yoweri-museveni-beats-/</guid><description>President Yoweri Museveni wins a seventh term, as his main rival Bobi Wine decries &amp;ldquo;fake results&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Here’s where Trump’s most jaw-dropping promises stand a year into his second term - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/heres-where-trumps-most-jaw-dropping-promis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/heres-where-trumps-most-jaw-dropping-promis/</guid><description>President Donald Trump has made lots of promises during the first year of his second term in the White House. Some ideas have come to fruition. Others have faded away. Some are kicking around. These include a new Air Force One gifted by Qatar and the U.S. ann…</description></item><item><title>From ‘A+’ grade to ‘we can’t stand this much longer,’ Georgia voters take stock of Trump’s first year back in office - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/from-a+-grade-to-we-cant-stand-this-much-lo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/from-a+-grade-to-we-cant-stand-this-much-lo/</guid><description>Franz Rowland has heard President Donald Trump endlessly brag about a roaring economy, but he’s seen few signs of it from his cotton farm here in southern Georgia.</description></item><item><title>How Ukrainians Are Protecting Their Homes Against Russia’s Winter Offensive - Kyiv Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-ukrainians-are-protecting-their-homes-aga/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-ukrainians-are-protecting-their-homes-aga/</guid><description>Kyiv faces up to 20 hours without electricity each day after relentless Russian strikes, yet residents are finding creative ways to cope with the blackout.</description></item><item><title>Trump administration rolls back $2 billion mental health, addiction grant cuts - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-administration-rolls-back-2-billion-me/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/trump-administration-rolls-back-2-billion-me/</guid><description>Sweeping cuts to mental health and addiction programs worth more than $2 billion are being reversed. After a political backlash from Republicans and Democrats, the grant money will be restored.</description></item><item><title>Reports: Shooting involving federal law enforcement in north Minneapolis - kare11.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reports-shooting-involving-federal-law-enforc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reports-shooting-involving-federal-law-enforc/</guid><description>A large crowd has formed in the Hawthorne neighborhood.</description></item><item><title>Iran briefly closes airspace as U.S. tensions rise, flights rerouted across region - CNBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/iran-briefly-closes-airspace-as-us-tensions-r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/iran-briefly-closes-airspace-as-us-tensions-r/</guid><description>Iran temporarily closed most of its airspace late Wednesday, forcing airlines to reroute flights as tensions with the United States escalated.</description></item><item><title>Twenty one English councils ask for election delays - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/twenty-one-english-councils-ask-for-election-/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:32:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/twenty-one-english-councils-ask-for-election-/</guid><description>Nearly a third of eligible authorities have want to postpone local polls scheduled for May.</description></item><item><title>US and UK pulling some personnel from Qatar military base - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/us-and-uk-pulling-some-personnel-from-qatar-m/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/us-and-uk-pulling-some-personnel-from-qatar-m/</guid><description>US officials say it is a &amp;ldquo;precautionary measure&amp;rdquo; and comes as Donald Trump weighs up whether to take action against Iran.</description></item><item><title>In a win for Democrats, court allows California's redistricting plan to proceed - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-a-win-for-democrats-court-allows-californi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:19:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-a-win-for-democrats-court-allows-californi/</guid><description>In November, California voters approved a new congressional map that could help Democrats win five more House seats and counter the Republican redistricting that President Trump has prompted in other states.</description></item><item><title>Embarrassing floor meltdown has House Republicans questioning their leaders - Politico</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/embarrassing-floor-meltdown-has-house-republi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:57:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/embarrassing-floor-meltdown-has-house-republi/</guid><description>A group of pro-labor holdouts handed the GOP its latest setback and underscored the tough path for party-line legislation this year.</description></item><item><title>US will suspend immigrant visa processing from 75 countries over public assistance concerns - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/us-will-suspend-immigrant-visa-processing-fro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/us-will-suspend-immigrant-visa-processing-fro/</guid><description>The State Department says it will suspend the processing of immigrant visas for citizens of 75 countries whose nationals are deemed likely to require public assistance while living in the United States. The department said Wednesday it had instructed consular…</description></item><item><title>Congressional Bill S. 222 Signed into Law - The White House (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/congressional-bill-s-222-signed-into-law-the-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:05:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/congressional-bill-s-222-signed-into-law-the-/</guid><description>On Wednesday, January 14, 2026, the President signed into law: S. 222, the &amp;ldquo;Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025,&amp;rdquo; which modifies the requirements for</description></item><item><title>Ryan Hurst Cast As Kratos In Prime Video’s ‘God of War’ - Deadline</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ryan-hurst-cast-as-kratos-in-prime-videos-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ryan-hurst-cast-as-kratos-in-prime-videos-go/</guid><description>Ryan Hurst has been cast in the series lead role of Kratos In Prime Video’s &amp;lsquo;God of War.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Red Sox To Sign Ranger Suárez - MLB Trade Rumors</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/red-sox-to-sign-ranger-su%C3%A1rez-mlb-trade-rumor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:17:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/red-sox-to-sign-ranger-su%C3%A1rez-mlb-trade-rumor/</guid><description>The Red Sox missed on Bregman but quickly pivot to adding more pitching.</description></item><item><title>Starlink reportedly made free in Iran - but protesters are taking huge risks by using it - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starlink-reportedly-made-free-in-iran-but-pro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starlink-reportedly-made-free-in-iran-but-pro/</guid><description>The satellite technology has become a vital communications lifeline after the government shut down the internet last week.</description></item></channel></rss>