<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>science on Newsround</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/tags/science/</link><description>Recent content in science on Newsround</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://newsround.github.io/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scientists may be approaching a 'fundamental breakthrough in cosmology and particle physics', if dark matter and 'ghost particles' can interact - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-be-approaching-a-fundamental-b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-be-approaching-a-fundamental-b/</guid><description>Astronomers found evidence that dark matter and neutrinos may interact, hinting at a &amp;ldquo;fundamental breakthrough&amp;rdquo; that challenges our understanding of how the universe evolved.</description></item><item><title>Scientist claims to have found the 'exact location of Heaven' with mind-blowing theory - UNILAD</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientist-claims-to-have-found-the-exact-loca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientist-claims-to-have-found-the-exact-loca/</guid><description>Former Harvard lecturer Dr Michael Guillen shared his in-depth theory about Heaven&amp;rsquo;s location and why we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been able to reach it</description></item><item><title>Mysterious Giants Could Be a Whole New Kind of Life That No Longer Exists - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-giants-could-be-a-whole-new-kind-o/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 03:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-giants-could-be-a-whole-new-kind-o/</guid><description>Ever since their discovery more than 165 years ago, massive fossilized structures left by an organism known as Prototaxites have proven impossible to categorize.</description></item><item><title>'We can handle any kind of difficult situation': Crew-11 astronauts say 1st medical evacuation from ISS had a silver lining - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-can-handle-any-kind-of-difficult-situation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-can-handle-any-kind-of-difficult-situation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;This is actually a very, very good experience for the future of human spaceflight.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis II Mission to Fly Legacy Keepsakes with Astronaut Crew - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-mission-to-fly-legacy-keeps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:48:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-mission-to-fly-legacy-keeps/</guid><description>As America approaches its 250th anniversary of declaring independence, NASA’s Artemis II mission will carry a host of mementos that reflect the nation’s long</description></item><item><title>Massive cloud with metallic winds discovered orbiting mystery object - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-cloud-with-metallic-winds-discovered-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:17:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-cloud-with-metallic-winds-discovered-/</guid><description>Sweeping winds of vaporized metals have been found in a massive cloud that dimmed the light of a star for nearly nine months. This discovery, made with the Gemini South telescope in Chile, one half of the International Gemini Observatory, offers a rare glimps…</description></item><item><title>'Eye of God' nebula looks like a cosmic lava lamp in new James Webb Space Telescope image - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eye-of-god-nebula-looks-like-a-cosmic-lava-la/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eye-of-god-nebula-looks-like-a-cosmic-lava-la/</guid><description>It may be one of the most iconic sights in the night sky, but astronomers have never seen the Helix Nebula like this before.</description></item><item><title>Meet the marten: An updated look at a rare, adorable carnivore - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-marten-an-updated-look-at-a-rare-ado/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:52:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-marten-an-updated-look-at-a-rare-ado/</guid><description>Oregon State University researchers have painted a clearer picture of the coastal marten, a secretive, ferret-sized forest carnivore renowned for its cuteness but nearly driven to extinction by human activity in the 20th century.</description></item><item><title>2.8 Days to Disaster: Low Earth Orbit Could Collapse Without Warning - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/28-days-to-disaster-low-earth-orbit-could-col/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/28-days-to-disaster-low-earth-orbit-could-col/</guid><description>A new analysis suggests modern satellite networks could suffer catastrophic collisions within days of losing control during a major solar storm. The phrase “House of Cards” is often associated today with a Netflix political drama, but its original meaning ref…</description></item><item><title>Astronauts say space station's ultrasound machine was critical during medical crisis - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-say-space-stations-ultrasound-mach/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:19:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-say-space-stations-ultrasound-mach/</guid><description>The astronauts evacuated last week from the International Space Station say a portable ultrasound machine came in “super handy” during the medical crisis&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Are your memories illusions? New study disentangles the Boltzmann brain paradox - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-your-memories-illusions-new-study-disenta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-your-memories-illusions-new-study-disenta/</guid><description>In a recent paper, SFI Professor David Wolpert, SFI Fractal Faculty member Carlo Rovelli, and physicist Jordan Scharnhorst examine a longstanding, paradoxical thought experiment in statistical physics and cosmology known as the &amp;ldquo;Boltzmann brain&amp;rdquo; hypothesis—th…</description></item><item><title>Glamping with the stars: These 7 retreats are perfect for night-sky watching - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/glamping-with-the-stars-these-7-retreats-are-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:19:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/glamping-with-the-stars-these-7-retreats-are-/</guid><description>Bask in modern luxury while taking in the cosmos at these astrotourism escapes.</description></item><item><title>2026’s Meteor Showers Could Be the Best in Decades, Here’s When to Watch - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026s-meteor-showers-could-be-the-best-in-de/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026s-meteor-showers-could-be-the-best-in-de/</guid><description>Don’t put your telescope away just yet. 2026 is bringing a lineup of meteor showers that might be worth losing a little sleep over.</description></item><item><title>Astronomy Days 2026 postponed - WRAL</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-days-2026-postponed-wral/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:37:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-days-2026-postponed-wral/</guid><description>Winter weather has forced the annual 2-day event which draws thousands to the North Carolina Museum of Natural Sciences to be rescheduled to January 31 and February 1.</description></item><item><title>Unified framework sorts spacetime fluctuations for quantum-gravity experiments - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unified-framework-sorts-spacetime-fluctuation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:22:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unified-framework-sorts-spacetime-fluctuation/</guid><description>A team of researchers led by the University of Warwick has developed the first unified framework for detecting &amp;ldquo;spacetime fluctuations&amp;rdquo;—tiny, random distortions in the fabric of spacetime that appear in many attempts to unite quantum physics and gravity.</description></item><item><title>Massive black hole mystery unlocked by researchers - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-black-hole-mystery-unlocked-by-resear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:16:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-black-hole-mystery-unlocked-by-resear/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s one of astronomy&amp;rsquo;s great mysteries: how did black holes get so big, so massive, so quickly. An answer to this cosmic conundrum has now been provided by researchers at Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Maynooth University (MU) and reported today in Nature Astronomy.</description></item><item><title>A Deep Sea Expedition Will Soon Confirm if 'Dark Oxygen' Exists - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-deep-sea-expedition-will-soon-confirm-if-da/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:03:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-deep-sea-expedition-will-soon-confirm-if-da/</guid><description>A team of scientists announced Tuesday they have developed new deep-sea landers specifically to test their contentious discovery that metallic rocks at the bottom of the ocean are producing &amp;ldquo;dark oxygen&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow’s “Full Moon” Phase of 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tomorrows-full-moon-phase-of-3i/atlas-avi-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:49:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tomorrows-full-moon-phase-of-3i/atlas-avi-/</guid><description>In a new paper that was just accepted for publication yesterday (and posted as a preprint here), I reported with Mauro Barbieri that…</description></item><item><title>Ageing promotes microglial accumulation of slow-degrading synaptic proteins - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ageing-promotes-microglial-accumulation-of-sl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ageing-promotes-microglial-accumulation-of-sl/</guid><description>Newly developed mouse models that enable cell-specific analyses of proteostasis dynamics across the lifespan of the mice reveal key aspects of neuronal proteostasis with ageing.</description></item><item><title>Gravity Solved? This Wild New Idea Might Explain the Entire Universe in One Shot - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravity-solved-this-wild-new-idea-might-expla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravity-solved-this-wild-new-idea-might-expla/</guid><description>Scientists propose one idea to explain it all from gravity to dark matter.</description></item><item><title>Schrödinger’s cat just got bigger: quantum physicists create largest ever ‘superposition’ - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/schr%C3%B6dingers-cat-just-got-bigger-quantum-phy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/schr%C3%B6dingers-cat-just-got-bigger-quantum-phy/</guid><description>Record-breaking experiment shows that a cluster of thousands of atoms can act like a wave as well as a particle.</description></item><item><title>Temporal tissue dynamics from a spatial snapshot - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/temporal-tissue-dynamics-from-a-spatial-snaps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/temporal-tissue-dynamics-from-a-spatial-snaps/</guid><description>One-shot tissue dynamics reconstruction can infer changes in tissue composition over time, from single-time-point spatial proteomics of human cancers.</description></item><item><title>Symmetry, microscopy and spectroscopy signatures of altermagnetism - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/symmetry-microscopy-and-spectroscopy-signatur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/symmetry-microscopy-and-spectroscopy-signatur/</guid><description>The symmetry, microscopy and spectroscopy signatures of altermagnetism are reviewed, and compared with traditional ferromagnetism and Néel antiferromagnetism, and magnetic phases with symmetry-protected compensated non-collinear spin orders.</description></item><item><title>Enormous freshwater reservoir discovered off the East Coast may be 20,000 years old and big enough to supply NYC for 800 years - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/enormous-freshwater-reservoir-discovered-off-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:24:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/enormous-freshwater-reservoir-discovered-off-/</guid><description>An expedition off the coast of Massachusetts has confirmed the existence of a freshwater reservoir beneath the seafloor. Now, scientists are starting to understand when and how it formed.</description></item><item><title>Four camera-type eyes in the earliest vertebrates from the Cambrian Period - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-camera-type-eyes-in-the-earliest-vertebr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-camera-type-eyes-in-the-earliest-vertebr/</guid><description>Early vertebrates, particularly myllokunmingids, possessed four camera-type eyes (a pair of lateral eyes and pineal and parapineal organs), which indicates that these structures functioned in image formation, in support of the hypothe…</description></item><item><title>Afar fossil shows broad distribution and versatility of Paranthropus - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/afar-fossil-shows-broad-distribution-and-vers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:08:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/afar-fossil-shows-broad-distribution-and-vers/</guid><description>With its attribution to Paranthropus, a 2.6-million-year-old partial mandible expands the range of the genus into the Afar region of Ethiopia and adds to our understanding of hominin evolution in eastern Africa.</description></item><item><title>Bird retinas function without oxygen—solving a centuries-old biological mystery - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bird-retinas-function-without-oxygensolving-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bird-retinas-function-without-oxygensolving-/</guid><description>Neural tissue normally dies quickly without oxygen. Yet bird retinas—among the most energy-demanding tissues in the animal kingdom—function permanently without it. This may be relevant in future treatment of stroke patients.</description></item><item><title>NASA Webb Finds Young Sun-Like Star Forging, Spewing Common Crystals - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-finds-young-sun-like-star-forging-s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-finds-young-sun-like-star-forging-s/</guid><description>Astronomers have long sought evidence to explain why comets at the outskirts of our own solar system contain crystalline silicates, since crystals require</description></item><item><title>How Animals Build a Sense of Direction - Quanta Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-animals-build-a-sense-of-direction-quanta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-animals-build-a-sense-of-direction-quanta/</guid><description>Researchers documented the activity of neurons that shape directional navigation as bats explored a remote island off the coast of Tanzania.</description></item><item><title>These Snapshots of the Moment a Star Exploded Will Fill You With Cosmic Dread - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/these-snapshots-of-the-moment-a-star-exploded/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:11:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/these-snapshots-of-the-moment-a-star-exploded/</guid><description>A pair of incredible images show the very moment that two different stars exploded, an incredible display that&amp;rsquo;s melting our minds.</description></item><item><title>NASA to end support for planetary science groups - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-to-end-support-for-planetary-science-gro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:24:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-to-end-support-for-planetary-science-gro/</guid><description>NASA is ending financial support for several planetary science groups as part of a broader drawdown of the agency’s advisory structure.</description></item><item><title>This Everyday Speech Pattern Is a Clear Sign Your Brain Is Starting to Shut Down - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-everyday-speech-pattern-is-a-clear-sign-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-everyday-speech-pattern-is-a-clear-sign-/</guid><description>A hidden speech pattern may reveal early brain decline, years before memory loss. Scientists have uncovered a surprising verbal clue linked to cognitive aging, and it’s something most people ignore every day.</description></item><item><title>A Cycle Deep Within Earth's Crust May Affect Climate More Than We Thought - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-cycle-deep-within-earths-crust-may-affect-c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:01:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-cycle-deep-within-earths-crust-may-affect-c/</guid><description>Our planet has experienced dramatic climate shifts throughout its history, oscillating between freezing &amp;ldquo;icehouse&amp;rdquo; periods and warm &amp;ldquo;greenhouse&amp;rdquo; states.</description></item><item><title>The Strength and Fitness Benchmarks Men Should be Hitting in Their 50s - Men's Health</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-strength-and-fitness-benchmarks-men-shoul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-strength-and-fitness-benchmarks-men-shoul/</guid><description>These strength and fitness benchmarks outline what healthy men in their 50s can aim for across strength, endurance, power and cardio.</description></item><item><title>Solar flares triggered by cascading magnetic avalanches, new observations reveal - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/solar-flares-triggered-by-cascading-magnetic-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/solar-flares-triggered-by-cascading-magnetic-/</guid><description>Just as avalanches on snowy mountains start with the movement of a small quantity of snow, the ESA-led Solar Orbiter spacecraft has discovered that a solar flare is triggered by initially weak disturbances that quickly become more violent. This rapidly evolvi…</description></item><item><title>Stanford scientists found a way to regrow cartilage and stop arthritis - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-found-a-way-to-regrow-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:56:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-found-a-way-to-regrow-car/</guid><description>Scientists at Stanford Medicine have discovered a treatment that can reverse cartilage loss in aging joints and even prevent arthritis after knee injuries. By blocking a protein linked to aging, the therapy restored healthy, shock-absorbing cartilage in old m…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover a New Quantum State of Matter Once Considered Impossible - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-new-quantum-state-of-ma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:20:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-new-quantum-state-of-ma/</guid><description>A quantum state of matter has appeared in a material where physicists thought it would be impossible, forcing a rethink on the conditions that govern the behaviors of electrons in certain materials.</description></item><item><title>Both astronauts that flew on Boeing’s troubled Starliner mission are now retired - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/both-astronauts-that-flew-on-boeings-trouble/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/both-astronauts-that-flew-on-boeings-trouble/</guid><description>Veteran NASA astronaut Suni Williams announced her retirement Tuesday. Her extended mission to orbit due to the troubled Boeing Starliner test flight was her final foray.</description></item><item><title>AI-driven ultrafast spectrometer-on-a-chip advances real-time sensing - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-driven-ultrafast-spectrometer-on-a-chip-ad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-driven-ultrafast-spectrometer-on-a-chip-ad/</guid><description>For decades, the ability to visualize the chemical composition of materials, whether for diagnosing a disease, assessing food quality, or analyzing pollution, depended on large, expensive laboratory instruments called spectrometers. These devices work by taki…</description></item><item><title>Interstellar Hitchhiking on Objects Like 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/interstellar-hitchhiking-on-objects-like-3i/a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:24:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/interstellar-hitchhiking-on-objects-like-3i/a/</guid><description>For a technological civilization born on a planet as massive as Earth, the easiest way to engage in high-speed interstellar travel might be…</description></item><item><title>Mysterious polar weather on Jupiter and Saturn could be key to understanding their insides - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-polar-weather-on-jupiter-and-satur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-polar-weather-on-jupiter-and-satur/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone&amp;rsquo;s made this connection between the surface fluid pattern and the interior properties of these planets.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>'Like watching a cosmic volcano erupt': Scientists see monster black hole 'reborn' after 100 million years - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-watching-a-cosmic-volcano-erupt-scientis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-watching-a-cosmic-volcano-erupt-scientis/</guid><description>Scientists saw an inactive black hole &amp;lsquo;reawaken&amp;rsquo; from a 100-million-year nap with fire and fury.</description></item><item><title>New NASA Artemis Payloads To Study Moon’s Terrain, Radiation, History - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-nasa-artemis-payloads-to-study-moons-ter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:23:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-nasa-artemis-payloads-to-study-moons-ter/</guid><description>NASA announced Tuesday the selection of three new science investigations that will strengthen humanity’s understanding and exploration of the Moon. As part of</description></item><item><title>Complex building blocks of life form spontaneously in space, research reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/complex-building-blocks-of-life-form-spontane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/complex-building-blocks-of-life-form-spontane/</guid><description>Challenging long-held assumptions, Aarhus University researchers have demonstrated that the protein building blocks essential for life as we know it can form readily in space. This discovery, appearing in Nature Astronomy, significantly raises the statistical…</description></item><item><title>A twitch in time? Quantum collapse models hint at tiny time fluctuations - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-twitch-in-time-quantum-collapse-models-hint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-twitch-in-time-quantum-collapse-models-hint/</guid><description>Quantum mechanics is rich with paradoxes and contradictions. It describes a microscopic world in which particles exist in a superposition of states—being in multiple places and configurations all at once, defined mathematically by what physicists call a &amp;ldquo;wave…</description></item><item><title>4,000 Space Mirrors Could Soon Light Up Your Night, and They’re Coming in 2026 - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4000-space-mirrors-could-soon-light-up-your-n/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4000-space-mirrors-could-soon-light-up-your-n/</guid><description>A bold new startup plans to launch mirrors into orbit to reflect sunlight onto Earth at night, a move that could outshine the Moon.</description></item><item><title>How to make a super-Earth: The universe's most common planets are whittled down by stellar radiation - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-make-a-super-earth-the-universes-most-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-make-a-super-earth-the-universes-most-/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s so exciting is that we&amp;rsquo;re seeing a preview of what will become a very normal planetary system.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Adam Hagen - wctrib.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/adam-hagen-wctribcom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/adam-hagen-wctribcom/</guid><description>Adam Benjamin Hagen, 44, of rural Benton County passed at home Saturday, January 17, 2026 after a valiant battle with cancer.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers Discover Gigantic Iron Bar Running Through Ring Nebula - PetaPixel</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-gigantic-iron-bar-runnin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-gigantic-iron-bar-runnin/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;We definitely need to know more.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>This Black Hole Jet Is So Powerful, It’s Shutting Down an Entire Galaxy - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-black-hole-jet-is-so-powerful-its-shutt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-black-hole-jet-is-so-powerful-its-shutt/</guid><description>This black hole isn’t just pulling stuff in, it’s blasting material out. And what that means for its galaxy is more serious than anyone expected.</description></item><item><title>What Isaac Roberts Saw Without A Space Telescope - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-isaac-roberts-saw-without-a-space-telesc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-isaac-roberts-saw-without-a-space-telesc/</guid><description>Space telescopes are all the rage, and rightfully so. The images they take are spectacular, and they’ve greatly increased what we know about the universe. Surely, any picture taken of, say, t…</description></item><item><title>NASA Unlocks Golden Age of Innovation, Exploration in Trump’s First Year - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-unlocks-golden-age-of-innovation-explora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-unlocks-golden-age-of-innovation-explora/</guid><description>One year into President Donald J. Trump’s second term, NASA is delivering measurable progress across human spaceflight, science, aeronautics, and cutting-edge</description></item><item><title>While Cleaning Up Flood Damage, Texas Volunteers Saw 15 Dinosaur Tracks Emerge From the Ground - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/while-cleaning-up-flood-damage-texas-voluntee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/while-cleaning-up-flood-damage-texas-voluntee/</guid><description>They thought the area was clear, until giant claw tracks surfaced after the floods.</description></item><item><title>Quote of the Day by Stephen Hawking: 'We are just an advanced breed of monkeys on a minor planet of a very average star. But...' - 19FortyFive</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quote-of-the-day-by-stephen-hawking-we-are-ju/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:08:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quote-of-the-day-by-stephen-hawking-we-are-ju/</guid><description>Stephen Hawking’s 1988 “advanced monkeys” quote argues that understanding the universe—and exploring space—may be humanity’s best path to endure.</description></item><item><title>Astronauts Helicoptered to Hospital After Mystery Evacuation From Space Station - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-helicoptered-to-hospital-after-mys/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:01:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-helicoptered-to-hospital-after-mys/</guid><description>Four astronauts were airlifted to a hospital in San Diego via helicopter after the International Space Station&amp;rsquo;s first medical evacuation.</description></item><item><title>A New Theory Says Gravity May Come From Entropy—Which Could Lead to a Unified Theory of Physics - Yahoo News Canada</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-theory-says-gravity-may-come-from-entro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-theory-says-gravity-may-come-from-entro/</guid><description>A new theory suggests gravity could possibly be the result of entropy—which would mean everything in the universe would fall apart if it all remained&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Discovered How Giant Dinosaurs Grew Necks So Massive They Changed the Way They Walked - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-discovered-how-giant-dinosaur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-discovered-how-giant-dinosaur/</guid><description>What made these dinosaurs so huge? Scientists point to one surprising feature: the neck.</description></item><item><title>Invisible companion leaves evidence trail around supergiant star Betelgeuse - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/invisible-companion-leaves-evidence-trail-aro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/invisible-companion-leaves-evidence-trail-aro/</guid><description>Optical proof of a tiny companion orbiting supergiant star Betelgeuse is hard to come by. Hubble just spotted new evidence.</description></item><item><title>Are We Trapped in a Cosmic Illusion? Scientists Say the Universe Might Be a Hall of Mirrors - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-we-trapped-in-a-cosmic-illusion-scientist/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-we-trapped-in-a-cosmic-illusion-scientist/</guid><description>Could the shape of the universe be tricking us? A new study suggests the universe could be shaped in a way that creates optical illusions on a cosmic scale.</description></item><item><title>Mars orbiter sees odd etchings in the sand photo of the day for Jan. 20, 2025 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-orbiter-sees-odd-etchings-in-the-sand-ph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-orbiter-sees-odd-etchings-in-the-sand-ph/</guid><description>Even though the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is thin, wind is still one of Mars' most relentless sculptors.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers Caught a Record-Breaking Stellar Explosion on Camera and It Looks Nothing Like They Expected - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-caught-a-record-breaking-stellar-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:46:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-caught-a-record-breaking-stellar-/</guid><description>High-resolution images of exploding stars challenge our understanding of cosmic death and shock physics</description></item><item><title>Comet Wierzchos buzzes the sun later today: But can you see it? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-wierzchos-buzzes-the-sun-later-today-bu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-wierzchos-buzzes-the-sun-later-today-bu/</guid><description>C/2024 E1 (Wierzchos) brightened significantly ahead of its close approach to the sun.</description></item><item><title>New quantum boundary discovered: Spin size determines how the Kondo effect behaves - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-quantum-boundary-discovered-spin-size-det/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-quantum-boundary-discovered-spin-size-det/</guid><description>Collective behavior is an unusual phenomenon in condensed-matter physics. When quantum spins interact together as a system, they produce unique effects not seen in individual particles. Understanding how quantum spins interact to produce this behavior is cent…</description></item><item><title>Redefining Risk: Lessons from Medicine, Money, and Spaceflight - The White Coat Investor</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/redefining-risk-lessons-from-medicine-money-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/redefining-risk-lessons-from-medicine-money-a/</guid><description>Achieving my lifelong goal of going to space was worth the 40 years of work it took to get there. This is how I made it happen.</description></item><item><title>North America’s Greenhouse Hub - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/north-americas-greenhouse-hub-nasa-science-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/north-americas-greenhouse-hub-nasa-science-/</guid><description>The expansion of greenhouses in southern Ontario is changing the appearance of the land surface—and the night sky.</description></item><item><title>World’s slowest science lab experiment is still going and about to turn 100 years old - supercarblondie.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/worlds-slowest-science-lab-experiment-is-sti/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/worlds-slowest-science-lab-experiment-is-sti/</guid><description>The world’s longest continuously running lab experiment has been live for almost 100 years, and it’s not set to end anytime soon</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis II reaches the launch pad and the countdown to the Moon begins - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-reaches-the-launch-pad-and-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-reaches-the-launch-pad-and-/</guid><description>NASA’s Artemis II rocket has reached its launch pad after a painstaking overnight crawl across Kennedy Space Center. Engineers are now preparing for crucial fueling and countdown tests ahead of the first crewed Artemis mission. The mission will send four astr…</description></item><item><title>Scripps Memorial Hospital La Jolla received astronauts after splashdown - San Diego Union-Tribune</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scripps-memorial-hospital-la-jolla-received-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:24:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scripps-memorial-hospital-la-jolla-received-a/</guid><description>With its helipad capable of receiving heavy military helicopters, the medical center received the four astronauts aboard the SpaceX capsule that splashed down off the San Diego coast on Thursday</description></item><item><title>The way Earth’s surface moves has a bigger impact on shifting the climate than we knew - The Conversation</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-way-earths-surface-moves-has-a-bigger-im/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-way-earths-surface-moves-has-a-bigger-im/</guid><description>Earth has experienced many icehouse and greenhouse climates. A new study shows how they connect to plate tectonics.</description></item><item><title>Damaged DSN antenna out of service until May - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/damaged-dsn-antenna-out-of-service-until-may-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/damaged-dsn-antenna-out-of-service-until-may-/</guid><description>A key antenna in NASA’s Deep Space Network (DSN) that was damaged last fall is expected to remain offline until May.</description></item><item><title>New Brain Drugs Mimic Psychedelics Without the Hallucinations - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-brain-drugs-mimic-psychedelics-without-th/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-brain-drugs-mimic-psychedelics-without-th/</guid><description>Scientists at UC Davis created a new class of serotonin-targeting molecules using a light-driven chemical method. UC Davis scientists have created a light-based technique that converts amino acids — the building blocks of proteins — into new molecules with ps…</description></item><item><title>An armada of 6,500 Elite Dangerous players just embarked on a three-month expedition to explore the Milky Way, and there's still time to join them - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/an-armada-of-6500-elite-dangerous-players-jus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/an-armada-of-6500-elite-dangerous-players-jus/</guid><description>To explore strange new worlds; to seek out new life and new civilizations; to boldly go where no one has gone before!</description></item><item><title>Polar Storms on Jupiter And Saturn Reveal Deep Atmospheric Differences - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/polar-storms-on-jupiter-and-saturn-reveal-dee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/polar-storms-on-jupiter-and-saturn-reveal-dee/</guid><description>The two largest planets in the Solar System – Jupiter and Saturn – have a lot in common.</description></item><item><title>Physicists uncover hidden magnetic order in the mysterious pseudogap phase - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-uncover-hidden-magnetic-order-in-t/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-uncover-hidden-magnetic-order-in-t/</guid><description>Physicists have uncovered a link between magnetism and a mysterious phase of matter called the pseudogap, which appears in certain quantum materials just above the temperature at which they become superconducting. The findings could help researchers design ne…</description></item><item><title>Golden Gate method enables fully-synthetic engineering of therapeutically relevant bacteriophages - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/golden-gate-method-enables-fully-synthetic-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/golden-gate-method-enables-fully-synthetic-en/</guid><description>Bacteriophages have been used therapeutically to treat infectious bacterial diseases for over a century. As antibiotic-resistant infections increasingly threaten public health, interest in bacteriophages as therapeutics has seen a resurgence. However, the fie…</description></item><item><title>What deep sea mud is revealing about giant earthquakes along the Pacific Coast - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-deep-sea-mud-is-revealing-about-giant-ea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:44:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-deep-sea-mud-is-revealing-about-giant-ea/</guid><description>Marine turbidites are layers of mud and sand deposited on the deep ocean floor by massive underwater landslides and are often used as a historical record for reconstructing earthquake histories.</description></item><item><title>What the first medical evacuation from the International Space Station tells us about healthcare in space - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-the-first-medical-evacuation-from-the-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-the-first-medical-evacuation-from-the-in/</guid><description>The evacuation was the first such event in the history of the ISS.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Found Space Signals Inside Beach Sand, Here's What They Reveal About Earth's Ancient - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-space-signals-inside-beach-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-space-signals-inside-beach-s/</guid><description>Encased within each grain lies a microscopic archive of its exposure to the open sky, a new way of reading the Earth’s surface history.</description></item><item><title>Dinosaurs Were Thriving Until The Very End, New Study Finds - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dinosaurs-were-thriving-until-the-very-end-ne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dinosaurs-were-thriving-until-the-very-end-ne/</guid><description>New research reveals that dinosaurs were thriving across diverse ecosystems until a sudden asteroid impact ended their reign 66 million years ago.</description></item><item><title>First direct evidence of Migdal effect opens new path for dark matter search - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/first-direct-evidence-of-migdal-effect-opens-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/first-direct-evidence-of-migdal-effect-opens-/</guid><description>In a landmark discovery that bridges nearly a century of theoretical physics, a Chinese research team has successfully captured the first direct evidence of the Migdal effect, a breakthrough with profound implications for probing dark matter—the invisible sub…</description></item><item><title>How to find 4 legendary spacecraft in January's night sky - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-find-4-legendary-spacecraft-in-january/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-find-4-legendary-spacecraft-in-january/</guid><description>Along with bonus stargazing targets!</description></item><item><title>Some moral acts matter more than others, study shows - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/some-moral-acts-matter-more-than-others-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:54:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/some-moral-acts-matter-more-than-others-study/</guid><description>Every day, we quietly judge the people around us. Did that co-worker split the credit fairly? Did a neighbor return a lost package? Did someone cut in line or respect the rules?</description></item><item><title>NASA Found a Planet That Rains Glass at 5,400 MPH, And It Looks Like Earth - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-found-a-planet-that-rains-glass-at-5400-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-found-a-planet-that-rains-glass-at-5400-/</guid><description>This close orbit subjects the planet to continuous stellar bombardment, turning its atmosphere into a furnace of volatile activity.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Say a Major Quantum Computing Breakthrough Was Not What It Seemed - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-say-a-major-quantum-computing-brea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-say-a-major-quantum-computing-brea/</guid><description>Replication is a cornerstone of science, yet even in the natural sciences, attempts to reproduce results do not always succeed. Quantum computing promises machines that can solve certain problems far beyond today’s computers, but it faces a stubborn obstacle:…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Rebuild Face Of Ancient American After 8,500 Years: The Results Are Jaw-Dropping - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-rebuild-face-of-ancient-american-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-rebuild-face-of-ancient-american-a/</guid><description>A new facial reconstruction of the Kennewick Man reveals the face of one of America’s oldest humans, after 8,500 years buried in mystery.</description></item><item><title>Beta-decay half-life measurements reveal evolution of nuclear shell structure - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beta-decay-half-life-measurements-reveal-evol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beta-decay-half-life-measurements-reveal-evol/</guid><description>An international team of researchers has systematically measured the β-decay half-lives of 40 nuclei near calcium-54, providing key experimental data for understanding the structure of extremely neutron-rich nuclei.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Found a 97-Million-Year Magnetic Fossil, And It Points to a Lost Ocean Creature - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-found-a-97-million-year-magne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-found-a-97-million-year-magne/</guid><description>A strange set of magnetic fossils from the age of dinosaurs is making scientists wonder: did an extinct marine animal once navigate using Earth’s magnetic field?</description></item><item><title>Reborn black hole seen erupting across 1 million light-years of space like a cosmic volcano - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reborn-black-hole-seen-erupting-across-1-mill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reborn-black-hole-seen-erupting-across-1-mill/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like watching a cosmic volcano erupt again after ages of calm — except this one is big enough to carve out structures stretching nearly a million light-years across space.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Gold No Longer Inert: Scientists Created a Novel Gold Hydride Under Planetary Core Conditions - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-no-longer-inert-scientists-created-a-nov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-no-longer-inert-scientists-created-a-nov/</guid><description>Gold, long considered untouchable, has revealed a hidden side in a lab experiment that could upend chemistry, energy science, and everything we thought we knew about the periodic table.</description></item><item><title>China previews how powerful its new Xuntian space telescope will be ahead of 2027 launch (video) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/china-previews-how-powerful-its-new-xuntian-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/china-previews-how-powerful-its-new-xuntian-s/</guid><description>Mock observations test the performance of the Chinese Space Station Telescope as the 2-meter-class observatory moves closer to launch.</description></item><item><title>Are the Three Mini-Jets, Coming Out of 3I/ATLAS at 120 Degree Separation, a Technological Signature? - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-the-three-mini-jets-coming-out-of-3i/atla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-the-three-mini-jets-coming-out-of-3i/atla/</guid><description>Shortly after its perihelion passage on October 29, 2025, the interstellar object 3I/ATLAS was imaged by amateur astronomers to have…</description></item><item><title>Observing the positronium beam as a quantum matter wave for the first time - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/observing-the-positronium-beam-as-a-quantum-m/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/observing-the-positronium-beam-as-a-quantum-m/</guid><description>One of the discoveries that fundamentally distinguished the emerging field of quantum physics from classical physics was the observation that matter behaves differently at the smallest scales. A key finding was wave-particle duality, the revelation that parti…</description></item><item><title>Was the Red Planet once blue? New evidence points to an ancient ocean on Mars - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/was-the-red-planet-once-blue-new-evidence-poi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/was-the-red-planet-once-blue-new-evidence-poi/</guid><description>Ancient shoreline features hint that water on Mars once formed a vast ocean.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Giant Balloons Over Antarctica Just Made A Breakthrough In The Hunt For Dark Matter - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-giant-balloons-over-antarctica-just-ma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-giant-balloons-over-antarctica-just-ma/</guid><description>NASA’s latest Antarctic balloon missions uncover new clues about dark matter and cosmic particles, setting new records in near-space exploration.</description></item><item><title>Outer Space Is a Viscous Fluid, New Paper Claims - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/outer-space-is-a-viscous-fluid-new-paper-clai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/outer-space-is-a-viscous-fluid-new-paper-clai/</guid><description>A paper proposes that outer space acts like viscous fluid, which if true could explain discrepancies in observations of the universe.</description></item><item><title>Remnants of spills on Renaissance-era textbook reveal recipes for 'curing' ailments with lizard heads and human feces - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/remnants-of-spills-on-renaissance-era-textboo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/remnants-of-spills-on-renaissance-era-textboo/</guid><description>A novel biochemical analysis of a Renaissance medical text has successfully recovered centuries-old proteins that might be from lizards and hippos.</description></item><item><title>Sun erupts with powerful X-class flare as huge CME races toward Earth, impact possible within 24 hours - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-erupts-with-powerful-x-class-flare-as-hug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-erupts-with-powerful-x-class-flare-as-hug/</guid><description>Aurora alert! The colossal solar storm could impact and trigger impressive northern lights.</description></item><item><title>Nebra Sky Disc: The world's oldest depiction of astronomical phenomena — and it may depict the Pleiades - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nebra-sky-disc-the-worlds-oldest-depiction-of/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nebra-sky-disc-the-worlds-oldest-depiction-of/</guid><description>The unique bronze-and-gold Nebra Sky Disc appears to represent what the night sky looked like more than three millennia ago.</description></item><item><title>Quantum 'alchemy' made feasible with excitons - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-alchemy-made-feasible-with-excitons-p/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-alchemy-made-feasible-with-excitons-p/</guid><description>What if you could create new materials just by shining a light at them? To most, this sounds like science fiction or alchemy, but to physicists investigating the burgeoning field of Floquet engineering, this is the goal. With a periodic drive, like light, sci…</description></item><item><title>James Webb telescope reveals sharpest-ever look at the edge of a black hole — and it could solve a major galactic mystery - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-reveals-sharpest-ever-lo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-reveals-sharpest-ever-lo/</guid><description>The James Webb Space Telescope snapped its sharpest image of the area around a black hole, solving a long-standing galactic mystery.</description></item><item><title>Viruses that evolved on the space station and were sent back to Earth were more effective at killing bacteria - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/viruses-that-evolved-on-the-space-station-and/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/viruses-that-evolved-on-the-space-station-and/</guid><description>Near-weightless conditions can mutate genes and alter the physical structures of bacteria and phages, disrupting their normal interactions in ways that could help us treat drug-resistant infections.</description></item><item><title>Experiments bring Enceladus' subsurface ocean into the lab - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experiments-bring-enceladus-subsurface-ocean-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experiments-bring-enceladus-subsurface-ocean-/</guid><description>Through new experiments, researchers in Japan and Germany have recreated the chemical conditions found in the subsurface ocean of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon, Enceladus. Published in Icarus, the results show that these conditions can readily produce many of the organic com…</description></item><item><title>Frozen Chemical Once Feared by Scientists May Have Ignited Life on Earth - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-chemical-once-feared-by-scientists-may/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-chemical-once-feared-by-scientists-may/</guid><description>A frozen chemical thought to be deadly is now revealing unexpected powers, scientists didn’t see this one coming.</description></item><item><title>New Fossil Discovery Could Kick Lucy Out of the Human Family Tree - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fossil-discovery-could-kick-lucy-out-of-t/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fossil-discovery-could-kick-lucy-out-of-t/</guid><description>Scientists have found fossil bones that could dethrone lucy as our most famous ancestor.</description></item><item><title>Northern Lights Forecast: Aurora Could Be Visible From These 10 States - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-aurora-could-be-visi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:03:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-aurora-could-be-visi/</guid><description>The aurora borealis could be visible from states along the U.S.-Canadian border.</description></item><item><title>What is below Earth, since space is present in every direction? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-below-earth-since-space-is-present-in/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-below-earth-since-space-is-present-in/</guid><description>Which way is ‘down’ has a different answer depending on where you are on Earth, in the solar system, in our galaxy and beyond.</description></item><item><title>NASA launches Pandora telescope, taking JWST's search for habitable worlds to a new level - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-launches-pandora-telescope-taking-jwsts-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-launches-pandora-telescope-taking-jwsts-/</guid><description>The findings from Pandora will complement data from the James Webb Space Telescope to give astronomers more insight into stars and planets outside our solar system.</description></item><item><title>New moon of January 2026 brings prime views of Jupiter, Saturn and winter stars tonight - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-moon-of-january-2026-brings-prime-views-o/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-moon-of-january-2026-brings-prime-views-o/</guid><description>With the moon out of the way on Jan. 18, bright Jupiter and Saturn become stand-outs in the January night sky.</description></item><item><title>Mars: Scientists Have Figured Out How Blue The Red Planet Used to Be - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-scientists-have-figured-out-how-blue-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:02:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-scientists-have-figured-out-how-blue-the/</guid><description>Mars is absolutely dripping with evidence that the red planet was once a striking blue, complete with glistening lakes, snaking rivers, and vast oceans.</description></item><item><title>Hubble Telescope watches star blast out jet of hot gas 32 light-years long - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-telescope-watches-star-blast-out-jet-o/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-telescope-watches-star-blast-out-jet-o/</guid><description>The protostar is launching the longest outburst ever seen at 32 light-years long.</description></item><item><title>James Webb telescope spots 'failed stars' in a breathtaking cluster near Earth — Space photo of the week - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-spots-failed-stars-in-a-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-spots-failed-stars-in-a-/</guid><description>The James Webb Space Telescope captured a colorful portrait of a nearby stellar cradle, revealing a wealth of insights about countless stars.</description></item><item><title>China's Shenzhou-21 crew continues with science experiments, life in orbit - news.cgtn.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinas-shenzhou-21-crew-continues-with-scienc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:55:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinas-shenzhou-21-crew-continues-with-scienc/</guid><description>China&amp;rsquo;s Shenzhou-21 astronauts have steadily advanced scientific experiments in several fields aboard China&amp;rsquo;s space station over the past week.The crew consists of mission commander Zhang Lu and astronauts Wu Fei and Zhang Hongzhang. They have been in</description></item><item><title>The evolutionary upside of same-sex sex among primates - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-evolutionary-upside-of-same-sex-sex-among/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:03:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-evolutionary-upside-of-same-sex-sex-among/</guid><description>New science suggests why monkeys and other primates engage in same-sex relations</description></item><item><title>A 47-year study reveals when fitness and strength start to fade - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-47-year-study-reveals-when-fitness-and-stre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-47-year-study-reveals-when-fitness-and-stre/</guid><description>A long-running Swedish study has followed adults for nearly five decades, uncovering when physical decline truly begins. Fitness and strength start slipping around age 35, then worsen gradually with age. The encouraging twist: adults who began exercising late…</description></item><item><title>NASA's new moon rocket moves to the pad ahead of astronaut launch as early as February - KSL.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-moon-rocket-moves-to-the-pad-ahead-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:26:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-moon-rocket-moves-to-the-pad-ahead-/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s giant new moon rocket moved to the launch pad Saturday in preparation for astronauts' first lunar fly-around in more than half a century.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Rewrote the Story of the Dinosaurs’ Final Days - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-rewrote-the-story-of-the-dino/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:54:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-rewrote-the-story-of-the-dino/</guid><description>Fossils reveal dinosaurs were flourishing in diverse ecosystems right up until the asteroid impact ended their reign.</description></item><item><title>Scientists issue warning that hidden 'ice volcanoes' could awaken: 'Talking about chaos' - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-issue-warning-that-hidden-ice-volc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-issue-warning-that-hidden-ice-volc/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Awakening after a decade of slumber.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Insects listen to plants 'talking' before deciding where to lay eggs, breakthrough study shows - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/insects-listen-to-plants-talking-before-decid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:39:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/insects-listen-to-plants-talking-before-decid/</guid><description>Female moths avoid laying eggs on stressed plants that emit ultrasonic sounds. Instead, they choose silent, healthy plants.</description></item><item><title>Artemis 2 rocket rollout latest news: Giant NASA moon rocket arrives at launch pad - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-rocket-rollout-latest-news-giant-na/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-rocket-rollout-latest-news-giant-na/</guid><description>Saturday, Jan. 17, 2026: See our latest news and updates on NASA&amp;rsquo;s Artemis 2 moon rocket rollout to the launch pad.</description></item><item><title>Something Hidden Beneath Greenland Is Speeding Up Global Ice Loss - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-hidden-beneath-greenland-is-speedin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-hidden-beneath-greenland-is-speedin/</guid><description>A newly discovered feature beneath Greenland’s ice sheet could dramatically reshape predictions for future sea-level rise.</description></item><item><title>A New Census of Dwarf Galaxies Shows More Massive Black Holes than Previously Thought - Universe Today</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-census-of-dwarf-galaxies-shows-more-mas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-census-of-dwarf-galaxies-shows-more-mas/</guid><description>A new census of more than 8,000 galaxies finds active black holes rising in frequency with galaxy mass, jumping sharply in galaxies similar in mass to the Milky Way.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious iron 'bar' discovered in famous nebula - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-iron-bar-discovered-in-famous-nebu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-iron-bar-discovered-in-famous-nebu/</guid><description>A mysterious bar-shaped cloud of iron has been discovered inside the iconic Ring Nebula by a European team led by astronomers at University College London (UCL) and Cardiff University.</description></item><item><title>New insights into how the famed Antikythera Mechanism may have worked - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-insights-into-how-the-famed-antikythera-m/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-insights-into-how-the-famed-antikythera-m/</guid><description>New simulations suggest that the Antikythera Mechanism may have jammed within months, as small errors in the spacing.</description></item><item><title>This Breakthrough Image Sensor Lets Scientists See Tiny Details From Far Away - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-breakthrough-image-sensor-lets-scientist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:16:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-breakthrough-image-sensor-lets-scientist/</guid><description>A new lens-free imaging system uses software to see finer details from farther away than optical systems ever could before.</description></item><item><title>Northern Lights Forecast: 10 States Could See Aurora Borealis Saturday And Sunday - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-10-states-could-see-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:48:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-10-states-could-see-/</guid><description>The Northern Lights could be “quite pleasing to look at” this weekend in parts of the US due to fast solar winds, NOAA says.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover Greenland's 'Achilles heel' that is driving its rapid ice melt - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-greenlands-achilles-heel-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-greenlands-achilles-heel-/</guid><description>Soft sediments hidden beneath Greenland&amp;rsquo;s ice could accelerate glacier flow, speeding up ice loss and future sea level rise.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover a plant that appears to have stolen genes from another species - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-plant-that-appears-to-h/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:47:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-plant-that-appears-to-h/</guid><description>A plant named Virectaria stellata has genetic traits foreign to its family, challenging the classic rules of plant inheritance.</description></item><item><title>NASA rolls out Artemis II craft ahead of crewed lunar orbit - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-rolls-out-artemis-ii-craft-ahead-of-crew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:12:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-rolls-out-artemis-ii-craft-ahead-of-crew/</guid><description>Mission Artemis plans to send Americans to the moon for the first time since the Nixon administration.</description></item><item><title>This is SPARDA: A self-destruct, self-defense system in bacteria that could be a new biotech tool - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-is-sparda-a-self-destruct-self-defense-s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-is-sparda-a-self-destruct-self-defense-s/</guid><description>A bacterial defense system called SPARDA employs kamikaze-like tactics to protect cells and could be useful in future biotechnologies.</description></item><item><title>Startup company wants to light up the night skies with reflected sunlight - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/startup-company-wants-to-light-up-the-night-s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:40:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/startup-company-wants-to-light-up-the-night-s/</guid><description>A company called Reflect Orbital wants to illuminate the Earth after sunset with orbital sky mirrors, raising alarm bells.</description></item><item><title>Most detailed map yet of Antarctica under the ice - Boing Boing</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-detailed-map-yet-of-antarctica-under-the/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-detailed-map-yet-of-antarctica-under-the/</guid><description>Researchers used satellite data and computer models of glacial movements to create a new map of Antarctica as it rests deep beneath the ice. The high-resolution imagery reveals the frozen…</description></item><item><title>Study finds albumin, the most abundant blood protein, acts as a shield against deadly fungal infections - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/study-finds-albumin-the-most-abundant-blood-p/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/study-finds-albumin-the-most-abundant-blood-p/</guid><description>Scientists at the Institute of Molecular Biology and Biotechnology (IMBB-FORTH) and the University of Crete, together with collaborators from Greece, Europe, the U.S., and India, have discovered a novel role of albumin, the most abundant protein in human bloo…</description></item><item><title>Japan Just Shut Down a Spacecraft That Cheated Death for 10 Years, Here's What It Saw on Venus - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-just-shut-down-a-spacecraft-that-cheate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-just-shut-down-a-spacecraft-that-cheate/</guid><description>It was Japan’s first leap beyond Earth orbit, and it didn’t go as planned.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious Underwater 'Atlantis' Is Like a Lost City in The Ocean - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-underwater-atlantis-is-like-a-lost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-underwater-atlantis-is-like-a-lost/</guid><description>In the shimmering blue waters off Japan&amp;rsquo;s Yonaguni Island lies a geological wonder.</description></item><item><title>1 month until a 'ring of fire' annular solar eclipse puts on a show — mostly for penguins - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1-month-until-a-ring-of-fire-annular-solar-ec/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1-month-until-a-ring-of-fire-annular-solar-ec/</guid><description>The first solar eclipse of the year will take place on Feb. 17, 2026.</description></item><item><title>Myth of wormholes and the quantum meaning of Einstein-Rosen Bridge - Interesting Engineering</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/myth-of-wormholes-and-the-quantum-meaning-of-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/myth-of-wormholes-and-the-quantum-meaning-of-/</guid><description>A new study goes back to the original problem Einstein and Rosen were tackling and reinterprets it using modern ideas from quantum theory—especially how time works at the smallest scales.</description></item><item><title>Science news this week: ISS medical evacuation, Mars Sample Return canceled, and woolly rhino flesh found in permafrost wolf - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/science-news-this-week-iss-medical-evacuation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/science-news-this-week-iss-medical-evacuation/</guid><description>Jan. 17, 2026: Our weekly roundup of the latest science in the news, as well as a few fascinating articles to keep you entertained over the weekend.</description></item><item><title>Astronauts’ Brains Are Being Displaced - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-brains-are-being-displaced-futuri/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-brains-are-being-displaced-futuri/</guid><description>Researchers found that the brain &amp;ldquo;shifts upward and backward within the skull following spaceflight,&amp;rdquo; a new wrinkle for future space travel.</description></item><item><title>A Yellowstone National Park Caldera Is Uplifting For The First Time In Years - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-yellowstone-national-park-caldera-is-uplift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-yellowstone-national-park-caldera-is-uplift/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s an area bigger than Chicago, and it seems to be inflating. So should we worry?</description></item><item><title>Alone in Space, a Chinese Astronaut Heard Something Knock on His Capsule 300 KM Above Earth - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/alone-in-space-a-chinese-astronaut-heard-some/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/alone-in-space-a-chinese-astronaut-heard-some/</guid><description>What Yang Liwei heard during China’s first crewed spaceflight still defies physics, sensors, and every known explanation.</description></item><item><title>Weird Jet Geometry Around 3I/ATLAS in Hubble Images from January 14, 2026 - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weird-jet-geometry-around-3i/atlas-in-hubble-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weird-jet-geometry-around-3i/atlas-in-hubble-/</guid><description>A new set of six images, taken by the Hubble Space Telescope on January 14, 2026, show the brightness map of the glowing halo surrounding…</description></item><item><title>How much of your body could you lose — and still survive? - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-much-of-your-body-could-you-lose-and-st/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-much-of-your-body-could-you-lose-and-st/</guid><description>Five vital organs are essential for life, but survival is more medically complex.</description></item><item><title>‘Over the next hour, it’s dispatched, dismantled and butchered, piece by piece.’ This may be the most savage ambush attack we’ve ever heard - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/over-the-next-hour-its-dispatched-dismantled/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:49:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/over-the-next-hour-its-dispatched-dismantled/</guid><description>Discover a delicate alliance between shrub, fungus and tiny forest guardians in the Amazonian understorey</description></item><item><title>NASA’s SpaceX Crew-11 to Discuss Space Station Science Mission - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-spacex-crew-11-to-discuss-space-statio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:19:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-spacex-crew-11-to-discuss-space-statio/</guid><description>After 167 days in space, the crew members of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-11 mission will hold a news conference at 2:15 p.m. EST, Wednesday, Jan. 21, at the agency’s</description></item><item><title>Crew-11 astronauts arrive in Houston after 1st-ever medical evacuation from ISS - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/crew-11-astronauts-arrive-in-houston-after-1s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/crew-11-astronauts-arrive-in-houston-after-1s/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;All crew members remain stable.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Indra Group writes off damaged SpainSat NG 2 - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/indra-group-writes-off-damaged-spainsat-ng-2-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/indra-group-writes-off-damaged-spainsat-ng-2-/</guid><description>The operator of a Spanish military communications satellite that suffered a “space particle” strike has written off the spacecraft.</description></item><item><title>Satellites Capture the Hidden World Beneath Antarctica’s Ice - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellites-capture-the-hidden-world-beneath-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellites-capture-the-hidden-world-beneath-a/</guid><description>A new map of the landscape beneath the continent&amp;rsquo;s ice sheet reveals a previously undiscovered terrain.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Reveal Why Humans Lost Their Fur, And It’s Not What You Think - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-humans-lost-their-fur-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-humans-lost-their-fur-a/</guid><description>Scientists uncover the genetic “off switches” that made humans lose their fur.</description></item><item><title>Liquid gears could challenge 5,000 years of mechanical engineering - TechSpot</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/liquid-gears-could-challenge-5000-years-of-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/liquid-gears-could-challenge-5000-years-of-me/</guid><description>The study, published January 13 in Physical Review Letters, replaces the metal or plastic cogs of conventional gears with controlled flows of liquid. In their experiments, NYU&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Uncover Hidden Earthquake Threat Lurking Beneath Northern California’s Fault Zone - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-hidden-earthquake-threat-l/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-hidden-earthquake-threat-l/</guid><description>Tiny, nearly undetectable earthquakes beneath Northern California are offering scientists new insights into the complex tectonic processes at play in the region’s most dangerous fault zones.</description></item><item><title>Neutralizing extracellular electron transport disarms antibiotic-resistant bacteria, restores healing in chronic wounds - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/neutralizing-extracellular-electron-transport/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/neutralizing-extracellular-electron-transport/</guid><description>An international team of scientists, led by Nanyang Technological University, Singapore (NTU Singapore), has discovered a new method that could speed up the healing of chronic wounds infected by antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</description></item><item><title>Mars Has A Massive Impact On Earth’s Climate, New Study Suggests - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-has-a-massive-impact-on-earths-climate-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-has-a-massive-impact-on-earths-climate-/</guid><description>New research reveals that Mars’ gravity quietly stabilizes Earth’s climate.</description></item><item><title>Imaging technique captures ultrafast electron and atom dynamics in chemical reactions - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-technique-captures-ultrafast-electron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:20:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-technique-captures-ultrafast-electron/</guid><description>During chemical reactions, atoms in the reacting substances break their bonds and re-arrange, forming different chemical products. This process entails the movement of both electrons (i.e., negatively charged particles) and nuclei (i.e., the positively charge…</description></item><item><title>Why Mars is Actively Manufacturing Poison - Universe Today</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-mars-is-actively-manufacturing-poison-uni/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-mars-is-actively-manufacturing-poison-uni/</guid><description>Chemistry on other worlds varies widely from that on Earth. Much of Earth’s chemistry is driven by well-understood processes, which typically involve water and heat in some form. Mars lacks both of those features, which makes how some of its chemicals formed …</description></item><item><title>85 Remarkably Preserved Human Footprints Have Emerged on a Moroccan Beach - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/85-remarkably-preserved-human-footprints-have/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/85-remarkably-preserved-human-footprints-have/</guid><description>While exploring a quiet beach in northern Morocco, a team of scientists spotted what looked like ancient human footprints in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover a Hidden World Thriving with Life in Earth’s Driest Desert - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-hidden-world-thriving-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-hidden-world-thriving-w/</guid><description>Scientists have uncovered a thriving ecosystem beneath the Atacama Desert&amp;rsquo;s surface.</description></item><item><title>NASA's Mars Sample Return is dead, leaving China to retrieve signs of life from the Red Planet - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-mars-sample-return-is-dead-leaving-chin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-mars-sample-return-is-dead-leaving-chin/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s plans for Mars sample return are effectively cancelled as part of a bill approved by the U.S. Congress, ending efforts to collect Perseverance rover samples that could contain evidence of alien life.</description></item><item><title>3D-printed low-voltage-driven ciliary hydrogel microactuators - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/3d-printed-low-voltage-driven-ciliary-hydroge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:54:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/3d-printed-low-voltage-driven-ciliary-hydroge/</guid><description>3D-printed gel microcilia arrays printed by two-photon polymerization and composed of a soft acrylic acid-co-acrylamide hydrogel with a nanometre-scale network structure are shown to respond to low-voltage electrical stimuli within milliseconds, ena…</description></item><item><title>In the stomach of a mummified wolf pup, scientists find DNA from a woolly rhinoceros - NBC News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-the-stomach-of-a-mummified-wolf-pup-scient/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:36:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-the-stomach-of-a-mummified-wolf-pup-scient/</guid><description>Inside the stomach of an ancient wolf puppy found entombed in Siberian permafrost, scientists discovered meat from a woolly rhinoceros — and sequenced its genome.</description></item><item><title>SpaceX breaks pad turnaround record at Cape Canaveral with midday Starlink launch - Spaceflight Now</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-breaks-pad-turnaround-record-at-cape-c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:27:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-breaks-pad-turnaround-record-at-cape-c/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>Detailed map reveals groundwater levels across the U.S. - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/detailed-map-reveals-groundwater-levels-acros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:21:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/detailed-map-reveals-groundwater-levels-acros/</guid><description>How much fresh water is in the United States? It&amp;rsquo;s a tough question, since most of the water is underground, accessible at varying depths. In previous decades, it&amp;rsquo;s been answered indirectly from data on rainfall and evaporation. Knowing how much groundwater i…</description></item><item><title>Jupiter's hidden depths: Simulation suggests planet holds 1.5 times more oxygen than the sun - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-hidden-depths-simulation-suggests-pl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:36:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-hidden-depths-simulation-suggests-pl/</guid><description>Spectacular clouds swirl across the surface of Jupiter. These clouds contain water, just like Earth&amp;rsquo;s, but are much denser on the gas giant—so thick that no spacecraft has been able to measure exactly what lies beneath.</description></item><item><title>Dominant contribution of Asgard archaea to eukaryogenesis - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dominant-contribution-of-asgard-archaea-to-eu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dominant-contribution-of-asgard-archaea-to-eu/</guid><description>A survey of the reconstructed gene set of the last eukaryotic common ancestor shows a consistent link between Asgard archaea and the origin of numerous, functionally diverse eukaryotic genes, demonstrating the dominant Asgard contribution to eukaryogenes…</description></item><item><title>Retraction Note: Antibodies against endogenous retroviruses promote lung cancer immunotherapy - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/retraction-note-antibodies-against-endogenous/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/retraction-note-antibodies-against-endogenous/</guid><description>Nature - Retraction Note: Antibodies against endogenous retroviruses promote lung cancer immunotherapy</description></item><item><title>Little red dots as young supermassive black holes in dense ionized cocoons - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/little-red-dots-as-young-supermassive-black-h/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:06:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/little-red-dots-as-young-supermassive-black-h/</guid><description>The highest-quality JWST spectra reveal that little red dots are young supermassive black holes shrouded in dense cocoons of ionized gas, where electron scattering, not Doppler motions, broadens their spectral lines.</description></item><item><title>How Mars' ancient lakes grew shields of ice to stay warm as the Red Planet froze - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-mars-ancient-lakes-grew-shields-of-ice-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-mars-ancient-lakes-grew-shields-of-ice-to/</guid><description>The findings potentially solve the paradox of how liquid water seems to have persisted on Mars even when the climate grew too cold.</description></item><item><title>New Image of the Milky Way Reveals Massive Hidden Structures, What’s Out There? - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-image-of-the-milky-way-reveals-massive-hi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-image-of-the-milky-way-reveals-massive-hi/</guid><description>This new map of the galaxy is so detailed it’ll make your head spin.</description></item><item><title>New state of matter discovered in a quantum material - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-state-of-matter-discovered-in-a-quantum-m/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-state-of-matter-discovered-in-a-quantum-m/</guid><description>At TU Wien, researchers have discovered a state in a quantum material that had previously been considered impossible. The definition of topological states should be generalized.</description></item><item><title>Video captures a baby hummingbird behaving like a poisonous caterpillar to fool predators - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/video-captures-a-baby-hummingbird-behaving-li/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/video-captures-a-baby-hummingbird-behaving-li/</guid><description>A white-necked jacobin hummingbird chick surprises scientists, scaring away wasps by mimicking a poisonous caterpillar.</description></item><item><title>The universe should be packed with tiny galaxies — so where are they? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-universe-should-be-packed-with-tiny-galax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-universe-should-be-packed-with-tiny-galax/</guid><description>There may not be as nearly as many small galaxies in the early universe as astronomers predict there should be, which has big implications for the story of how our universe grew up.</description></item><item><title>T. rex grew up slowly: New study reveals 'king of dinosaurs' kept growing until age 40 - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/t-rex-grew-up-slowly-new-study-reveals-king-o/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/t-rex-grew-up-slowly-new-study-reveals-king-o/</guid><description>For decades, scientists have been counting annual growth rings—similar to tree rings—inside fossilized leg bones of Tyrannosaurus rex to estimate how old the giant carnivores were when they died and how quickly they grew to adulthood. The best estimates from …</description></item><item><title>Most complete Homo habilis skeleton ever found dates to more than 2 million years ago and retains 'Lucy'-like features - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-complete-homo-habilis-skeleton-ever-foun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-complete-homo-habilis-skeleton-ever-foun/</guid><description>Scientists have revealed the most complete skeleton yet of our 2 million-year-old ancestor Homo habilis.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover Bizarre Form Of Water That’s Both Solid And Liquid - Study Finds</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-bizarre-form-of-water-tha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-bizarre-form-of-water-tha/</guid><description>Scientists discover water that&amp;rsquo;s solid and liquid. Superionic ice found in lab could explain Uranus and Neptune&amp;rsquo;s bizarre magnetic fields.</description></item><item><title>When does the Nasa Moon mission launch and who are the Artemis II crew? - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/when-does-the-nasa-moon-mission-launch-and-wh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:13:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/when-does-the-nasa-moon-mission-launch-and-wh/</guid><description>The first crewed Moon mission in 50 years could launch in February, preparing the way for a future landing.</description></item></channel></rss>