<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>science on Newsround</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/tags/science/</link><description>Recent content in science on Newsround</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://newsround.github.io/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optical Combs Help Radio Telescopes Work Together - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/optical-combs-help-radio-telescopes-work-toge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/optical-combs-help-radio-telescopes-work-toge/</guid><description>Very-long baseline interferometry (VLBI) is a technique in radio astronomy whereby multiple radio telescopes cooperate to bundle their received data and in effect create a much larger singular radi…</description></item><item><title>It May Be Safe to Nuke an Earthbound Asteroid After All, Simulation Suggests - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/it-may-be-safe-to-nuke-an-earthbound-asteroid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/it-may-be-safe-to-nuke-an-earthbound-asteroid/</guid><description>Could humanity nuke an incoming asteroid to deflect it and save the Earth, disaster-movie style? A unique new impact simulation suggests that a nuclear option could be a viable last resort to avert an apocalypse.</description></item><item><title>We’re Nowhere Near Ready to Make Babies in Space, Experts Warn - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/were-nowhere-near-ready-to-make-babies-in-spa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/were-nowhere-near-ready-to-make-babies-in-spa/</guid><description>If we want to colonize space, we need to figure out the whole reproduction thing.</description></item><item><title>Space tourism raises ‘urgent’ fertility questions, Nasa says - The Times</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/space-tourism-raises-urgent-fertility-questio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/space-tourism-raises-urgent-fertility-questio/</guid><description>As more people travel beyond Earth, scientists have warned that the risks to reproductive health from zero-gravity and radiation remain little understood</description></item><item><title>The 3-Body Problem Just Got an Upgrade—and You Can Thank Einstein - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-3-body-problem-just-got-an-upgradeand-yo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:05:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-3-body-problem-just-got-an-upgradeand-yo/</guid><description>A double sunset appears to be a true rarity in the cosmos, and general relativity explains why.</description></item><item><title>Reddit Mod Deleted Breathtaking Photo Taken by NASA Astronaut From Space Because It Was Blurry - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reddit-mod-deleted-breathtaking-photo-taken-b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reddit-mod-deleted-breathtaking-photo-taken-b/</guid><description>A moderator at the r/aviation subreddit didn&amp;rsquo;t look too kindly on a shot by astronaut Don Pettit, deeming it too &amp;ldquo;blurry&amp;rdquo; and taking it down.</description></item><item><title>Supermassive black holes sit in 'eye of their own storms,' studies find - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/supermassive-black-holes-sit-in-eye-of-their/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:42:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/supermassive-black-holes-sit-in-eye-of-their/</guid><description>Gigantic black holes lurk at the center of virtually every galaxy, including ours, but we&amp;rsquo;ve lacked a precise picture of what impact they have on their surroundings. However, a University of Chicago-led group of scientists has used data from a recently launch…</description></item><item><title>Physicists achieve near-zero friction on macroscopic scales - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-achieve-near-zero-friction-on-macr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-achieve-near-zero-friction-on-macr/</guid><description>For the first time, physicists in China have virtually eliminated the friction felt between two surfaces at scales visible to the naked eye. In demonstrating &amp;ldquo;structural superlubricity,&amp;rdquo; the team, led by Quanshui Zheng at Tsinghua University, have resolved a …</description></item><item><title>2.6-million-year-old jawbone changes the story of human history - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/26-million-year-old-jawbone-changes-the-story/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:46:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/26-million-year-old-jawbone-changes-the-story/</guid><description>A fossil jaw found in Ethiopia shows Paranthropus ranged far north, challenging long-held ideas about early human relatives and their diets.</description></item><item><title>A new class of strange one-dimensional particles - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-class-of-strange-one-dimensional-partic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-class-of-strange-one-dimensional-partic/</guid><description>Physicists have long categorized every elementary particle in our three-dimensional universe as being either a boson or a fermion—the former category mostly capturing force carriers like photons, the latter including the building blocks of everyday matter lik…</description></item><item><title>Jupiter’s New Measurements: Flatter, Squashed, Still the Biggest Boy - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-new-measurements-flatter-squashed-st/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-new-measurements-flatter-squashed-st/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Textbooks will need to be updated.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Did we just see a black hole explode? Physicists think so—and it could explain (almost) everything - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/did-we-just-see-a-black-hole-explode-physicis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/did-we-just-see-a-black-hole-explode-physicis/</guid><description>In 2023, a subatomic particle called a neutrino crashed into Earth with such a high amount of energy that it should have been impossible. In fact, there are no known sources anywhere in the universe capable of producing such energy—100,000 times more than the…</description></item><item><title>Many people have no mental imagery. What’s going on in their brains? - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/many-people-have-no-mental-imagery-whats-goin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:07:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/many-people-have-no-mental-imagery-whats-goin/</guid><description>People with aphantasia are offering a window into consciousness.</description></item><item><title>There's a unique asteroid in space worth $10,000,000,000,000,000,000 that could make everyone on Earth a billionaire - supercarblondie.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/theres-a-unique-asteroid-in-space-worth-1000/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/theres-a-unique-asteroid-in-space-worth-1000/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a unique asteroid in space worth around $10 billion billion, and if NASA was feelign generous, it could make us all billionaires</description></item><item><title>NASA waves off February launch for Artemis II moon mission; now targeting early March - Spaceflight Now</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-waves-off-february-launch-for-artemis-ii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:11:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-waves-off-february-launch-for-artemis-ii/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>NASA begins mission to map the boundaries of our heliosphere - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-begins-mission-to-map-the-boundaries-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:07:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-begins-mission-to-map-the-boundaries-of/</guid><description>A NASA mission is underway to map the heliosphere, which is a huge protective bubble around the solar system that was created by the sun.</description></item><item><title>This May Be the Oldest Known Victim of a Bear Attack—and It’s Brutal - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-may-be-the-oldest-known-victim-of-a-bear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:05:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-may-be-the-oldest-known-victim-of-a-bear/</guid><description>At least they had a nice burial?</description></item><item><title>Scientists Reveal Why the Green River Cuts Straight Through One of America's Biggest Mountains - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-the-green-river-cuts-st/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-the-green-river-cuts-st/</guid><description>Is this the biggest geological discovery of the year? The secret behind the green river’s path uncovered!</description></item><item><title>What Happens If Science Finally Explains Consciousness? A New Study Explores the Consequences - The Debrief</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-happens-if-science-finally-explains-cons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-happens-if-science-finally-explains-cons/</guid><description>Consciousness remains science’s greatest mystery. A new study explores how it arises—and why solving it could reshape existence.</description></item><item><title>Ultra-thin metasurface can generate and direct quantum entanglement - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ultra-thin-metasurface-can-generate-and-direc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:50:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ultra-thin-metasurface-can-generate-and-direc/</guid><description>Quantum technologies, devices and systems that process, store, detect, or transfer information leveraging quantum mechanical effects, have the potential to outperform classical technologies in a variety of tasks. An ongoing quest within quantum engineering is…</description></item><item><title>SpaceX pauses Falcon 9 launches after upper stage anomaly - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-pauses-falcon-9-launches-after-upper-s/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:29:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-pauses-falcon-9-launches-after-upper-s/</guid><description>SpaceX is pausing Falcon 9 launches after an issue with the rocket’s upper stage encountered at the end of a launch Feb. 2.</description></item><item><title>Two huge hot blobs of rock influence Earth's magnetic field, study reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-huge-hot-blobs-of-rock-influence-earths-m/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-huge-hot-blobs-of-rock-influence-earths-m/</guid><description>Exploring Earth&amp;rsquo;s deep interior is a far bigger challenge than exploring the solar system. While we have traveled 25 billion km into space, the deepest we have ever gone below our feet is just over 12 km. Consequently, little is known about the conditions at …</description></item><item><title>Have you got what it takes to go to the Moon? - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/have-you-got-what-it-takes-to-go-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/have-you-got-what-it-takes-to-go-to-the-moon/</guid><description>When the Artemis mission lands on the Moon, its crew will have to grapple with a challenging environment and extreme isolation. What will it take to thrive in a lonely Moon base?</description></item><item><title>Physicists push thousands of atoms to a 'Schrödinger's cat' state — bringing the quantum world closer to reality than ever before - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-push-thousands-of-atoms-to-a-schr%C3%B6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-push-thousands-of-atoms-to-a-schr%C3%B6/</guid><description>Researchers have demonstrated that a nanoparticle of 7,000 sodium atoms can act as a wave, creating a record-setting superposition.</description></item><item><title>Are cats 'vegan' meat eaters? Why isotopic signatures of feline fur could trick us into thinking that way - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-cats-vegan-meat-eaters-why-isotopic-signa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 05:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-cats-vegan-meat-eaters-why-isotopic-signa/</guid><description>Cats—unlike humans—are true carnivores: they must eat meat to survive because their bodies can&amp;rsquo;t draw some essential nutrients from plants. By looking at tissues, researchers can get a good understanding of what foods animals ate.</description></item><item><title>Sun Fires Off 4 Powerful Flares as More 'Exciting Activity' Is Forecast - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-fires-off-4-powerful-flares-as-more-excit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 04:22:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-fires-off-4-powerful-flares-as-more-excit/</guid><description>The Sun has unleashed a quartet of strong solar flares, which could herald a wild week of space weather.</description></item><item><title>It's Official: Astronomers Detect Complex Sulfur Molecule in Interstellar Space - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/its-official-astronomers-detect-complex-sulfu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 01:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/its-official-astronomers-detect-complex-sulfu/</guid><description>In the heart of our galaxy, scientists have discovered the largest sulfur-bearing molecule ever detected beyond Earth, with significant implications for the study of the cosmic origins of life.</description></item><item><title>We ate space mushrooms and survived to tell the tale - The Conversation</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-ate-space-mushrooms-and-survived-to-tell-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-ate-space-mushrooms-and-survived-to-tell-t/</guid><description>The mushrooms lived in space for over a month – and could be key to the health of astronauts in the future.</description></item><item><title>Bleached Martian rocks offer fresh evidence of a wetter and warmer Mars: 'But where did they come from? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bleached-martian-rocks-offer-fresh-evidence-o/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bleached-martian-rocks-offer-fresh-evidence-o/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;You need so much water that we think these could be evidence of an ancient warmer and wetter climate where there was rain falling for millions of years.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Cells adapt to aging by actively remodeling endoplasmic reticulum, study reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cells-adapt-to-aging-by-actively-remodeling-e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cells-adapt-to-aging-by-actively-remodeling-e/</guid><description>Improvements in public health have allowed humankind to survive to older ages than ever before, but, for many people, these added golden years are not spent in good health. Aging is a natural part of life, but it is associated with a greatly increased inciden…</description></item><item><title>Newly identified RNA molecule may drive cancer patient survival - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/newly-identified-rna-molecule-may-drive-cance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:46:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/newly-identified-rna-molecule-may-drive-cance/</guid><description>In a recent study, researchers at the Texas A&amp;amp;M University Health Science Center (Texas A&amp;amp;M Health) identify a novel RNA molecule that plays a crucial role in preserving the integrity of a key cellular structure, the nucleolus . Their findings also su…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Uncover Thousands Of Mysterious Creatures Lurking Near A Deep-Sea Volcano - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-thousands-of-mysterious-cr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:21:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-thousands-of-mysterious-cr/</guid><description>A newly studied deep-sea hotspot reveals thousands of creatures lurking in warmth and darkness near an underwater volcano.</description></item><item><title>Tiny New Species of Herbivorous Dinosaur Unearthed in Spain - Sci.News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tiny-new-species-of-herbivorous-dinosaur-unea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:55:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tiny-new-species-of-herbivorous-dinosaur-unea/</guid><description>A new genus and species of diminutive bipedal dinosaur has been identified from the fossils found in Burgos province of Spain.</description></item><item><title>AI finds hundreds of never-before-seen 'cosmic anomalies' in old Hubble Telescope images - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-finds-hundreds-of-never-before-seen-cosmic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-finds-hundreds-of-never-before-seen-cosmic/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;This is a powerful demonstration of how AI can enhance the scientific return of archival datasets.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Earth's largest volcanic event reshaped an oceanic plate, seismic wave analysis reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earths-largest-volcanic-event-reshaped-an-oce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earths-largest-volcanic-event-reshaped-an-oce/</guid><description>A research group has revealed through seismic wave analysis that the oceanic plate beneath the Ontong Java Plateau—the world&amp;rsquo;s largest oceanic plateau—was extensively altered by massive volcanic activity during its formation. The study is published in Geophys…</description></item><item><title>Lab-grown algae remove microplastics from water - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lab-grown-algae-remove-microplastics-from-wat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:30:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lab-grown-algae-remove-microplastics-from-wat/</guid><description>A University of Missouri researcher is pioneering an innovative solution to remove tiny bits of plastic pollution from our water. Mizzou&amp;rsquo;s Susie Dai recently applied a revolutionary strain of algae toward capturing and removing harmful microplastics from poll…</description></item><item><title>This Tiny Prehistoric Predator Could Hear You Whisper, Long Before Dinosaurs Walked the Earth - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-tiny-prehistoric-predator-could-hear-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-tiny-prehistoric-predator-could-hear-you/</guid><description>Millions of years before the first dinosaurs, a small predator called Thrinaxodon had a hidden edge: it could hear faint sounds like a whisper.</description></item><item><title>Hubble sees galaxy with dark rings in new light - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-sees-galaxy-with-dark-rings-in-new-lig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:36:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-sees-galaxy-with-dark-rings-in-new-lig/</guid><description>This NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope image features an uncommon galaxy with a striking appearance. NGC 7722 is a lenticular galaxy located about 187 million light-years away in the constellation Pegasus.</description></item><item><title>2-month-olds see the world in a more complex way than scientists thought, study suggests - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2-month-olds-see-the-world-in-a-more-complex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2-month-olds-see-the-world-in-a-more-complex/</guid><description>A new study suggests that babies are able to distinguish between the different objects they see around them at 2 months old, which earlier than scientists previously thought. The findings may help doctors and researchers better understand cognitive developmen…</description></item><item><title>What Kind of Photos Will the Artemis II Astronauts Take? And Who Will Take Them? - PetaPixel</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-kind-of-photos-will-the-artemis-ii-astro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:29:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-kind-of-photos-will-the-artemis-ii-astro/</guid><description>Blastoff could be less than one week away.</description></item><item><title>91-qubit processor accurately simulates many-body quantum chaos - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/91-qubit-processor-accurately-simulates-many/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:16:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/91-qubit-processor-accurately-simulates-many/</guid><description>Quantum chaos describes chaotic classical dynamical systems in terms of quantum theory, but simulations of these systems are limited by computational resources. However, one team seems to have found a way by leveraging error mitigation and specialized circuit…</description></item><item><title>The Baby Universe Really Was a Goopy Soup, Research Suggests - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-baby-universe-really-was-a-goopy-soup-res/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:15:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-baby-universe-really-was-a-goopy-soup-res/</guid><description>The early universe is full of mysteries, but we can now at least be sure it was soupy.</description></item><item><title>NASA's IMAP Active Link for Real-Time Data now Available - Space Weather Prediction Center (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-imap-active-link-for-real-time-data-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-imap-active-link-for-real-time-data-now/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>How Modern and Antique Technologies Reveal a Dynamic Cosmos - Quanta Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-modern-and-antique-technologies-reveal-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:48:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-modern-and-antique-technologies-reveal-a/</guid><description>Today’s observatories document every pulse and flash in the sky each night. To understand how the cosmos has changed over longer periods, scientists rely on a more tactile technology.</description></item><item><title>House NASA bill seeks details on lunar lander and spacesuit development - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/house-nasa-bill-seeks-details-on-lunar-lander/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:43:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/house-nasa-bill-seeks-details-on-lunar-lander/</guid><description>A NASA authorization bill the House Science Committee is scheduled to take up this week would require closer scrutiny of lunar lander and spacesuit work.</description></item><item><title>There’s Something Hiding Under Jupiter’s Clouds, Scientists Find - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/theres-something-hiding-under-jupiters-clouds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/theres-something-hiding-under-jupiters-clouds/</guid><description>Scientists have created a highly detailed computational model of Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere to peer below its thick clouds.</description></item><item><title>See the moon eclipse one of the brightest stars in the sky during rare alignment tonight - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/see-the-moon-eclipse-one-of-the-brightest-sta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/see-the-moon-eclipse-one-of-the-brightest-sta/</guid><description>One of the brightest stars in the night sky will vanish as seen from North America and Europe in a rare event.</description></item><item><title>Focusing and defocusing light without a lens: First demonstration of the structured Montgomery effect in free space - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/focusing-and-defocusing-light-without-a-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:39:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/focusing-and-defocusing-light-without-a-lens/</guid><description>Applied physicists in the Harvard John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences (SEAS) have demonstrated a new way to structure light in custom, repeatable, three-dimensional patterns, all without the use of traditional optical elements like lens…</description></item><item><title>Infrared running of gravity offers a field-theoretic route to dark matter phenomena - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/infrared-running-of-gravity-offers-a-field-th/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:40:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/infrared-running-of-gravity-offers-a-field-th/</guid><description>The mystery of dark matter—unseen, pervasive, and essential in standard cosmology—has loomed over physics for decades. In new research, I explore a different possibility: Rather than postulating new particles, I propose that perhaps gravity itself behaves dif…</description></item><item><title>A student made cosmic dust in her lab—what she found could help us understand how life started on Earth - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-student-made-cosmic-dust-in-her-labwhat-sh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-student-made-cosmic-dust-in-her-labwhat-sh/</guid><description>A Sydney Ph.D. student has recreated a tiny piece of the universe inside a bottle in her laboratory, producing cosmic dust from scratch. The results shed new light on how the chemical building blocks of life may have formed long before Earth existed. Linda Lo…</description></item><item><title>600-Million-Year-Old Mystery Solved: Scientists Identify the First Branch on the Tree of Life - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/600-million-year-old-mystery-solved-scientist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/600-million-year-old-mystery-solved-scientist/</guid><description>Scientists settle a major evolutionary mystery as new research reveals the comb jelly, not the sea sponge, was the first animal to branch off on Earth</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Unveiled a New Map of Antarctica, and What's Under is Bigger Than Anyone Expected - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-unveiled-a-new-map-of-antarct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-unveiled-a-new-map-of-antarct/</guid><description>This new map of Antarctica reveals something no one was supposed to see, and scientists can’t believe it’s real.</description></item><item><title>Geologists may have solved mystery of Green River's 'uphill' route - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/geologists-may-have-solved-mystery-of-green-r/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/geologists-may-have-solved-mystery-of-green-r/</guid><description>New research may have solved an American mystery which has baffled geologists for a century and a half: How did a river carve a path through a mountain in one of the country&amp;rsquo;s most iconic landscapes? Scientists have long sought an answer to this question of h…</description></item><item><title>This Sea Creature Found the Secret to Immortality, and Now Scientists Want It - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-sea-creature-found-the-secret-to-immorta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-sea-creature-found-the-secret-to-immorta/</guid><description>A tiny sea creature may have cracked the code to eternal youth, and scientists just found the cells that could make it possible for humans, too.</description></item><item><title>UPDATE! An X8.1 (Strong) flare from Region 4366 - NOAA (National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration) (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/update-an-x81-strong-flare-from-region-4366/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/update-an-x81-strong-flare-from-region-4366/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover the Milky Way Is Floating on a Vast Sheet of Dark Matter Stretching Millions of Light-Years - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-the-milky-way-is-floating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-the-milky-way-is-floating/</guid><description>A massive cosmic structure hiding in plain sight may finally explain why galaxies near the Milky Way behave so strangely.</description></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope watches distant galaxies form farthest cluster ever seen in the ancient universe (image) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-watches-distant-ga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-watches-distant-ga/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;JADES-ID1 is giving us new evidence that the universe was in a huge hurry to grow up.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>In Photos: Full ‘Snow Moon’ Rises To Set Up A ‘Blood Moon’ Eclipse - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-photos-full-snow-moon-rises-to-set-up-a-bl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:31:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-photos-full-snow-moon-rises-to-set-up-a-bl/</guid><description>The second full moon of 2026 — the snow moon — rose after sunset on Sunday, Feb. 1, lighting up the night sky across the world. Here are the best photos.</description></item><item><title>Tiny new dinosaur Foskeia pelendonum fills in an evolutionary gap - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tiny-new-dinosaur-foskeia-pelendonum-fills-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tiny-new-dinosaur-foskeia-pelendonum-fills-in/</guid><description>An international team has described Foskeia pelendonum, a tiny Early Cretaceous ornithopod from Vegagete (Burgos, Spain), measuring barely half a meter long. Led by Paul-Emile Dieudonné (National University of Río Negro, Argentina), the study reveals an unexp…</description></item><item><title>What to know about Artemis II's 'wet dress rehearsal' - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-to-know-about-artemis-iis-wet-dress-rehe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:49:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-to-know-about-artemis-iis-wet-dress-rehe/</guid><description>As astronauts prepare to fly around the moon, critical testing must occur before there is &amp;ldquo;Go&amp;rdquo; for launch.</description></item><item><title>Museum of Idaho launches new exhibit exploring 'Life Before Dinosaurs' - KSL News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/museum-of-idaho-launches-new-exhibit-explorin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:48:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/museum-of-idaho-launches-new-exhibit-explorin/</guid><description>From looking into the future with artificial intelligence to learning about mummies of the past, the Museum of Idaho ventures further back in time, before dinosaurs existed.</description></item><item><title>Satellite study reveals 24.2 billion ton annual groundwater loss in High Mountain Asia - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellite-study-reveals-242-billion-ton-annua/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 22:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellite-study-reveals-242-billion-ton-annua/</guid><description>A recent satellite-based study has uncovered alarming declines in groundwater storage across High Mountain Asia (HMA), widely known as the &amp;ldquo;Asian Water Tower.&amp;rdquo; This critical water source, which sustains agricultural irrigation, urban water supplies and ecolog…</description></item><item><title>Live coverage: SpaceX to launch 25 Starlink satellites on Falcon 9 rocket from Vandenberg SFB - Spaceflight Now</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/live-coverage-spacex-to-launch-25-starlink-sa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 21:29:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/live-coverage-spacex-to-launch-25-starlink-sa/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>It's the size of 3 Central Parks in New York, could be 8,650 years old – and glows in the dark. Forget the blue whale this beast is the world's biggest organism - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/its-the-size-of-3-central-parks-in-new-york-c/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:22:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/its-the-size-of-3-central-parks-in-new-york-c/</guid><description>This humongous fungus is the biggest organism in the world</description></item><item><title>Mapped: The World’s 12 Largest Impact Craters - Visual Capitalist</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mapped-the-worlds-12-largest-impact-craters-v/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:15:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mapped-the-worlds-12-largest-impact-craters-v/</guid><description>See Earth&amp;rsquo;s largest impact craters, including the ones tied to extinction events and rare geological formations.</description></item><item><title>Hard-to-synthesize materials revived using AI: An LLM-based materials redesign technology - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hard-to-synthesize-materials-revived-using-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hard-to-synthesize-materials-revived-using-ai/</guid><description>A research team led by Prof. Yousung Jung of the Department of Chemical and Biological Engineering at Seoul National University (SNU) has developed an innovative AI-based technology that uses large language models (LLMs) to redesign new materials that were pr…</description></item><item><title>250-Million-Year-Old Fossil Reveals Origins of Our Unique Hearing - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/250-million-year-old-fossil-reveals-origins-o/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/250-million-year-old-fossil-reveals-origins-o/</guid><description>Modern mammals have unique hearing abilities, able to sense a broad range of volumes and frequencies using middle-ear features, including our eardrums and a few small bones.</description></item><item><title>New Data Points to Massive Underground Structures Beneath Venus - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-data-points-to-massive-underground-struct/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:57:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-data-points-to-massive-underground-struct/</guid><description>Beneath Venus’s scorched surface, scientists may have found something massive—and it could rewrite planetary history.</description></item><item><title>Bright Light Streaks Across New Zealand Skyline: What Could It Be? - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bright-light-streaks-across-new-zealand-skyli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bright-light-streaks-across-new-zealand-skyli/</guid><description>A mysterious streak of light appeared over Wellington, New Zealand, on January 30, 2026.</description></item><item><title>Two rare 5th millennium BC fetal burials in Iran reveal variable prehistoric practices - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-rare-5th-millennium-bc-fetal-burials-in-i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:10:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-rare-5th-millennium-bc-fetal-burials-in-i/</guid><description>In a study conducted by Dr. Mahdi Alirezazadeh and Dr. Hanan Bahranipoor, published in Archaeological Research in Asia, two exceptionally well-preserved fetal burials from Chaparabad, Iran, dating to the mid-5th millennium BC, were analyzed including burial L…</description></item><item><title>Plastic pollution promotes hazardous water conditions, new study finds - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/plastic-pollution-promotes-hazardous-water-co/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/plastic-pollution-promotes-hazardous-water-co/</guid><description>Dangerous concentrations of algae such as &amp;ldquo;red tides&amp;rdquo; have been consistently emerging in locations around the world. A region in Southern Australia is experiencing a nine-month toxic algae bloom that spans thousands of miles and has caused thousands of deaths…</description></item><item><title>Imaging the Wigner crystal state in a new type of quantum material - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-the-wigner-crystal-state-in-a-new-typ/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-the-wigner-crystal-state-in-a-new-typ/</guid><description>In some solid materials under specific conditions, mutual Coulomb interactions shape electrons into many-body correlated states, such as Wigner crystals, which are essentially solids made of electrons. So far, the Wigner crystal state remains sensitive to var…</description></item><item><title>Galactic Monsters Grew in Cocoons Like Giant Bugs, Scientists Say - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/galactic-monsters-grew-in-cocoons-like-giant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/galactic-monsters-grew-in-cocoons-like-giant/</guid><description>Astronomers say that ancient almost impossibly massive &amp;ldquo;Little Red Dots&amp;rdquo; may be black holes trapped in &amp;ldquo;cocoons.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>What Is the Farmer’s Walk and Why Everyone’s Using It to Build Strength and Improve Balance - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-the-farmers-walk-and-why-everyones-us/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-the-farmers-walk-and-why-everyones-us/</guid><description>An old-school strength move used by farmers is quietly revolutionizing modern fitness and rehab. Trainers, doctors, and elite athletes are all turning to this brutally simple exercise for results machines can’t match.</description></item><item><title>This Photo of Mars at Night Is Straight Up Haunting - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-photo-of-mars-at-night-is-straight-up-ha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-photo-of-mars-at-night-is-straight-up-ha/</guid><description>An image taken by NASA&amp;rsquo;s Curiosity rover shows its LED lights lighting up a hole it drilled into the surface of the rock.</description></item><item><title>Multi-agent AI and robots automate materials discovery in closed-loop lab system - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/multi-agent-ai-and-robots-automate-materials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/multi-agent-ai-and-robots-automate-materials/</guid><description>Traditional processes used to discover new materials are complex, time-consuming, and costly, often requiring years of sustained effort. Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated powerful capabilities in information processing, offerin…</description></item><item><title>The Pelican Nebula shines near the Las Vegas Strip in gorgeous deep space photo - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-pelican-nebula-shines-near-the-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-pelican-nebula-shines-near-the-las-vegas/</guid><description>The Pelican Nebula is located in the constellation Cygnus, the swan.</description></item><item><title>“Existential risk” – Why scientists are racing to define consciousness - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/existential-risk-why-scientists-are-racin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:51:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/existential-risk-why-scientists-are-racin/</guid><description>Scientists warn that rapid advances in AI and neurotechnology are outpacing our understanding of consciousness, creating serious ethical risks. New research argues that developing scientific tests for awareness could transform medicine, animal welfare, law, a…</description></item><item><title>We asked retired astronauts about their favorite space movies, and this is what they shared with us - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-asked-retired-astronauts-about-their-favor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-asked-retired-astronauts-about-their-favor/</guid><description>Ahead of the launch of Artemis II, the first crewed mission to the moon in more than 50 years, astronauts share the movies that capture the danger, teamwork, and wonder of spaceflight. Their picks offer cinematic glimpses into the real challenges and triumphs…</description></item><item><title>The Father of Astronomy Left Us a Star Map, We Just Found It Under 6 Layers of Ink - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-father-of-astronomy-left-us-a-star-map-we/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-father-of-astronomy-left-us-a-star-map-we/</guid><description>A lost star catalog from the dawn of astronomy was just found, and it’s far more accurate than anyone expected.</description></item><item><title>Eyes to the Skies for February: Rocket launch, winter constellations, eclipse and more - WTOP</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eyes-to-the-skies-for-february-rocket-launch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eyes-to-the-skies-for-february-rocket-launch/</guid><description>NASA has scheduled the launch for the Artemis II moon rocket for no earlier than Feb. 8. WTOP will have details on the mission as they become available.</description></item><item><title>A 512-Million-Year-Old Fossil Site in China Reveals Strange Sea Creatures From an Ancient Underwater World - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-512-million-year-old-fossil-site-in-china-r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-512-million-year-old-fossil-site-in-china-r/</guid><description>A 512-million-year-old ecosystem, frozen in stone, reveals an explosive comeback after a mass extinction no one fully understood, until now.</description></item><item><title>Buried for 3.4 Million Years, New Fossil Evidence Is Removing Lucy From the Story of Human Evolution - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/buried-for-34-million-years-new-fossil-eviden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/buried-for-34-million-years-new-fossil-eviden/</guid><description>A 3.4-million-year-old fossil foot uncovered in Ethiopia is shaking the foundations of human origins. Hidden for over a decade, this ancient find reveals a shocking twist in how early ancestors moved.</description></item><item><title>Hubble shares eerie portrait of constantly changing stars — Space photo of the week - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-shares-eerie-portrait-of-constantly-ch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-shares-eerie-portrait-of-constantly-ch/</guid><description>A new image from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope shows the Lupus 3 cloud in Scorpius bursting with young stars that are forming within collapsing clouds of gas and dust.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover hidden geometry that bends electrons like gravity - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-hidden-geometry-that-bend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:05:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-hidden-geometry-that-bend/</guid><description>Researchers have discovered a hidden quantum geometry inside materials that subtly steers electrons, echoing how gravity warps light in space. Once thought to exist only on paper, this effect has now been observed experimentally in a popular quantum material.…</description></item><item><title>Tonight's Snow Moon is a last chance to see a high Moon of winter. Here are 6 reasons to catch it - BBC Sky at Night Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tonights-snow-moon-is-a-last-chance-to-see-a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:19:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tonights-snow-moon-is-a-last-chance-to-see-a/</guid><description>Reasons why you should see the Snow Moon rise on Sunday 1 February 2026, the last high full Moon of this winter.</description></item><item><title>David Sean Cunningham - LancasterOnline</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/david-sean-cunningham-lancasteronline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:34:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/david-sean-cunningham-lancasteronline/</guid><description>David Sean Cunningham passed away on January 21, 2026, in Cleveland, OH. Dave was born on October 29, 1967, to Margerie and James Cunningham in Lancaster, PA. He was a</description></item><item><title>Researchers reveal hidden landscape beneath miles of ice: 'Now you've got a properly zoomed-in digital image' - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/researchers-reveal-hidden-landscape-beneath-m/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/researchers-reveal-hidden-landscape-beneath-m/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;[This study gives] us a better picture of what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen in the future.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Expired Cans of Salmon From Decades Ago Preserved a Huge Surprise - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/expired-cans-of-salmon-from-decades-ago-prese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 22:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/expired-cans-of-salmon-from-decades-ago-prese/</guid><description>Scientists have made some intriguing parasite discoveries in an accidental back-of-the-pantry natural history museum. Canned salmon, well past its prime, has preserved decades of Alaskan marine ecology in brine and tin.</description></item><item><title>Giant Virus Discovered in Japanese Pond May Hint at Multicellular Life's Origins - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/giant-virus-discovered-in-japanese-pond-may-h/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 21:03:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/giant-virus-discovered-in-japanese-pond-may-h/</guid><description>Scientists in Japan have discovered a previously unknown giant virus, offering new insight into this enigmatic category of viruses – and possibly also into the origins of multicellular life.</description></item><item><title>Thomas Edison May Have Discovered Graphene - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/thomas-edison-may-have-discovered-graphene-ha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/thomas-edison-may-have-discovered-graphene-ha/</guid><description>Thomas Edison is well known for his inventions (even if you don’t agree he invented all of them). However, he also occasionally invented things he didn’t understand, so they had to be r…</description></item><item><title>A Young Bear Thought It Found Easy Prey Until This 800-Pound Protector Intervened - Yahoo Lifestyle Singapore</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-young-bear-thought-it-found-easy-prey-until/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-young-bear-thought-it-found-easy-prey-until/</guid><description>The only way that bear cubs can learn to hunt effectively is by practicing their skills. Finding some baby prey that you can overpower is a great opportunity&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Artemis II highlights a shift in U.S. space strategy since Apollo and contrasts with China's closed program - PBS</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-highlights-a-shift-in-us-space-str/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:30:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-highlights-a-shift-in-us-space-str/</guid><description>China’s program is centrally directed and tightly controlled by the state, while the U.S. approach is intentionally open and designed so partners can operate within a shared framework.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the high-performance potential of CF₃SF₄ - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unlocking-the-high-performance-potential-of-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unlocking-the-high-performance-potential-of-c/</guid><description>Fluorine has changed the world of medicine. You might not see it, but newly approved drugs contain at least one fluorine atom. This tiny but powerful element is the &amp;ldquo;hidden engine&amp;rdquo; that makes our medications more stable and effective. Over the past decades, c…</description></item><item><title>Sprint or marathon? Aging muscle stem cells shift from rapid repair to long-term survival - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sprint-or-marathon-aging-muscle-stem-cells-sh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sprint-or-marathon-aging-muscle-stem-cells-sh/</guid><description>Aging muscles heal more slowly after injury—a frustrating reality familiar to many older adults. A UCLA study conducted in mice reveals an unexpected cause: Stem cells in aged muscle accumulate higher levels of a protein that slows their ability to activate a…</description></item><item><title>Particle Accelerator Decodes Lost Ancient Greek Star Catalog - Ground News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/particle-accelerator-decodes-lost-ancient-gre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/particle-accelerator-decodes-lost-ancient-gre/</guid><description>Researchers led by Victor Gysembergh of CNRS used a synchrotron at SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory to decode erased ancient Greek text from the Codex Climaci Rescriptus, revealing star coordinates from astronomer Hipparchus dating back to around 150 B.C.</description></item><item><title>Fossil hunters uncover 132-million-year-old dinosaur footprints on South Africa's coast - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/fossil-hunters-uncover-132-million-year-old-d/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/fossil-hunters-uncover-132-million-year-old-d/</guid><description>Southern Africa is world renowned for its fossil record of creatures that lived in the very distant past, including dinosaurs. But, about 182 million years ago, a huge eruption of lava covered much of the landscape (the inland Karoo Basin) where most of the d…</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis 2 Suits Are Ready for Historic Mission! - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-2-suits-are-ready-for-historic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-2-suits-are-ready-for-historic/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s Artemis 2 mission is ready to make history, with innovative spacesuits playing a critical role in the crew’s safety and success.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers spot 'time-warped' supernovas whose light both has and hasn't reached Earth - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-spot-time-warped-supernovas-whose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-spot-time-warped-supernovas-whose/</guid><description>Will two rare supernovas finally tell us how fast the universe is expanding? Perhaps, but we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait for it for them to &amp;lsquo;reappear&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>With speeds of 100 miles per hour, it leaves birds like swifts and albatrosses eating its dust. - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/with-speeds-of-100-miles-per-hour-it-leaves-b/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/with-speeds-of-100-miles-per-hour-it-leaves-b/</guid><description>did you know the fastest flying animal in the world isn&amp;rsquo;t a bird</description></item><item><title>Jupiter’s clouds are hiding something big - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-clouds-are-hiding-something-big-scie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 15:31:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-clouds-are-hiding-something-big-scie/</guid><description>Jupiter’s swirling storms have concealed its true makeup for centuries, but a new model is finally peeling back the clouds. Researchers found the planet likely holds significantly more oxygen than the Sun, a key clue to how Jupiter—and the rest of the solar s…</description></item><item><title>Secret Ingredients - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/secret-ingredients-hackaday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/secret-ingredients-hackaday/</guid><description>We were talking on the podcast about rope. But not just any rope – especially non-stretchy rope for using in a mechanical context. The hack in question was a bicycle wheel that swapped out normal m…</description></item><item><title>See February’s full snow moon light up the sky - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/see-februarys-full-snow-moon-light-up-the-sky/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/see-februarys-full-snow-moon-light-up-the-sky/</guid><description>Ahead of the anticipated launch of the Artemis II mission, catch a glimpse of February’s full moon, called the snow moon.</description></item><item><title>Saturday Citations: Understanding procrastination; delicious baby sauropods; a study on musical 'pleasure chills' - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/saturday-citations-understanding-procrastinat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/saturday-citations-understanding-procrastinat/</guid><description>This week, researchers identified the role of the brain&amp;rsquo;s protein clean-up system in dementia. Fecal transplants show promising benefits in treating multiple cancer types. And biologists found that saltwater crocodiles traveled thousands of miles across the I…</description></item><item><title>NASA taps Claude to conjure Mars rover's travel plan - theregister.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-taps-claude-to-conjure-mars-rovers-trave/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-taps-claude-to-conjure-mars-rovers-trave/</guid><description>: Is there life on Mars? Well, there&amp;rsquo;s Claude in the machine</description></item><item><title>It Took 400,000 MPH to Get There, Here’s What NASA’s Probe Found Near the Sun - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/it-took-400000-mph-to-get-there-heres-what-na/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/it-took-400000-mph-to-get-there-heres-what-na/</guid><description>Scientists sent a probe into the Sun’s atmosphere, and it came back with answers no one expected.</description></item><item><title>This Giant Star Fooled the Entire Astronomy World, Here’s What’s Really Going On - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-giant-star-fooled-the-entire-astronomy-w/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-giant-star-fooled-the-entire-astronomy-w/</guid><description>Astronomers believed WOH G64 was about to go supernova, but new data revealed a hidden companion star behind its bizarre behavior.</description></item><item><title>Our Entire Galaxy Appears to Be Embedded in a Colossal Sheet of Dark Matter - Yahoo News New Zealand</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/our-entire-galaxy-appears-to-be-embedded-in-a/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/our-entire-galaxy-appears-to-be-embedded-in-a/</guid><description>We live in a dark, dark, world.</description></item><item><title>AI Discovers Hundreds of Anomalies in Archive of Hubble Images - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-discovers-hundreds-of-anomalies-in-archive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-discovers-hundreds-of-anomalies-in-archive/</guid><description>Astronomers used an a custom-built AI tool to scour millions of Hubble images, uncovering the universe&amp;rsquo;s overlooked curiosities.</description></item><item><title>Weekend reads: Did a researcher ‘Obscure a Baby’s Poisoning?’; ‘Critical social media posts linked to retractions’; arXiv ‘clamps down on AI slop’ - Retraction Watch</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weekend-reads-did-a-researcher-obscure-a-baby/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weekend-reads-did-a-researcher-obscure-a-baby/</guid><description>If your week flew by — we know ours did — catch up here with what you might have missed. The week at Retraction Watch featured: Study is stolen, sold, published. Now the victim is accused of plagia…</description></item><item><title>What actually happens to a spacecraft during its fiery last moments? Here's why ESA wants to find out - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-actually-happens-to-a-spacecraft-during/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-actually-happens-to-a-spacecraft-during/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Understanding how different materials behave as they burn up could help engineers design satellites that fully disintegrate, leaving nothing behind in orbit or in the atmosphere.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>New optical method bypasses light's limit by 100,000× to image atoms - Interesting Engineering</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-optical-method-bypasses-lights-limit-by-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-optical-method-bypasses-lights-limit-by-1/</guid><description>Scientists have shattered the diffraction limit, using continuous-wave lasers to resolve images at 0.1 nanometers.</description></item><item><title>NASA Selects Axiom Space for Fifth Private Mission to Space Station - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-selects-axiom-space-for-fifth-private-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 23:37:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-selects-axiom-space-for-fifth-private-mi/</guid><description>NASA and Axiom Space have signed an order for the fifth private astronaut mission to the International Space Station, targeted to launch no earlier than</description></item><item><title>NASA's Artemis 2 mission to the moon puts Crew-12 SpaceX launch in delicate dance - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-2-mission-to-the-moon-puts-crew/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 23:25:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-2-mission-to-the-moon-puts-crew/</guid><description>Artemis seems to be NASA&amp;rsquo;s primary focus.</description></item><item><title>Baby long-necked dinosaurs were a 'perfect snack' for predators - KSL.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/baby-long-necked-dinosaurs-were-a-perfect-sna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/baby-long-necked-dinosaurs-were-a-perfect-sna/</guid><description>New research shows Brachiosaurus and other sauropod babies appear to have been regular dinner fare for meat-eating dinosaurs 150 million years ago.</description></item><item><title>Japan Botched a Satellite Launch in One of the Weirdest Ways Possible - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-botched-a-satellite-launch-in-one-of-th/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:15:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-botched-a-satellite-launch-in-one-of-th/</guid><description>Japan&amp;rsquo;s H3 rocket lost its payload fairing around 4 minutes after launch, leaving a satellite exposed and hanging on for dear life.</description></item><item><title>One Catastrophic Event Could Cause All Of Earth's Satellites To Crash In Just Days - AOL.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/one-catastrophic-event-could-cause-all-of-ear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/one-catastrophic-event-could-cause-all-of-ear/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no understatement to say that the modern world could not function without our satellites, but they&amp;rsquo;re a lot more vulnerable than you may think.</description></item><item><title>Russian 'inspector' satellite appears to break apart in orbit, raising debris concerns - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-inspector-satellite-appears-to-break/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-inspector-satellite-appears-to-break/</guid><description>Ground-based observations suggest the former geostationary inspector satellite suffered a fragmentation event months after retirement, raising new concerns about debris in high Earth orbit.</description></item><item><title>Large Hadron Collider reveals 'primordial soup' of the early universe was surprisingly soupy - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/large-hadron-collider-reveals-primordial-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/large-hadron-collider-reveals-primordial-soup/</guid><description>Waiter, there&amp;rsquo;s a quark in my soup!</description></item><item><title>Record-breaking photons at telecom wavelengths—on demand - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/record-breaking-photons-at-telecom-wavelength/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/record-breaking-photons-at-telecom-wavelength/</guid><description>A team of researchers from the University of Stuttgart and the Julius-Maximilians-Universität Würzburg led by Prof. Stefanie Barz (University of Stuttgart) has demonstrated a source of single photons that combines on-demand operation with record-high photon q…</description></item><item><title>Lab study suggests longer waves fracture floating ice sheets at lower stress - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lab-study-suggests-longer-waves-fracture-floa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lab-study-suggests-longer-waves-fracture-floa/</guid><description>When waves are moving across ice-covered seas, they can cause sheets of ice to bend and ultimately break. Understanding the processes underlying these wave-induced ice fractures and predicting when they will occur could help to better forecast how climate cha…</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Curiosity Rover Lights Up Mars for Very Rare Night Photo - PetaPixel</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-curiosity-rover-lights-up-mars-for-very/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:29:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-curiosity-rover-lights-up-mars-for-very/</guid><description>How and why NASA&amp;rsquo;s Curiosity rover captured a rare nighttime photo of Mars.</description></item><item><title>Quantum mechanical effects help overcome a fundamental limitation of optical microscopy - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-mechanical-effects-help-overcome-a-fu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:21:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-mechanical-effects-help-overcome-a-fu/</guid><description>Researchers from Regensburg and Birmingham have overcome a fundamental limitation of optical microscopy. With the help of quantum mechanical effects, they succeeded for the first time in performing optical measurements with atomic resolution. Their work is pu…</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover molecule in space that hints at origin of life - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-molecule-in-space-that-hi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-molecule-in-space-that-hi/</guid><description>A 13-atom molecule containing sulfur has been discovered in interstellar space for the first time, providing insight into the origins of the chemistry of life.</description></item><item><title>Why are Tatooine planets rare? General relativity explains why binary star systems rarely host planets - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-are-tatooine-planets-rare-general-relativ/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:27:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-are-tatooine-planets-rare-general-relativ/</guid><description>Astronomers have found thousands of exoplanets around single stars, but few around binary stars—even though both types of stars are equally common. Physicists can now explain the dearth.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Realized This Dinosaur is Breaking Records, and Could Rival a Sauropod in Size - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-realized-this-dinosaur-is-bre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-realized-this-dinosaur-is-bre/</guid><description>Long ignored, this fossil find may belong to the biggest dinosaur ever discovered. Experts are stunned by what they missed for over 70 years.</description></item><item><title>Spider spinneret evolution: How a genome duplication event 438 million years ago set the stage - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spider-spinneret-evolution-how-a-genome-dupli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:40:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spider-spinneret-evolution-how-a-genome-dupli/</guid><description>Scientists have uncovered a 400-million-year-old genetic secret that gave spiders the ability to produce silk and weave their webs. Spiders didn&amp;rsquo;t begin their journey on Earth in the same way as they are known today. Arthropods such as our eight-legged weaver…</description></item><item><title>Citizen Scientist Spots Earth-like Planet: Now Astrophysicists Will Focus Most Powerful Telescopes on it - Good News Network</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/citizen-scientist-spots-earth-like-planet-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/citizen-scientist-spots-earth-like-planet-now/</guid><description>Alexander Venner picked his way by hand through the data collected by a now-retired NASA telescope called Kepler, which examined the sky for exoplanets</description></item><item><title>More than 43,000 years ago, Neanderthals spent centuries collecting animal skulls in a cave; but archaeologists aren't sure why - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/more-than-43000-years-ago-neanderthals-spent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/more-than-43000-years-ago-neanderthals-spent/</guid><description>Neanderthals repeatedly returned to the cave to store horned animal skulls, revealing this cultural tradition was transmitted over time.</description></item><item><title>NASA delays critical Artemis 2 rocket fueling test due to below-freezing temperatures, launch no earlier than Feb. 8 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-delays-critical-artemis-2-rocket-fueling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:52:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-delays-critical-artemis-2-rocket-fueling/</guid><description>Arctic cold is chilling the Artemis 2 timeline.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Unearthed a 150-Million-Year-Old Dinosaur Egg Nest on a Portuguese Beach - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-unearthed-a-150-million-year-old-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-unearthed-a-150-million-year-old-d/</guid><description>A rare fossil discovery on Portugal’s coast reveals a dinosaur nest from the Late Jurassic period, perfectly preserved in stone.</description></item><item><title>The Massive Nucleus of 3I/ATLAS and its Puzzling Methane Outgassing, Based on New Data from the… - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-massive-nucleus-of-3i-atlas-and-its-puzzl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-massive-nucleus-of-3i-atlas-and-its-puzzl/</guid><description>What a glorious day! Today, new data on the interstellar object 3I/ATLAS was released from the Hubble and Webb space telescopes in two…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Found a Spider That Builds 80-Foot Webs, And Its Silk Is Tougher Than Steel - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-a-spider-that-builds-80-foot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-a-spider-that-builds-80-foot/</guid><description>Deep in Madagascar, a spider spins webs across rivers, using silk so strong, it rivals bulletproof materials.</description></item><item><title>Measuring up to the length of a bus, these creatures have the longest tentacles in the world - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/measuring-up-to-the-length-of-a-bus-these-cre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/measuring-up-to-the-length-of-a-bus-these-cre/</guid><description>Discover the creatures that have the longest tentacles in the world – with some reaching up to 30 metres</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Watched These Entities Rapidly Evolve In Space. They Could Save Our Lives. - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-watched-these-entities-rapidl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-watched-these-entities-rapidl/</guid><description>Scientists analyzed how a biological battle played out between E. coli and a T7 bacteriophage, both on Earth and aboard the International Space Station.</description></item><item><title>Black Hole Formation from a Disappearing Star in the Andromeda Galaxy - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/black-hole-formation-from-a-disappearing-star/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:14:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/black-hole-formation-from-a-disappearing-star/</guid><description>A new paper led by Kishalay De (accessible here), on which I was privileged to be a co-author, reports the discovery of a disappearing star…</description></item><item><title>Comet C/2025 K1 (ATLAS) crumbles apart in stunning new telescope images - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-c-2025-k1-atlas-crumbles-apart-in-stu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-c-2025-k1-atlas-crumbles-apart-in-stu/</guid><description>The comet broke into pieces after making a close approach around the sun in October 2025.</description></item><item><title>Watch awkward Chinese humanoid robot lay it all down on the dance floor - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-awkward-chinese-humanoid-robot-lay-it-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-awkward-chinese-humanoid-robot-lay-it-a/</guid><description>The model demonstrated remarkable precision, stability and speed across a highly complex dance routine.</description></item><item><title>“Unlike Anything We Have Seen Before” – An Unexplained Space Object Is Sending Powerful Signals Across the Galaxy - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unlike-anything-we-have-seen-before-an-un/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:16:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unlike-anything-we-have-seen-before-an-un/</guid><description>Astronomers at the International Centre for Radio Astronomy Research (ICRAR), working with international collaborators, have made a striking discovery involving a previously unknown type of cosmic phenomenon. A strange astronomical object known as ASKAP J1832…</description></item><item><title>The Special Regions on Mars Where It Is Totally Forbidden to Explore, for a Haunting Reason - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-special-regions-on-mars-where-it-is-total/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-special-regions-on-mars-where-it-is-total/</guid><description>A secret map of Mars exists, one that space agencies are forbidden to follow. Hidden within its surface are regions so scientifically sensitive that even NASA rovers are ordered to keep out.</description></item><item><title>How DeepMind's genome AI could help solve rare disease mysteries - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-deepminds-genome-ai-could-help-solve-rare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:29:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-deepminds-genome-ai-could-help-solve-rare/</guid><description>Hackathons using AlphaGenome and other AI models are hunting down the genetic causes of devastating conditions that have evaded diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>Colossal Biosciences Announces Historic Breakthrough: The Woolly Mammoth Is Back, Meet Baby Manny - Technology Org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/colossal-biosciences-announces-historic-break/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:41:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/colossal-biosciences-announces-historic-break/</guid><description>DALLAS, TX — January 27, 2026 — Colossal Biosciences, the world’s leading de-extinction company, proudly announces the successful</description></item><item><title>If asteroid YR4 hits our Moon, it'll cause a bright flash and meteors as debris hits Earth, say scientists - BBC Sky at Night Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/if-asteroid-yr4-hits-our-moon-itll-cause-a-br/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:29:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/if-asteroid-yr4-hits-our-moon-itll-cause-a-br/</guid><description>Scientists have worked out the effects of asteroid 2024 YR4 hitting our Moon in 2032, including what we&amp;rsquo;ll see in the days after the event.</description></item><item><title>Rescuer Goes To Save Dogs Abandoned In Orchard And Ends Up With 10 Newborn Puppies - The Dodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/rescuer-goes-to-save-dogs-abandoned-in-orchar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 23:11:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/rescuer-goes-to-save-dogs-abandoned-in-orchar/</guid><description>She was able to rescue all of them.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers watch 1st black hole ever imaged launch a 3,000‑light‑year‑long cosmic jet from its glowing 'shadow' - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-watch-1st-black-hole-ever-imaged/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-watch-1st-black-hole-ever-imaged/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It is amazing to see that we are gradually moving towards combining these breakthrough observations across multiple frequencies and completing the picture of the jet launching region.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Halley wasn't the first to figure out the famous comet. An 11th-century monk did it first, new research suggests. - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/halley-wasnt-the-first-to-figure-out-the-famo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:30:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/halley-wasnt-the-first-to-figure-out-the-famo/</guid><description>An 11th-century monk saw the famous &amp;ldquo;Halley&amp;rsquo;s comet&amp;rdquo; first as a child and later as an adult, new research finds.</description></item><item><title>Whoa, Why Has This Frozen Lake Turned Green? - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/whoa-why-has-this-frozen-lake-turned-green-gi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/whoa-why-has-this-frozen-lake-turned-green-gi/</guid><description>Scientists say it&amp;rsquo;s a rare natural phenomenon driven by pollution and—yep—climate change.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Moon Spacesuits Are Plagued With Issues - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-moon-spacesuits-are-plagued-with-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-moon-spacesuits-are-plagued-with-issues/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s Moon astronauts will be using a new spacesuit to explore the lunar surface. Unfortunately, experts say, it has problems.</description></item><item><title>Artemis 2 SLS wet dress rehearsal latest news: NASA preps for critical test ahead of astronaut launch to the moon - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-sls-wet-dress-rehearsal-latest-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-sls-wet-dress-rehearsal-latest-news/</guid><description>Thursday, Jan. 29, 2026: Follow NASA&amp;rsquo;s last major test of SLS before the launch of Artemis 2 and a crew of astronauts around the moon.</description></item><item><title>New map of the Milky Way's magnetism offers insights into cosmic evolution - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-map-of-the-milky-ways-magnetism-offers-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:20:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-map-of-the-milky-ways-magnetism-offers-in/</guid><description>A UBC Okanagan-led research project has given a group of international scientists their clearest view yet of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field, revealing that it is far more complex than previously believed.</description></item><item><title>Why termite kings and queens are monogamous: Scientists uncover surprising answer - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-termite-kings-and-queens-are-monogamous-s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-termite-kings-and-queens-are-monogamous-s/</guid><description>Termites are among the most successful animals on Earth, forming vast societies that can number in the millions. But how did such complex social systems evolve from solitary ancestors that looked much like today&amp;rsquo;s cockroaches?</description></item><item><title>NASA's Juno spacecraft spots the largest volcanic eruption ever seen on Jupiter's moon Io - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-juno-spacecraft-spots-the-largest-volca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-juno-spacecraft-spots-the-largest-volca/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What makes the event even more extraordinary is that it did not involve a single volcano, but multiple active sources.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Unearthed a 500,000-Year-Old Tool in England, and Cracked a Decades-Old Mystery - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-unearthed-a-500000-year-old-tool-i/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-unearthed-a-500000-year-old-tool-i/</guid><description>Buried for 500,000 years, this enigmatic object is forcing researchers to rethink early human capabilities.</description></item><item><title>From metabolism to disease: Mitochondria's hidden signaling networks unveiled - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/from-metabolism-to-disease-mitochondrias-hidd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:11:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/from-metabolism-to-disease-mitochondrias-hidd/</guid><description>The structural and functional characteristics of mitochondria shape their role as signaling organelles, with far-reaching effects regarding immune responses, inflammatory processes, and diseases. A research team led by Professor Konstanze F. Winklhofer at the…</description></item><item><title>Strange Bright Lines on Mercury Suggest It's Not 'Dead' After All - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/strange-bright-lines-on-mercury-suggest-its-n/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:01:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/strange-bright-lines-on-mercury-suggest-its-n/</guid><description>The smallest planet in our Solar System may be hiding a big secret.</description></item><item><title>Curiosity Just Lit Up Mars At Night And Revealed A Never-Before-Seen Side Of The Red Planet - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/curiosity-just-lit-up-mars-at-night-and-revea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/curiosity-just-lit-up-mars-at-night-and-revea/</guid><description>Curiosity switched on its lights during the Martian night, capturing a rare view that is forcing scientists to look at the Red Planet in a new way.</description></item><item><title>Gravitational wave signal tests Einstein's theory of general relativity - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravitational-wave-signal-tests-einsteins-the/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:26:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravitational-wave-signal-tests-einsteins-the/</guid><description>For those who watch gravitational waves roll in from the universe, GW250114 is a big one. It&amp;rsquo;s the clearest gravitational wave signal from a binary black hole merger to date, and it gives researchers an opportunity to test Albert Einstein&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity,…</description></item><item><title>Starlink in Full Retreat? 4,400 Satellites Slashed 70KM After ‘Dangerous’ Chinese Encounter - eurasiantimes.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starlink-in-full-retreat-4400-satellites-slas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:39:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starlink-in-full-retreat-4400-satellites-slas/</guid><description>Space scientists have long warned of an apocalyptic scenario: the collision of two satellites in Earth’s orbit, creating space debris that triggers a domino effect of further collisions, potentially rendering low Earth orbit unusable. This model of a chain re…</description></item><item><title>Is time a fundamental part of reality? A quiet revolution in physics suggests not - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/is-time-a-fundamental-part-of-reality-a-quiet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/is-time-a-fundamental-part-of-reality-a-quiet/</guid><description>Time feels like the most basic feature of reality. Seconds tick, days pass and everything from planetary motion to human memory seems to unfold along a single, irreversible direction. We are born and we die, in exactly that order. We plan our lives around tim…</description></item><item><title>Stone Age teenager was mauled by a bear 28,000 years ago, skeletal analysis confirms - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stone-age-teenager-was-mauled-by-a-bear-28000/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:04:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stone-age-teenager-was-mauled-by-a-bear-28000/</guid><description>The mystery of a Stone Age teenager&amp;rsquo;s death has been solved — 80 years after he was found in an ancient burial ground in Italy.</description></item><item><title>NASA Spots Eerie Black Spots in the Sahara Making Dunes Vanish on One Side and Grow On the Other - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-spots-eerie-black-spots-in-the-sahara-ma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-spots-eerie-black-spots-in-the-sahara-ma/</guid><description>A trio of ancient mesas is rewriting what we know about wind, sand, and deep-time geology, captured in stunning detail from space.</description></item><item><title>Discovery of a Galaxy at Redshift 14.4, 280-Million Years After the Big-Bang - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/discovery-of-a-galaxy-at-redshift-144-280-mil/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:23:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/discovery-of-a-galaxy-at-redshift-144-280-mil/</guid><description>On January 15, 2013, I published a comprehensive textbook with my former PhD student, Steve Furlanetto (currently a tenured professor at…</description></item><item><title>Top Anthropic Researcher No Longer Sure Whether AI Is Conscious - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/top-anthropic-researcher-no-longer-sure-wheth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/top-anthropic-researcher-no-longer-sure-wheth/</guid><description>Is AI conscious? Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s conflcited in-house philosopher is surprisingly open to the idea that they can already feel.</description></item><item><title>This AI has chemical expertise — and helps synthesize 35 new compounds - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-ai-has-chemical-expertise-and-helps-sy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:41:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-ai-has-chemical-expertise-and-helps-sy/</guid><description>An open-source program helps researchers bypass a major bottleneck in the process chemical synthesis.</description></item><item><title>Greenland’s Ice Vanished 7,000 Years Ago and That Terrifies Scientists Today. Is History About to Repeat Itself? - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/greenlands-ice-vanished-7000-years-ago-and-th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/greenlands-ice-vanished-7000-years-ago-and-th/</guid><description>For the first time, scientists have confirmed that a major part of Greenland&amp;rsquo;s ice cap, the Prudhoe Dome, was completely gone between 6,000 and 8,200 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discovered a city-sized bulge on the Yellowstone volcano’s north rim - oregonlive.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discovered-a-city-sized-bulge-on-t/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discovered-a-city-sized-bulge-on-t/</guid><description>The bulge first appeared in 1996 and has now returned, but Yellowstone Volcano Observatory says there&amp;rsquo;s no cause for alarm.</description></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope reveals new origin story for the universe's 1st supermassive black holes - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-reveals-new-origin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-reveals-new-origin/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Looking out into the universe is uniquely allowing us to look back in time and piece together this beautiful cosmic story that we are part of.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>NASA prepares for Artemis II wet dress rehearsal - wral.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-prepares-for-artemis-ii-wet-dress-rehear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:25:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-prepares-for-artemis-ii-wet-dress-rehear/</guid><description>Systems and procedures are tested including loading the rocket with 700,000 gallons of super-cold fuels.</description></item><item><title>Great White Sharks Grow Deadly New Types of Teeth as They Age - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/great-white-sharks-grow-deadly-new-types-of-t/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:01:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/great-white-sharks-grow-deadly-new-types-of-t/</guid><description>A great white shark is a masterwork of evolutionary engineering.</description></item><item><title>Did Edison Make a 'Wonder Material' 125 Years Before Its Official Creation? - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/did-edison-make-a-wonder-material-125-years-b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:44:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/did-edison-make-a-wonder-material-125-years-b/</guid><description>Inventor Thomas Edison is known for being ahead of his time, and a new study could add another notch to his overachieving belt.</description></item><item><title>Critical social media posts linked to retractions of scientific papers - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/critical-social-media-posts-linked-to-retract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/critical-social-media-posts-linked-to-retract/</guid><description>Online discussions can catch errors or fraud in articles that can be missed in peer review.</description></item><item><title>NASA Detects Most Powerful Eruption Ever on Jupiter’s Volcanic Moon Io - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-detects-most-powerful-eruption-ever-on-j/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-detects-most-powerful-eruption-ever-on-j/</guid><description>The volcanic hot spot is larger than Lake Superior, spewing eruptions six times the total energy of all of the world&amp;rsquo;s power plants.</description></item><item><title>New fear unlocked: Runaway black holes - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fear-unlocked-runaway-black-holes-physorg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fear-unlocked-runaway-black-holes-physorg/</guid><description>Last year, astronomers were fascinated by a runaway asteroid passing through our solar system from somewhere far beyond. It was moving at around 68 kilometers per second, just over double Earth&amp;rsquo;s speed around the sun.</description></item><item><title>NASA and SpaceX move up launch of Crew-12 astronauts to Feb. 11 as relief crew after ISS medical evacuation - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-and-spacex-move-up-launch-of-crew-12-ast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-and-spacex-move-up-launch-of-crew-12-ast/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s four days earlier than originally planned.</description></item><item><title>NASA readies unique science experiments and tech demonstrations for Artemis II crew - NASASpaceFlight.com -</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-readies-unique-science-experiments-and-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:23:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-readies-unique-science-experiments-and-t/</guid><description>Artemis II, the next mission in NASA’s Artemis program to explore the Moon, is scheduled…</description></item><item><title>NASA exoplanet probe tracks interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS to gauge its spin - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-exoplanet-probe-tracks-interstellar-come/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-exoplanet-probe-tracks-interstellar-come/</guid><description>The interstellar visitor may still have a few things to tell us before it leaves our solar system.</description></item><item><title>Teenage girl who lived in Italy 12,000 years ago had a rare form of dwarfism, DNA study shows - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/teenage-girl-who-lived-in-italy-12000-years-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/teenage-girl-who-lived-in-italy-12000-years-a/</guid><description>In 1963, researchers unearthed two Stone Age skeletons that were buried in an embraced position in a cave in Italy. Now, DNA testing has revealed that one of them had a rare genetic condition.</description></item><item><title>Massive runaway stars in the Milky Way: Observational study explores origins and ejection process - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-runaway-stars-in-the-milky-way-observ/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:51:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-runaway-stars-in-the-milky-way-observ/</guid><description>Researchers from the Institute of Cosmos Sciences of the University of Barcelona (ICCUB) and the Institute of Space Studies of Catalonia (IEEC), in collaboration with the Institute of Astrophysics of the Canary Islands (IAC), have led the most extensive obser…</description></item><item><title>Essential oils may provide a natural remedy for antibiotic resistance - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/essential-oils-may-provide-a-natural-remedy-f/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:41:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/essential-oils-may-provide-a-natural-remedy-f/</guid><description>Thyme, rosemary, and lavender have long been associated with natural medicine. Today, however, these aromatic plants are increasingly being studied by researchers. &amp;ldquo;In an era of ever-increasing microbial resistance to antibiotics, there is a growing emphasis …</description></item><item><title>Russian Scientists Test Plasma Engine That Could Cut Mars Travel to About 30 Days - Yahoo! Tech</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-scientists-test-plasma-engine-that-co/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-scientists-test-plasma-engine-that-co/</guid><description>Russia is testing a plasma engine prototype designed to slash Mars travel time to just 60 days. Developed by Rosatom’s Troitsk Institute, the system uses&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Beyond polymers: New state-of-the-art 3D micro and nanofabrication technique overcomes material limitations - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beyond-polymers-new-state-of-the-art-3d-micro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:19:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beyond-polymers-new-state-of-the-art-3d-micro/</guid><description>Building things so small that they are smaller than the width of a human hair was previously achieved by using a method called two-photon polymerization, also known as 2PP—today&amp;rsquo;s state-of-the-art in 3D micro- and nanofabrication. Tiny sculptures such as a mi…</description></item><item><title>New animal species that survived mass extinction event half a billion years ago found in a quarry in China - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-animal-species-that-survived-mass-extinct/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:21:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-animal-species-that-survived-mass-extinct/</guid><description>The fossils offer a rare glimpse into a cataclysmic event that brought a sudden end to the greatest explosion of life in our planet&amp;rsquo;s history.</description></item><item><title>430,000-year-old wooden handheld tools from Greece are the oldest on record — and they predate modern humans - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/430000-year-old-wooden-handheld-tools-from-gr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:13:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/430000-year-old-wooden-handheld-tools-from-gr/</guid><description>Archaeologists have found the oldest-known surviving examples of handheld wooden tools.</description></item><item><title>Constraints on axion dark matter by distributed intercity quantum sensors - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/constraints-on-axion-dark-matter-by-distribut/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/constraints-on-axion-dark-matter-by-distribut/</guid><description>Amplification and optimal noise filtering in hyperpolarized noble-gas spins of observations from distributed intercity quantum sensors monitoring for unexpected transient rotations of polarized spins set parameter range constraints in the search for axion dar…</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover the possible secret blueprint of the human body in a 700-million-year-old brainless creature... and it was at the bottom of the sea - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-the-possible-secret-bluep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:25:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-the-possible-secret-bluep/</guid><description>You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a genius: anemones have been using human genes to form their bodies for 600 million years.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover seismic hotspot in US that could trigger devastating magnitude-8 earthquakes - AOL.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-seismic-hotspot-in-us-tha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:23:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-seismic-hotspot-in-us-tha/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re on shakier ground than previously thought.</description></item><item><title>Webb pushes boundaries of observable universe closer to Big Bang - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/webb-pushes-boundaries-of-observable-universe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/webb-pushes-boundaries-of-observable-universe/</guid><description>The NASA/ESA/CSA James Webb Space Telescope has topped itself once again, delivering on its promise to push the boundaries of the observable universe closer to cosmic dawn with the confirmation of a bright galaxy that existed 280 million years after the Big B…</description></item><item><title>Superfluids are supposed to flow indefinitely. Physicists just watched one stop moving - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/superfluids-are-supposed-to-flow-indefinitely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/superfluids-are-supposed-to-flow-indefinitely/</guid><description>Ordinary matter, when cooled, transitions from a gas into a liquid. Cool it further still, and it freezes into a solid. Quantum matter, however, can behave very differently. In the early 20th century, researchers discovered that when helium is cooled, it tran…</description></item><item><title>The 14,000-Year-Old Stomach: How a Wolf Puppy Solved the Mystery of the Woolly Rhino’s Extinction - A-Z Animals</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-14000-year-old-stomach-how-a-wolf-puppy-s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-14000-year-old-stomach-how-a-wolf-puppy-s/</guid><description>The contents of an ancient wolf pup&amp;rsquo;s stomach yields surprising clues into the genetic lineage of extinct species.</description></item><item><title>NASA Has a New Estimate for Europa’s Ice Shell, and Whoa Is It Ever Thick - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-has-a-new-estimate-for-europas-ice-shell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-has-a-new-estimate-for-europas-ice-shell/</guid><description>Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s fourth-largest moon is a main character in our search for other life-friendly places in our solar system.</description></item><item><title>Scientists just mapped the family tree of all 11,000 bird species—and you can explore it - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-mapped-the-family-tree-of-all/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:18:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-mapped-the-family-tree-of-all/</guid><description>The Cornell Lab of Ornithology today announced the release of a new online tool for studying biodiversity and the evolutionary relationships among birds: the illustrated Birds of the World Phylogeny Explorer. Available on Birds of the World, the Phylogeny Exp…</description></item><item><title>A Comprehensive Network for the Discovery and Characterization of Interstellar Objects Like… - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-comprehensive-network-for-the-discovery-and/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:33:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-comprehensive-network-for-the-discovery-and/</guid><description>Inspired by the unresolved anomalies displayed by the latest interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS (as listed here), I co-authored a new paper with…</description></item><item><title>A Thin Line in the Ocean Is Doing What We Thought Was Impossible - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-thin-line-in-the-ocean-is-doing-what-we-tho/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-thin-line-in-the-ocean-is-doing-what-we-tho/</guid><description>For decades, attention went elsewhere. But these ocean “fronts” may be the missing piece in how carbon is taken up.</description></item><item><title>'Extraordinary' trove of ancient species found in China quarry - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/extraordinary-trove-of-ancient-species-found/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/extraordinary-trove-of-ancient-species-found/</guid><description>Almost a hundred new animal species that survived a mass extinction event half a billion years ago have been discovered in a small quarry in China&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A possible ice-cold Earth discovered in the archives of the retired Kepler Space Telescope - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-possible-ice-cold-earth-discovered-in-the-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:10:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-possible-ice-cold-earth-discovered-in-the-a/</guid><description>Scientists continue to mine data gathered by NASA&amp;rsquo;s Kepler Space Telescope, retired in 2018, and continue to turn up surprises. A new paper reveals the latest: a possible rocky planet slightly larger than Earth, orbiting a sun-like star about 146 light-years …</description></item><item><title>Low-power integrated optical amplification through second-harmonic resonance - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/low-power-integrated-optical-amplification-th/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/low-power-integrated-optical-amplification-th/</guid><description>An integrated optical parametric amplifier on thin-film lithium niobate achieves more than 17 dB gain with less than 200 mW input power.</description></item><item><title>Asteroid 2024 YR4: Astronomers Are Preparing For The Most Energetic Lunar Impact Witnessed In Human History - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/asteroid-2024-yr4-astronomers-are-preparing-f/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:33:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/asteroid-2024-yr4-astronomers-are-preparing-f/</guid><description>If the impact occurs,</description></item><item><title>NASA Webb Pushes Boundaries of Observable Universe Closer to Big Bang - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-pushes-boundaries-of-observable-uni/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-pushes-boundaries-of-observable-uni/</guid><description>NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope has topped itself once again, delivering on its promise to push the boundaries of the observable universe closer to cosmic</description></item><item><title>The Amazing Maser - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-amazing-maser-hackaday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-amazing-maser-hackaday/</guid><description>While it has become a word, laser used to be an acronym: “light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation”. But there is an even older technology called a maser, which is the sa…</description></item><item><title>The infant universe's 'primordial soup' was actually soupy, study finds - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-infant-universes-primordial-soup-was-actu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:40:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-infant-universes-primordial-soup-was-actu/</guid><description>In its first moments, the infant universe was a trillion-degree-hot soup of quarks and gluons. These elementary particles zinged around at light speed, creating a &amp;ldquo;quark-gluon plasma&amp;rdquo; that lasted for only a few millionths of a second. The primordial goo then …</description></item><item><title>Something Strange Is Happening on the Seafloor, Scientists Watched for 10 Years and Saw Nothing - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-strange-is-happening-on-the-seafloo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-strange-is-happening-on-the-seafloo/</guid><description>Deep beneath the waves, something is shifting. Life once drawn to sunken whales and wood is missing, leaving the seafloor strangely untouched.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Find Earth-sized Exoplanet Candidate in Star's Habitable Zone - Ground News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-earth-sized-exoplanet-candida/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-earth-sized-exoplanet-candida/</guid><description>An international team led by Australian astronomers identified HD 137010 b, a potentially habitable Earth-sized planet candidate about 146 light-years away, using archival data from NASA&amp;rsquo;s retired Kepler Space Telescope.</description></item><item><title>Physicists Say They May Have Found a Portal to a Fifth Dimension Where Dark Matter Could Be Hiding - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-say-they-may-have-found-a-portal-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-say-they-may-have-found-a-portal-t/</guid><description>A new theory suggests that dark matter, which makes up most of the universe&amp;rsquo;s mass, might not be invisible, it might be in another dimension.</description></item><item><title>Two twisty doughnut shapes solve a 150-year-old geometry puzzle - Boing Boing</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-twisty-doughnut-shapes-solve-a-150-year-o/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/two-twisty-doughnut-shapes-solve-a-150-year-o/</guid><description>Two doughnut-shaped surfaces look completely different but share identical measurements. It took 150 years to find them.</description></item><item><title>Scientists let AI loose on Hubble’s archives - The Verge</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-let-ai-loose-on-hubbles-archives-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:15:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-let-ai-loose-on-hubbles-archives-t/</guid><description>AI model AnomalyMatch took just 2.5 days to flag rarities like merging galaxies and gravitational lenses from 100 million image cutouts in Hubble’s archives.</description></item><item><title>Diagnostic dilemma: Liquid-nitrogen-infused cocktail popped a man's stomach like a balloon - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/diagnostic-dilemma-liquid-nitrogen-infused-co/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/diagnostic-dilemma-liquid-nitrogen-infused-co/</guid><description>Liquid nitrogen can be used safely in food preparation — but one man&amp;rsquo;s stomach burst after he threw back a cocktail that had been cooled with the substance.</description></item><item><title>Diets don't work for men who want to lose weight – but these 5 things do - BikeRadar</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/diets-dont-work-for-men-who-want-to-lose-weig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/diets-dont-work-for-men-who-want-to-lose-weig/</guid><description>Research suggests men require a gender-specific approach to weight loss, fusing camaraderie, fitness targets and group exercise</description></item><item><title>Frozen methane bubbles make this lake look like a portal to another world - Boing Boing</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-methane-bubbles-make-this-lake-look-li/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:36:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-methane-bubbles-make-this-lake-look-li/</guid><description>These frozen methane bubbles look like stacked UFOs hovering beneath the ice. Bacteria release gas that freezes mid-rise.</description></item><item><title>SpaceX launches advanced GPS satellite for US Space Force (photos) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-launches-advanced-gps-satellite-for-us/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-launches-advanced-gps-satellite-for-us/</guid><description>Liftoff of the GPS III-SV09 mission occurred at 11:53 p.m. ET on Tuesday (Jan. 27).</description></item><item><title>“Greater detail than ever before.” Ancient creature found immaculately entombed in amber - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/greater-detail-than-ever-before-ancient-cre/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:07:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/greater-detail-than-ever-before-ancient-cre/</guid><description>The now-extinct animal was one of three species discovered within fossilised tree resin from a museum in Germany.</description></item><item><title>443-million-year-old eel-like animal discovered near Glasgow stuns scientists - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/443-million-year-old-eel-like-animal-discover/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:07:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/443-million-year-old-eel-like-animal-discover/</guid><description>A team of scientists from the University of Manchester have uncovered some of the earliest evidence of advanced, camera-like eyes in two jawless fish found just south of the Scottish city…</description></item><item><title>Great white sharks grow a whole new kind of tooth for slicing bone as they age - The Conversation</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/great-white-sharks-grow-a-whole-new-kind-of-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 23:25:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/great-white-sharks-grow-a-whole-new-kind-of-t/</guid><description>The teeth of white sharks are not static weapons but living records of a shark’s changing lifestyle.</description></item><item><title>New fear unlocked: runaway black holes - The Conversation</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fear-unlocked-runaway-black-holes-the-con/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:55:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fear-unlocked-runaway-black-holes-the-con/</guid><description>Astronomers have spotted runaway black holes screaming through space, leaving trails of stars in in their wake.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers discover the 'growing pains' of teenage exoplanets - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-the-growing-pains-of-tee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-the-growing-pains-of-tee/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve often seen the &amp;lsquo;baby pictures&amp;rsquo; of planets forming, but until now, the &amp;lsquo;teenage years&amp;rsquo; have been a missing link.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Higher water levels could turn cultivated peatland in the North into a CO₂ sink - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/higher-water-levels-could-turn-cultivated-pea/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/higher-water-levels-could-turn-cultivated-pea/</guid><description>In its natural state, peatland is one of the largest carbon stores in nature. This is because the soil is so waterlogged and low in oxygen that dead plant material breaks down very slowly. The plants do not fully decompose but instead accumulate over thousand…</description></item><item><title>Can Bacteria from the Toilet Really Travel to Our Toothbrushes? - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/can-bacteria-from-the-toilet-really-travel-to/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:55:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/can-bacteria-from-the-toilet-really-travel-to/</guid><description>The conclucions are a bit unsettling.</description></item><item><title>'The dream has come true': Standard model of cosmology holds up in massive 6-year study of the universe — with one big caveat - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-dream-has-come-true-standard-model-of-cos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:15:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-dream-has-come-true-standard-model-of-cos/</guid><description>The six-year Dark Energy Survey has released its full results, showing that two leading models of cosmology are equally valid — but both fail to explain one key observation.</description></item><item><title>Rare Predator Thought to Be Extinct Spotted on Camera in California’s Remote Forests - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/rare-predator-thought-to-be-extinct-spotted-o/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/rare-predator-thought-to-be-extinct-spotted-o/</guid><description>Once believed to be lost forever, a rare predator has been spotted in California’s remote forests.</description></item><item><title>NASA moves critical fueling test for Artemis 2 moon rocket up to Jan. 31 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-moves-critical-fueling-test-for-artemis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:51:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-moves-critical-fueling-test-for-artemis/</guid><description>The SLS wet dress rehearsal is the rocket&amp;rsquo;s last major hurdle before launch.</description></item><item><title>Milky Way is embedded in a 'large-scale sheet' of dark matter, which explains motions of nearby galaxies - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/milky-way-is-embedded-in-a-large-scale-sheet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:20:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/milky-way-is-embedded-in-a-large-scale-sheet/</guid><description>Computer simulations carried out by astronomers from the University of Groningen in collaboration with researchers from Germany, France and Sweden show that most of the (dark) matter beyond the Local Group of galaxies (which includes the Milky Way and the And…</description></item><item><title>Professor Avi Loeb Has an Official YouTube Channel - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/professor-avi-loeb-has-an-official-youtube-ch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/professor-avi-loeb-has-an-official-youtube-ch/</guid><description>Wonderful news! I have just launched my official YouTube channel at the link:</description></item><item><title>Massive star WOH G64 is still a red supergiant—for now - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-star-woh-g64-is-still-a-red-supergian/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:45:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-star-woh-g64-is-still-a-red-supergian/</guid><description>An international team of astronomers led by a researcher at Keele University has solved a long-standing cosmic mystery surrounding one of the most extreme stars ever observed. The star, known as WOH G64, is located in the Large Magellanic Cloud—a satellite ga…</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Juno Measures Thickness of Europa’s Ice Shell - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-juno-measures-thickness-of-europas-ice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:21:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-juno-measures-thickness-of-europas-ice/</guid><description>Results from the solar-powered spacecraft provide a new measurement of the thickness of the ice shell encasing the Jovian moon’s ocean.</description></item><item><title>Highly stable Cu₄₅ superatom could transform carbon recycling - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/highly-stable-cu-superatom-could-transform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/highly-stable-cu-superatom-could-transform/</guid><description>After years of trying, scientists have finally created a stable superatom of copper, a long-sought-after chemical breakthrough that could revolutionize how we deal with carbon emissions.</description></item><item><title>Gold 'supraballs' nearly double solar energy absorption in tests - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-supraballs-nearly-double-solar-energy-ab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-supraballs-nearly-double-solar-energy-ab/</guid><description>Sunbeams contain a lot of energy. But current technology for harvesting solar power doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture as much as it could. Now, in ACS Applied Materials &amp;amp; Interfaces, researchers report that gold nanospheres, named supraballs, can absorb nearly all wavelengths …</description></item><item><title>Star’s Final Breath Appears Like Columns of Smoke in Breathtaking New James Webb Image - Good News Network</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stars-final-breath-appears-like-columns-of-sm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stars-final-breath-appears-like-columns-of-sm/</guid><description>Imaged many times by previous space telescopes, the Helix Nebula is loved for its similarity to the Eye of Sauron from The Lord of the Rings.</description></item><item><title>Ancient Martian beach discovered, providing new clues to red planet's habitability - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ancient-martian-beach-discovered-providing-ne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:24:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ancient-martian-beach-discovered-providing-ne/</guid><description>New findings from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance rover have revealed evidence of wave-formed beaches and rocks altered by subsurface water in a Martian crater that once held a vast lake—considerably expanding the timeline for potential habitability at this ancient site.…</description></item><item><title>Composite tool find puts China in tech revolution up to 160,000 years ago: paper - South China Morning Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/composite-tool-find-puts-china-in-tech-revolu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/composite-tool-find-puts-china-in-tech-revolu/</guid><description>Team says discovery of 2,600 stone tools, including hafted tools, reshapes understanding of human evolution in eastern Asia.</description></item><item><title>160,000-year-old sophisticated stone tools discovered in China may not have been made by Homo sapiens - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/160000-year-old-sophisticated-stone-tools-dis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/160000-year-old-sophisticated-stone-tools-dis/</guid><description>Archaeologists have found the oldest known evidence of hafted tools in East Asia, and they challenge a previously held assumption about stone tool use.</description></item><item><title>Watch NASA's Artemis 2 moon rocket on the launch pad with this 24-hour livestream - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-nasas-artemis-2-moon-rocket-on-the-laun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-nasas-artemis-2-moon-rocket-on-the-laun/</guid><description>Artemis 2 could launch as early as Feb. 6.</description></item><item><title>Artemis II: Inside NASA’s New Ride to the Moon - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-inside-nasas-new-ride-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:06:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-inside-nasas-new-ride-to-the-moon/</guid><description>Tour Orion—NASA’s spaceship to the Moon—and pop the hood of NASA’s Space Launch System rocket, which sends Artemis astronauts to deep space.</description></item><item><title>Chinese satellite forces 4,400 of its Starlink rivals into lower altitude: study - South China Morning Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinese-satellite-forces-4400-of-its-starlink/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinese-satellite-forces-4400-of-its-starlink/</guid><description>Researchers in China said the SpaceX decision was ‘directly triggered’ by a close call between two satellites in December.</description></item><item><title>NASA assembling a formal anomaly review board for MAVEN - theregister.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-assembling-a-formal-anomaly-review-board/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-assembling-a-formal-anomaly-review-board/</guid><description>: Communication attempts ongoing for stricken spacecraft</description></item><item><title>Who are the Artemis II crew? Nasa’s moon astronauts want to be forgotten - The Times</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/who-are-the-artemis-ii-crew-nasas-moon-astron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/who-are-the-artemis-ii-crew-nasas-moon-astron/</guid><description>Christina Koch, Reid Wiseman, Victor Glover and Jeremy Hansen have gone into quarantine before a mission that is not without risks — but could pave the way for humans on Mars</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Curiosity Rover Just Found Something On Mars That Looks Exactly Like Coral - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-curiosity-rover-just-found-something-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-curiosity-rover-just-found-something-on/</guid><description>A strange coral-like rock just appeared in NASA’s latest Mars photos. Could this tiny structure reveal secrets of ancient water?</description></item><item><title>Are mysterious 'Little Red Dots' discovered by the James Webb Space Telescope actually nurseries for direct-collapse black holes? - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-mysterious-little-red-dots-discovered-by/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-mysterious-little-red-dots-discovered-by/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It is exciting to think that Little Red Dots may represent the first direct observational evidence of the birth of the most massive black holes in the&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Paleontologists Smashed Open Red Rocks… and Found Perfectly Preserved Fossils - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/paleontologists-smashed-open-red-rocks-and-f/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/paleontologists-smashed-open-red-rocks-and-f/</guid><description>What looked like lifeless rock turned out to contain fossils, and the discovery is nothing short of astonishing.</description></item><item><title>Hidden Faults Discovered at a Major US Earthquake Hotspot - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hidden-faults-discovered-at-a-major-us-earthq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:01:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hidden-faults-discovered-at-a-major-us-earthq/</guid><description>Three huge tectonic plates meet at the Mendocino triple junction off the coast of northern California, and a new study reveals that the underlying geology is significantly more complex than current models show.</description></item><item><title>Artificial Intelligence Reveals Fingerprints Aren't Truly Unique, Debunking 100 Years of Forensic Science - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artificial-intelligence-reveals-fingerprints/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artificial-intelligence-reveals-fingerprints/</guid><description>A breakthrough in AI has uncovered hidden patterns in fingerprints that experts never thought existed. This discovery could upend over a century of forensic science, challenge the reliability of biometric security, and force courts to reconsider long-held ass…</description></item><item><title>What were the first animals? The fierce sponge–jelly battle that just won’t end - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-were-the-first-animals-the-fierce-sponge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-were-the-first-animals-the-fierce-sponge/</guid><description>For almost two decades, scientists have debated whether sponges or comb jellies are the first animal lineage. Now some are calling for a more harmonious approach.</description></item><item><title>Ambitious Survey Hints at Tantalizing New Theories on Dark Energy - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ambitious-survey-hints-at-tantalizing-new-the/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:01:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ambitious-survey-hints-at-tantalizing-new-the/</guid><description>Astrophysicists are closer than ever to solving the mystery of what makes up almost 70 percent of the Universe.</description></item><item><title>Voyager 2's close encounter with Uranus wasn't in the original plan - theregister.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/voyager-2s-close-encounter-with-uranus-wasnt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/voyager-2s-close-encounter-with-uranus-wasnt/</guid><description>: 40 years later, mission boffin recalls being told to pronounce it correctly</description></item><item><title>Magnetic avalanches on the sun reveal the hidden engine powering solar flares - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/magnetic-avalanches-on-the-sun-reveal-the-hid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/magnetic-avalanches-on-the-sun-reveal-the-hid/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;This is one of the most exciting results from Solar Orbiter so far.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Mighty microscopic fibers are the key to cell division and life itself - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mighty-microscopic-fibers-are-the-key-to-cell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:43:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mighty-microscopic-fibers-are-the-key-to-cell/</guid><description>Every second, millions of cells in your body divide in two. In the space of an hour, they duplicate their DNA and grow a web of protein fibers around it called a spindle. The spindle extends its many fibers from the chromosomes in the center to the edges of t…</description></item><item><title>Toothbrush-activated powder whitens, repairs and protects teeth - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/toothbrush-activated-powder-whitens-repairs-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/toothbrush-activated-powder-whitens-repairs-a/</guid><description>Even with regular brushing, teeth can become stained from genetic factors or consuming foods and drinks like tomatoes and coffee. Chemical whiteners can help, but they can also damage teeth in the process. So, researchers reporting in ACS Nano have designed a…</description></item><item><title>Super-Earth exoplanets may have built-in magnetic protection from churning magma — and that's good news for life - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/super-earth-exoplanets-may-have-built-in-magn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/super-earth-exoplanets-may-have-built-in-magn/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;A strong magnetic field is very important for life on a planet.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Connect This Lethal Poison to the Origin of Life on Earth, and Possibly Beyond - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-connect-this-lethal-poison-to-the/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-connect-this-lethal-poison-to-the/</guid><description>Long feared as a silent killer, hydrogen cyanide may have been a key ingredient in the origin of life on Earth.</description></item><item><title>Earth's Lower Orbit Could Rapidly Collapse, Scientists Warn, Raining Deadly Missiles Onto Planet Below - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earths-lower-orbit-could-rapidly-collapse-sci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:08:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earths-lower-orbit-could-rapidly-collapse-sci/</guid><description>A solar storm could wreck havoc on our satellites and send them all crashing into each other, creating an unstoppable debris storm.</description></item><item><title>Scientists recover the oldest wooden tools from a site in Greece - AP News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-recover-the-oldest-wooden-tools-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-recover-the-oldest-wooden-tools-fr/</guid><description>Scientists say two artifacts found at a lake shore in Greece are the oldest wooden tools uncovered so far. One is a spindly stick possibly used for digging and the other is a handheld chunk that may have been used to shape stone tools. They were found in Gree…</description></item><item><title>Only 16 People Might See This Eclipse, And It’ll Be the Most Spectacular in Years - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/only-16-people-might-see-this-eclipse-and-itl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/only-16-people-might-see-this-eclipse-and-itl/</guid><description>A rare solar eclipse is set to unfold in one of the most remote places on Earth. But who will actually be there to witness it?</description></item><item><title>Scientists research how Greenland sharks live for hundreds of years - Boing Boing</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-research-how-greenland-sharks-live/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:42:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-research-how-greenland-sharks-live/</guid><description>The scarring that indicates cardiovascular disease in humans appears not to affect the sharks' hearts.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious dark matter seen in new high-resolution map of distant galaxies - CBS News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-dark-matter-seen-in-new-high-resol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-dark-matter-seen-in-new-high-resol/</guid><description>Dark matter doesn&amp;rsquo;t absorb or give off light so scientists can&amp;rsquo;t study it directly. But they can observe how its gravity warps and bends the star stuff around it.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Finally Figured Out How Much Groundwater There Is Under the US and It Is Enough to Fill the Great Lakes 13 Times Over - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-finally-figured-out-how-much-groun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:19:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-finally-figured-out-how-much-groun/</guid><description>Researchers used 1 million data points and a machine learning algorithm to estimate groundwater stores with higher resolution than ever before.</description></item><item><title>NASA Technology Brings Golden Age of Exploration to Earth - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-technology-brings-golden-age-of-explorat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-technology-brings-golden-age-of-explorat/</guid><description>As NASA fosters technologies needed to live and work farther away from home than ever before, the agency’s Technology Transfer program has the sole mission of</description></item><item><title>AI makes quantum field theories computable - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-makes-quantum-field-theories-computable-ph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-makes-quantum-field-theories-computable-ph/</guid><description>An old puzzle in particle physics has been solved: How can quantum field theories be best formulated on a lattice to optimally simulate them on a computer? The answer comes from AI.</description></item><item><title>The Wallace Line Forms an Invisible Barrier That Keeps Tigers and Koalas from Ever Meeting. We Finally Know What Happened - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-wallace-line-forms-an-invisible-barrier-t/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:58:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-wallace-line-forms-an-invisible-barrier-t/</guid><description>Ever wondered why you won&amp;rsquo;t find kangaroos outside Australia? It all started with massive climate change millions of years ago.</description></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope sees comet-seeding crystals flowing far from newborn star (photo) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-sees-comet-seeding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-sees-comet-seeding/</guid><description>This process could help explain how the comets found at the outskirts of our own solar system formed.</description></item><item><title>Scalable and multiplexed recorders of gene regulation dynamics across weeks - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scalable-and-multiplexed-recorders-of-gene-re/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scalable-and-multiplexed-recorders-of-gene-re/</guid><description>Nature - Scalable and multiplexed recorders of gene regulation dynamics across weeks</description></item><item><title>Astronomy Live On Twitch - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-live-on-twitch-hackaday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-live-on-twitch-hackaday/</guid><description>Although there are a few hobbies that have low-cost entry points, amateur astronomy is not generally among them. A tabletop Dobsonian might cost a few hundred dollars, and that is just the entry po…</description></item><item><title>NASA Reveals New Details About Dark Matter’s Influence on Universe - NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-reveals-new-details-about-dark-matters-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:02:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-reveals-new-details-about-dark-matters-i/</guid><description>With the Webb telescope’s unprecedented sensitivity, scientists are learning more about dark matter’s influence on stars, galaxies, and even planets like Earth.</description></item><item><title>570-Megapixel Dark Energy Camera Unravels Mysteries of the Dark Universe - PetaPixel</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/570-megapixel-dark-energy-camera-unravels-mys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/570-megapixel-dark-energy-camera-unravels-mys/</guid><description>Scientists are narrowing the scope of cosmology models thanks to the high-res Dark Energy Camera.</description></item><item><title>Mapping cell development with mathematics-informed machine learning - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mapping-cell-development-with-mathematics-inf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:40:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mapping-cell-development-with-mathematics-inf/</guid><description>The development of humans and other animals unfolds gradually over time, with cells taking on specific roles and functions via a process called cell fate determination. The fate of individual cells, or in other words, what type of cells they will become, is i…</description></item><item><title>Milky Way shines over Gemini South Observatory photo of the day for Jan. 26, 2025 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/milky-way-shines-over-gemini-south-observator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/milky-way-shines-over-gemini-south-observator/</guid><description>Sometimes astronomers don&amp;rsquo;t need giant telescopes to observe the wonders of the cosmos; they just need to look up at the night sky.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Found a Creature That’s Breaking the Rules of Reproduction - Yahoo News Canada</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-a-creature-thats-breaking-th/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-a-creature-thats-breaking-th/</guid><description>Quite an advantage in today’s world.</description></item><item><title>Mars Could Turn Green… And It’s No Longer Just Science Fiction - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-could-turn-green-and-its-no-longer-just/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-could-turn-green-and-its-no-longer-just/</guid><description>New research suggests making Mars green could be a real, testable goal, if we&amp;rsquo;re ready to take the ethical leap.</description></item><item><title>Meet the Sea’s Most Mysterious Creature, It Looks Like Sauron, But Bites Like a Jelly - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-seas-most-mysterious-creature-it-loo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-seas-most-mysterious-creature-it-loo/</guid><description>This glowing ocean creature looks like it came from a sci-fi movie, but it&amp;rsquo;s 100% real.</description></item><item><title>Post-Perihelion Spectrum of 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/post-perihelion-spectrum-of-3i-atlas-avi-loeb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:36:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/post-perihelion-spectrum-of-3i-atlas-avi-loeb/</guid><description>After its closest-approach to the Sun (perihelion) on October 29, 2025, the interstellar object 3I/ATLAS was observed on November 16, 2025…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Uncover Strange New Life Forms Inside Human Bodies That Don't Fit Any Known Category of Living Things - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-strange-new-life-forms-ins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-strange-new-life-forms-ins/</guid><description>Hidden inside the human body, scientists have uncovered thousands of bizarre RNA loops unlike anything in biology. These microscopic structures don’t act like viruses or bacteria and could rewrite what we think life is.</description></item><item><title>Microbes in Space Mutated And Developed a Remarkable Ability - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/microbes-in-space-mutated-and-developed-a-rem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:01:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/microbes-in-space-mutated-and-developed-a-rem/</guid><description>A box full of viruses and bacteria has completed its return trip to the International Space Station, and the changes these &amp;lsquo;bugs&amp;rsquo; experienced in their travels could help us Earthlings tackle drug-resistant infections.</description></item><item><title>Scientists just got the clearest picture of the dark universe yet: 'Now the dream has come true' - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-got-the-clearest-picture-of-t/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-got-the-clearest-picture-of-t/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;These results from the Dark Energy Survey shine new light on our understanding of the universe and its expansion.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Artemis II astronauts enter quarantine. A milestone moment in the next crewed mission to the Moon - BBC Sky at Night Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-astronauts-enter-quarantine-a-mile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:17:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-astronauts-enter-quarantine-a-mile/</guid><description>The Artemis II astronauts have entered quarantine, ahead of the launch of their mission to the Moon and back.</description></item><item><title>Live coverage: SpaceX to launch GPS 3 satellite following switch from ULA Vulcan rocket - Spaceflight Now</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/live-coverage-spacex-to-launch-gps-3-satellit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:05:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/live-coverage-spacex-to-launch-gps-3-satellit/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>'Lost City' Deep Beneath The Ocean Is Unlike Anything Seen Before on Earth - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lost-city-deep-beneath-the-ocean-is-unlike-an/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lost-city-deep-beneath-the-ocean-is-unlike-an/</guid><description>Close to the summit of an underwater mountain west of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, a jagged landscape of towers rises from the gloom.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Identify Brain Waves That Define The Limits of 'You' - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-identify-brain-waves-that-define-t/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-identify-brain-waves-that-define-t/</guid><description>At what point do &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; end and the outside world begins? It might feel like a weird question with an obvious answer, but your brain has to work surprisingly hard to judge that boundary.</description></item><item><title>Starfish Control Hundreds of Feet Without a Brain. Here's How. - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starfish-control-hundreds-of-feet-without-a-b/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/starfish-control-hundreds-of-feet-without-a-b/</guid><description>Starfish (aka sea stars) are master climbers.</description></item><item><title>Breakthrough laser technique holds quantum matter in stable packets - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/breakthrough-laser-technique-holds-quantum-ma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/breakthrough-laser-technique-holds-quantum-ma/</guid><description>For the first time, physicists have generated and observed stable bright matter-wave solitons with attractive interactions within a grid of laser light.</description></item><item><title>One Flour Swap Can Transform Your Sourdough - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/one-flour-swap-can-transform-your-sourdough-s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:45:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/one-flour-swap-can-transform-your-sourdough-s/</guid><description>The flour you choose helps decide which microbes run your sourdough and how it tastes.</description></item><item><title>Bacteria use wrapping flagella to tunnel through microscopic passages, research reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bacteria-use-wrapping-flagella-to-tunnel-thro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bacteria-use-wrapping-flagella-to-tunnel-thro/</guid><description>Researchers have discovered how bacteria break through spaces barely larger than themselves, by wrapping their flagella around their bodies and moving forward. Using a microfluidic device that mimics insect gut channels, the team revealed a remarkable &amp;ldquo;flagel…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Intrigued by Unfamiliar Life Form - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-intrigued-by-unfamiliar-life-form/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-intrigued-by-unfamiliar-life-form/</guid><description>A team of researchers say that a puzzling, spire-shaped organism that lived 400 million year ago is like no type of creature ever found.</description></item><item><title>Strange Red Rocks in Australia Are Challenging Long-Held Ideas About Fossils - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/strange-red-rocks-in-australia-are-challengin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:35:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/strange-red-rocks-in-australia-are-challengin/</guid><description>Iron-rich rocks at McGraths Flat preserve Miocene rainforest life in remarkable detail, reshaping ideas about how and where exceptional fossils form. Beneath agricultural land in the central tablelands of New South Wales sits one of Australia’s most remarkabl…</description></item><item><title>Purple Isn’t Real, Science Says. Your Brain Is Just Making It Up. - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/purple-isnt-real-science-says-your-brain-is-j/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/purple-isnt-real-science-says-your-brain-is-j/</guid><description>The human eye does not actually see purple, as purple is not a color on the visual spectrum, scientists say. Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Warn Of A Rapid Collapse Scenario In Earth’s Busiest Orbital Zone - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-warn-of-a-rapid-collapse-scenario/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-warn-of-a-rapid-collapse-scenario/</guid><description>A new study warns that Low Earth Orbit could shift from stable to chaotic in just days, threatening satellites and the services they support.</description></item><item><title>Mars Atmosphere May Hold the Key to Human Survival, Scientists Reveal - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-atmosphere-may-hold-the-key-to-human-sur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-atmosphere-may-hold-the-key-to-human-sur/</guid><description>A new study reveals how moisture in the Martian atmosphere could provide an essential backup water source for future human missions.</description></item><item><title>New DNA analysis rewrites the story of the Beachy Head Woman - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-dna-analysis-rewrites-the-story-of-the-be/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-dna-analysis-rewrites-the-story-of-the-be/</guid><description>A Roman-era skeleton discovered in southern England has finally given up her secrets after more than a decade of debate. Known as the Beachy Head Woman, she was once thought to have roots in sub-Saharan Africa or the Mediterranean—an idea that sparked global …</description></item><item><title>Novel biosensor enables real-time tracking of iron (II) in living cells - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/novel-biosensor-enables-real-time-tracking-of/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/novel-biosensor-enables-real-time-tracking-of/</guid><description>Iron is an essential trace element in biological cells. The concentration of the element and its so-called redox state—it can exist either in a doubly ionized state as iron (II) (Fe2+) or a triply ionized state as iron (III) (Fe3+)—play a key role in metaboli…</description></item><item><title>Scientists twist tiny crystals to control electricity - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-twist-tiny-crystals-to-control-ele/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:49:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-twist-tiny-crystals-to-control-ele/</guid><description>Researchers have developed a technique that allows them to carve complex three dimensional nanodevices directly from single crystals. To demonstrate its power, they sculpted microscopic helices from a magnetic material and found that the structures behave lik…</description></item><item><title>A drying climate is making East Africa pull apart faster - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-drying-climate-is-making-east-africa-pull-a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-drying-climate-is-making-east-africa-pull-a/</guid><description>A switch from a humid to a dry climate has led the Eastern African Rift Zone to pull apart more freely, new research finds.</description></item><item><title>The Brightest Meteor Shower of 2026 Will Peak Under a Moonless Sky—Here’s Where and When to See It - Travel + Leisure</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-brightest-meteor-shower-of-2026-will-peak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-brightest-meteor-shower-of-2026-will-peak/</guid><description>The year&amp;rsquo;s best and brightest meteor shower is the Perseids, peaking Aug. 12 and Aug. 13.</description></item><item><title>A Glowing Bar of Iron Is Haunting The Ring Nebula – And No One Knows Why - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-glowing-bar-of-iron-is-haunting-the-ring-ne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:01:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-glowing-bar-of-iron-is-haunting-the-ring-ne/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve known about the iconic Ring Nebula for nearly 250 years, but it&amp;rsquo;s only now that astronomers have found a giant mystery right at its core.</description></item><item><title>Amazon's internet-beaming satellites are bright enough to disrupt astronomical research, study finds - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/amazons-internet-beaming-satellites-are-brigh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/amazons-internet-beaming-satellites-are-brigh/</guid><description>Amazon Leo satellites are generally not visible to the naked eye but still could obstruct astronomical observations.</description></item><item><title>James Webb telescope previews the death of the sun in glorious new 'Eye of God' image - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-previews-the-death-of-th/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-previews-the-death-of-th/</guid><description>A spectacular new image from the James Webb Space Telescope reveals intricate structures inside the Helix Nebula, where a dying sunlike star is enriching the galaxy with the elements needed for life.</description></item><item><title>40 years after Challenger: Lingering guilt and lessons learned - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/40-years-after-challenger-lingering-guilt-and/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/40-years-after-challenger-lingering-guilt-and/</guid><description>Forty years after the Challenger disaster, NPR explores the engineers' last-minute efforts to stop the launch, their decades of guilt and the vital lessons that remain critical for NASA today.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to post-Darwinism: AI fires silver bullet for creating new life - The Times</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/welcome-to-post-darwinism-ai-fires-silver-bul/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/welcome-to-post-darwinism-ai-fires-silver-bul/</guid><description>In a breakthrough experiment, molecular biologists and tech entrepreneurs have teamed up to write the genetic code of a virus that destroys killer bacteria</description></item><item><title>Field Notes: Ancient Star Map, New Cat Cafe, San Jose’s Batman, and Disquiet in Suburbia - sfist.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/field-notes-ancient-star-map-new-cat-cafe-san/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 23:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/field-notes-ancient-star-map-new-cat-cafe-san/</guid><description>This week: Polynesian dance in Fremont, a new cat cafe in SF, a South Bay Batman, book clubs of the Peninsula, and California pollinators. Also, examining an ancient Greek star map using physics; supporting stroke survivors; and highlighting the unsettling pa…</description></item><item><title>Artemis II astronauts train in Iceland for lunar geology - WRAL</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-astronauts-train-in-iceland-for-lu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-ii-astronauts-train-in-iceland-for-lu/</guid><description>Lunar like landscapes in Iceland and Canada provide training grounds for astronauts.</description></item><item><title>A Biologist Explains Why Humans Have Chins. Hint: Anthropologists Still Can’t Agree On The Answer - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-biologist-explains-why-humans-have-chins-hi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-biologist-explains-why-humans-have-chins-hi/</guid><description>The chin is one of our most familiar features, yet scientists still debate why we evolved it. Here’s a breakdown of what we know about it so far.</description></item><item><title>A Hidden Warning Sign Discovered in The Gut May Increase Cancer Risk - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-hidden-warning-sign-discovered-in-the-gut-m/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:01:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-hidden-warning-sign-discovered-in-the-gut-m/</guid><description>As we get older, chemical marks on our DNA slowly shift.</description></item><item><title>Russian Scientists Build Plasma Engine That Could Reach Mars in 30 Days, Leaving Spacex's Starship Looking Obsolete - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-scientists-build-plasma-engine-that-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/russian-scientists-build-plasma-engine-that-c/</guid><description>Russia is quietly testing a new space engine that could change everything about how we reach Mars. Early results suggest a leap in speed and tech no one saw coming, and it’s not coming from NASA or SpaceX.</description></item><item><title>A Red and Green Sky Over Europe? NASA’s Photo From Space Shows the Full Spectacle - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-red-and-green-sky-over-europe-nasas-photo-f/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-red-and-green-sky-over-europe-nasas-photo-f/</guid><description>A mysterious red and green glow swept across Europe, captured from 262 miles up.</description></item><item><title>Vandenberg’s Next Mission: SpaceX Rocket Launch on Sunday Morning - noozhawk.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/vandenbergs-next-mission-spacex-rocket-launch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:05:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/vandenbergs-next-mission-spacex-rocket-launch/</guid><description>What: Falcon 9 rocket at Vandenberg Space Force Base in Santa Barbara County. When: Between 7:17 and 11:17 a.m. Sunday, according to SpaceX. If needed,</description></item><item><title>NASA Scientist Looked Into 50-Year-Old Moon Dirt, Here’s What He Found - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-scientist-looked-into-50-year-old-moon-d/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-scientist-looked-into-50-year-old-moon-d/</guid><description>What if the key to Earth’s oceans had been hidden on the Moon all along? A surprising lunar discovery is turning old theories upside down.</description></item><item><title>Mind Blowing James Webb Photo Shows Star Crumbling Into Dust - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mind-blowing-james-webb-photo-shows-star-crum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mind-blowing-james-webb-photo-shows-star-crum/</guid><description>A stunning new image taken with the James Webb Space Telescope provides a closeup look a dying star and its irradiated remains.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s New AI Just Spotted 7,000 Planet Candidates in a Single Sweep - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-ai-just-spotted-7000-planet-candida/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-ai-just-spotted-7000-planet-candida/</guid><description>A powerful new NASA AI is quietly scanning the skies, and what it’s finding is making scientists pause.</description></item><item><title>A new three-way single step rearrangement enables precise ring editing - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-three-way-single-step-rearrangement-ena/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:10:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-three-way-single-step-rearrangement-ena/</guid><description>A new three-way bond-breaking and making mechanism makes the synthesis of five-membered rings easier than before.</description></item><item><title>A year after undermining Bredt's rule, scientists make cage-shaped, double-bonded molecules that defy expectations - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-year-after-undermining-bredts-rule-scientis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-year-after-undermining-bredts-rule-scientis/</guid><description>Organic chemistry is packed with rules about structure and reactivity, especially when it comes to making and breaking chemical bonds. The rules governing how these bonds, which hold atoms together in molecules, form and the shapes they give molecules are oft…</description></item><item><title>Ancient Spanish trees reveal Mediterranean storms are intensifying - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ancient-spanish-trees-reveal-mediterranean-st/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ancient-spanish-trees-reveal-mediterranean-st/</guid><description>Ancient pine trees growing in the Iberian mountains of eastern Spain have quietly recorded more than five centuries of Mediterranean weather. Now, by reading the annual growth rings preserved in their wood, scientists have uncovered a striking message: today'…</description></item><item><title>480,000-year-old ax sharpener is the oldest known elephant bone tool ever discovered in Europe - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/480000-year-old-ax-sharpener-is-the-oldest-kn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/480000-year-old-ax-sharpener-is-the-oldest-kn/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;very rare&amp;rdquo; find provides an extraordinary glimpse into the ingenuity of early human relatives who lived around half a million years ago.</description></item><item><title>Saturday Citations: A weird, extinct life form; cholesterol hacking; interspecies prosociality of whales - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/saturday-citations-a-weird-extinct-life-form/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:40:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/saturday-citations-a-weird-extinct-life-form/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s Saturday! This week, in an eminently practical analysis of the Boltzmann brain conjecture, physicists put constraints on the idea that memories could arise from random fluctuations in entropy rather than reflecting the actual past of the universe—news yo…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Astonished by Glimpse of Huge, Ancient Ocean on Mars - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-astonished-by-glimpse-of-huge-anci/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-astonished-by-glimpse-of-huge-anci/</guid><description>Researchers used satellite data to calculate and simulate the sea level in a canyon, getting a glimpse of a huge ocean.</description></item><item><title>This Polish Astronaut Filmed the Earth and Moon from Space, It's the Most Beautiful Thing You’ll See Today - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-polish-astronaut-filmed-the-earth-and-mo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-polish-astronaut-filmed-the-earth-and-mo/</guid><description>A Polish astronaut spent 20 days aboard the ISS and captured stunning timelapse footage of Earth and the Moon.</description></item><item><title>AI can develop 'personality' spontaneously with minimal prompting, research shows. What does that mean for how we use it? - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-can-develop-personality-spontaneously-with/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-can-develop-personality-spontaneously-with/</guid><description>When large language models (LLMs) are allowed to interact without any preset goals, scientists found distinct personalities emerged by themselves.</description></item><item><title>January's full Wolf Moon leaps past the Eiffel Tower in stunning photo of Paris skyline - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/januarys-full-wolf-moon-leaps-past-the-eiffel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/januarys-full-wolf-moon-leaps-past-the-eiffel/</guid><description>The Wolf Moon is named for the hungry predators that sometimes can be heard howling in the winter month.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Perseverance Just Major Milestone, and It’s Not Done Yet - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-perseverance-just-major-milestone-and-i/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-perseverance-just-major-milestone-and-i/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance rover just passed the marathon mark on Mars, with new tests showing it&amp;rsquo;s ready for many more miles ahead.</description></item><item><title>Joshua trees are flowering in the Calif. desert. That’s bad news. - SFGATE</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/joshua-trees-are-flowering-in-the-calif-deser/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:10:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/joshua-trees-are-flowering-in-the-calif-deser/</guid><description>Joshua trees normally start flowering in February. This year, the bloom started in late October.</description></item><item><title>Stanford Scientists Reveal Oldest Map of the Night Sky, Previously Lost to Time - KQED</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-reveal-oldest-map-of-the/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-reveal-oldest-map-of-the/</guid><description>SLAC researchers used X-ray beams and the particle accelerator to recover the work of an ancient astronomer, who made the earliest known attempt to log the stars.</description></item><item><title>A Children’s Art Book Inspired by 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-childrens-art-book-inspired-by-3i-atlas-avi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:53:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-childrens-art-book-inspired-by-3i-atlas-avi/</guid><description>Before my morning jog at sunrise, I was delighted to receive the following email from a school teacher in Brazil:</description></item><item><title>The tiny world from 34 million years ago discovered under Antarctica: “It’s like a time capsule” - Diario AS</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-tiny-world-from-34-million-years-ago-disc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:34:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-tiny-world-from-34-million-years-ago-disc/</guid><description>Research allows for the development of strategies to combat climate change, taking into account the hidden landscapes discovered.</description></item><item><title>Why don't you usually see your nose? - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-dont-you-usually-see-your-nose-live-scien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-dont-you-usually-see-your-nose-live-scien/</guid><description>Our nose is right in front of us. So why don&amp;rsquo;t we normally notice it?</description></item><item><title>Lost Ocean That Vanished 100 Million Years Ago May Have Built Asia - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lost-ocean-that-vanished-100-million-years-ag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/lost-ocean-that-vanished-100-million-years-ag/</guid><description>New research reveals that Central Asia’s rugged terrain was molded by the vanished Tethys Ocean, millions of years before the Himalayas even rose.</description></item><item><title>Scientists May Have Just Discovered A New Life Form While Studying Fossils Of An Extinct, Fungus-Like Organism - All That's Interesting</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-have-just-discovered-a-new-lif/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:50:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-have-just-discovered-a-new-lif/</guid><description>A fossil analysis has revealed that Prototaxites, a prehistoric organism, was neither a plant nor a fungus and may have been a completely new life form.</description></item><item><title>NASA Sets Briefings for SpaceX Crew-12 Mission to Space Station - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-sets-briefings-for-spacex-crew-12-missio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:46:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-sets-briefings-for-spacex-crew-12-missio/</guid><description>Next, the crew of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-12 mission will participate in a virtual news conference from NASA Johnson crew quarters at 1 p.m., also on the agency’s</description></item><item><title>A mystery object is holding this 120 million-mile-wide cloud of vaporized metal together - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-mystery-object-is-holding-this-120-million/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-mystery-object-is-holding-this-120-million/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Stars like the sun don’t just stop shining for no reason.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Hubble Images of 3I/ATLAS During Its Rare Alignment with the Sun-Earth Axis on January 22, 2026 - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-images-of-3i-atlas-during-its-rare-ali/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:58:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-images-of-3i-atlas-during-its-rare-ali/</guid><description>Good news. The rare cosmic alignment between the interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS, the Earth and the Sun, was captured by the Hubble Space…</description></item><item><title>Scientists May Have Found a Blueprint to Revive Old Cells - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-have-found-a-blueprint-to-revi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:01:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-have-found-a-blueprint-to-revi/</guid><description>Many of the body&amp;rsquo;s processes slow down or falter as we get older, including tissue regeneration.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Next Moon Rocket Runs on Shuttle Engines—Here’s the Story Behind Each One - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-next-moon-rocket-runs-on-shuttle-engine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-next-moon-rocket-runs-on-shuttle-engine/</guid><description>SLS is ready to fly and will feature three shuttle-era engines that have already flown to space.</description></item><item><title>Archaeologists Found a 800,000-Year-Old Human Footprints Under UK Sand, And They're Perfectly Preserved - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/archaeologists-found-a-800000-year-old-human/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/archaeologists-found-a-800000-year-old-human/</guid><description>A stretch of British beach has revealed something extraordinary: the oldest human footprints ever found outside Africa.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers discover a gigantic, wobbling black hole jet that 'changes the way we think about the galaxy' - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-a-gigantic-wobbling-blac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:40:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-a-gigantic-wobbling-blac/</guid><description>Combining observations from several powerful telescopes, astronomers have detected a gargantuan, &amp;lsquo;wobbling&amp;rsquo; black hole outburst that&amp;rsquo;s as wide as an entire galaxy.</description></item><item><title>NASA Finds Lunar Regolith Limits Meteorites as Source of Earth’s Water - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-finds-lunar-regolith-limits-meteorites-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-finds-lunar-regolith-limits-meteorites-a/</guid><description>A new NASA study of its Apollo lunar soils clarifies the Moon’s record of meteorite impacts and timing of water delivery. These findings place upper bounds on</description></item><item><title>Experts Warn That There's Something Wrong With the Moon Rocket NASA Is About to Launch With Astronauts Aboard - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experts-warn-that-theres-something-wrong-with/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experts-warn-that-theres-something-wrong-with/</guid><description>Some experts aren&amp;rsquo;t convinced of NASA&amp;rsquo;s reassurances that the Orion spacecraft, which will house its Moon astronauts, is safe to use.</description></item><item><title>The Moment We've Been Waiting For: JWST Zooms Into The 'Eye of Sauron' - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-moment-weve-been-waiting-for-jwst-zooms-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-moment-weve-been-waiting-for-jwst-zooms-i/</guid><description>We know what will happen to the Sun and our Solar System because we can look outward into the galaxy and examine older Sun-like stars in their evolutionary end states.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Chandra Releases Deep Cut From Catalog of Cosmic Recordings - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-chandra-releases-deep-cut-from-catalog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:02:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-chandra-releases-deep-cut-from-catalog/</guid><description>Like a recording artist who has had a long career, NASA’s Chandra X-ray Observatory has a “back catalog” of cosmic recordings that is impossible to</description></item><item><title>Stunned boaters encounter massive orca pod at Channel Islands - Yahoo Lifestyle Canada</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stunned-boaters-encounter-massive-orca-pod-at/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:52:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stunned-boaters-encounter-massive-orca-pod-at/</guid><description>“We witnessed these apex predators combing the shoreline for their favorite pinniped prey, and they easily connected.&amp;quot;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover What Vanished from the Oceans After the Dinosaurs Died Out - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-what-vanished-from-the-oc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-what-vanished-from-the-oc/</guid><description>What really cooled the oceans after the dinosaurs? It wasn’t what you think.</description></item><item><title>Why Do All The Sun’s Planets Orbit In (Almost) The Same Plane? - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-do-all-the-suns-planets-orbit-in-almost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-do-all-the-suns-planets-orbit-in-almost/</guid><description>It appears the same is true for most other star systems, but the exceptions are very interesting.</description></item><item><title>Particle permutation task can be tackled by quantum but not classical computers, study finds - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/particle-permutation-task-can-be-tackled-by-q/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/particle-permutation-task-can-be-tackled-by-q/</guid><description>Quantum computers, systems that process information leveraging quantum mechanical effects, are expected to outperform classical computers on some complex tasks. Over the past few decades, many physicists and quantum engineers have tried to demonstrate the adv…</description></item><item><title>A colossal asteroid may have warped the moon from the inside out - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-colossal-asteroid-may-have-warped-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-colossal-asteroid-may-have-warped-the-moon/</guid><description>The findings are a big clue as to why the far and near hemispheres of the moon look so different.</description></item><item><title>Scientists observe a 300-million-year-old brain rhythm in several animal species - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-observe-a-300-million-year-old-bra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-observe-a-300-million-year-old-bra/</guid><description>Sleep is a universal biological state that allows all animals, from mammals to amphibians, fish and even insects, to restore their energy and consolidate knowledge that can contribute to their survival. Neuroscientists and zoologists have been investigating t…</description></item><item><title>Paleontologists Found a Clue Hidden in T. rex Bones for 66 Million Years and It Rewrites Everything They Thought They Knew - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/paleontologists-found-a-clue-hidden-in-t-rex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/paleontologists-found-a-clue-hidden-in-t-rex/</guid><description>The Tyrannosaurus rex, long thought to be a fast-growing apex predator, may have had a much slower path to adulthood than scientists once believed.</description></item><item><title>Monster Neutrino Could Be a Messenger of Ancient Black Holes - Quanta Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/monster-neutrino-could-be-a-messenger-of-anci/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/monster-neutrino-could-be-a-messenger-of-anci/</guid><description>Primordial black holes could rewrite our understanding of dark matter and the early universe. A record-breaking detection at the bottom of the Mediterranean Sea has some physicists wondering if we just spotted one.</description></item><item><title>Comet-3I/ATLAS Dramatically Changed Activity After Perihelion With Massive Release Of Organic Molecules - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-3i-atlas-dramatically-changed-activity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-3i-atlas-dramatically-changed-activity/</guid><description>Pretty much all of its different ices started sublimating even at that distance.</description></item><item><title>NASA is about to send people to the moon — in a spacecraft not everyone thinks is safe to fly - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-is-about-to-send-people-to-the-moon-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:44:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-is-about-to-send-people-to-the-moon-in/</guid><description>As the four-person crew of Artemis II prepares to launch on a historic mission around the moon as soon as February, some experts are worried about the spacecraft’s heat shield.</description></item><item><title>Chinese scientists turn carbon dioxide to starch with 10-fold productivity boost - South China Morning Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinese-scientists-turn-carbon-dioxide-to-sta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinese-scientists-turn-carbon-dioxide-to-sta/</guid><description>Feat seen to pave the way for industrial starch production without relying on water- and land-intensive corn.</description></item><item><title>After Years of Doubt, Physicists Just Confirmed That Time Mirrors Exist in a stunning breakthrough - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/after-years-of-doubt-physicists-just-confirme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/after-years-of-doubt-physicists-just-confirme/</guid><description>Scientists have achieved what once seemed impossible, sending signals backward through time using a groundbreaking electromagnetic experiment.</description></item><item><title>Have We Been Wrong About Language for 70 Years? New Study Challenges Long-Held Theory - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/have-we-been-wrong-about-language-for-70-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:52:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/have-we-been-wrong-about-language-for-70-year/</guid><description>A new study suggests that language may rely less on complex grammar than previously thought. Every time we speak, we’re improvising. “Humans possess a remarkable ability to talk about almost anything, sometimes putting words together into never-before-spoken …</description></item><item><title>Sinking ice on Jupiter's moon Europa may be slowly feeding its ocean the ingredients for life - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sinking-ice-on-jupiters-moon-europa-may-be-sl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sinking-ice-on-jupiters-moon-europa-may-be-sl/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Most excitingly, this new idea addresses one of the longstanding habitability problems on Europa and is a good sign for the prospects of extraterrestrial life in its ocean.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>NASA reveals huge clue about medical emergency behind historic ISS evacuation - UNILAD Tech</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-reveals-huge-clue-about-medical-emergenc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-reveals-huge-clue-about-medical-emergenc/</guid><description>NASA has revealed a major clue behind the medical emergency that forced an early evacuation of the ISS earlier this month.</description></item><item><title>Scientists just overturned a 100-year-old rule of chemistry, and the results are “impossible” - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-overturned-a-100-year-old-rul/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:35:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-overturned-a-100-year-old-rul/</guid><description>Chemists at UCLA are showing that some of organic chemistry’s most famous “rules” aren’t as unbreakable as once thought. By creating bizarre, cage-shaped molecules with warped double bonds—structures long considered impossible—the team is opening the door to …</description></item><item><title>Earthquake Sensors Detect Sonic Booms From Incoming Space Junk - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earthquake-sensors-detect-sonic-booms-from-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:38:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/earthquake-sensors-detect-sonic-booms-from-in/</guid><description>Scientists have just found a new way to track the uncontrolled reentry of falling space junk.</description></item><item><title>Scientific-Integrity Theft by Artificial Intelligence - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientific-integrity-theft-by-artificial-inte/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:16:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientific-integrity-theft-by-artificial-inte/</guid><description>The saga to preserve my scientific integrity against deception by artificial intelligence (AI) started two months ago and was described…</description></item><item><title>Scientists find a new Neanderthal population that stayed completely isolated for 50,000 years - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-a-new-neanderthal-population/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-find-a-new-neanderthal-population/</guid><description>Something like this would seem unimaginable for our Homo sapiens species.</description></item><item><title>A black hole 'feeding frenzy' could help explain a cosmic mystery uncovered by the James Webb Space Telescope - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-black-hole-feeding-frenzy-could-help-explai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-black-hole-feeding-frenzy-could-help-explai/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It is exciting to think that Little Red Dots may represent the first direct observational evidence of the birth of the most massive black holes in the universe.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Hubble uncovers the secret of blue straggler stars that defy aging - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-uncovers-the-secret-of-blue-straggler/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:53:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-uncovers-the-secret-of-blue-straggler/</guid><description>Some stars appear to defy time itself. Nestled within ancient star clusters, they shine bluer and brighter than their neighbors, looking far younger than their true age. Known as blue straggler stars, these stellar oddities have puzzled astronomers for more t…</description></item><item><title>The ISS Will Crash In 2030, and This Remote Spot On Earth Will Be Its Final Resting Place - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-iss-will-crash-in-2030-and-this-remote-sp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-iss-will-crash-in-2030-and-this-remote-sp/</guid><description>This desolate spot has been the final resting place for hundreds of decommissioned satellites and space stations over the last few decades.</description></item><item><title>Congress Saves NASA From Trump's Proposed Budget Cuts, Fully Funds Agency And Its Science Missions - Jalopnik</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/congress-saves-nasa-from-trumps-proposed-budg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/congress-saves-nasa-from-trumps-proposed-budg/</guid><description>Did we avert the crisis? Getting funding again is nice, but a lot of damage has already been done.</description></item><item><title>Like an Avalanche: Wild Video Captures the Violent Trigger Behind Solar Flares - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-an-avalanche-wild-video-captures-the-vio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:05:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-an-avalanche-wild-video-captures-the-vio/</guid><description>Solar Orbiter captured the most detailed view of a solar flare, observing the build-up of events that lead to the explosion.</description></item><item><title>Cancer might protect against Alzheimer’s — this protein helps explain why - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cancer-might-protect-against-alzheimers-thi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:50:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/cancer-might-protect-against-alzheimers-thi/</guid><description>A molecule produced by cancer cells can shield the brain from Alzheimer’s disease in mice.</description></item><item><title>Oregon State study reveals coastal marten's habitat and population insights - katu.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/oregon-state-study-reveals-coastal-martens-ha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/oregon-state-study-reveals-coastal-martens-ha/</guid><description>Oregon State University researchers from the Institute for Natural Resources led a three-month project in 2022 to collect information about the coastal marten.</description></item><item><title>Dark energy survey scientists release analysis of all six years of survey data - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dark-energy-survey-scientists-release-analysi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:03:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dark-energy-survey-scientists-release-analysi/</guid><description>The Dark Energy Survey Collaboration collected information on hundreds of millions of galaxies across the universe using the U.S. Department of Energy-fabricated Dark Energy Camera, mounted on the U.S. National Science Foundation Víctor M. Blanco 4-meter Tele…</description></item><item><title>Webb telescope reveals galaxy cluster's gravity warping light from distant galaxies - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/webb-telescope-reveals-galaxy-clusters-gravit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/webb-telescope-reveals-galaxy-clusters-gravit/</guid><description>This NASA/ESA/CSA James Webb Space Telescope Picture of the Month brings us a scene from the distant universe. Pictured here is the galaxy cluster MACS J1149.5+2223, or MACS J1149 for short, which is located about 5 billion light-years away in the constellati…</description></item><item><title>4 Exciting Space Missions Launch This Year Including NASA's Return to Moon, Japan's Jump to Mars - Good News Network</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4-exciting-space-missions-launch-this-year-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:30:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4-exciting-space-missions-launch-this-year-in/</guid><description>From a return of humans to lunar orbit, to Japan&amp;rsquo;s first crack at Mars, advanced space travel and exploration is set to continue in 2026.</description></item><item><title>Four-eyed Cambrian fish fossils hint at origins of vertebrate pineal complex - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-eyed-cambrian-fish-fossils-hint-at-origi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-eyed-cambrian-fish-fossils-hint-at-origi/</guid><description>New fossil evidence from China suggests that some of our vertebrate ancestors had four eyes. The study, published in Nature, takes a closer look at a structure found in multiple 518 million-year-old fossils, which appears to have the same features of other fo…</description></item><item><title>Life beyond Earth may be more common than thought - jpost.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/life-beyond-earth-may-be-more-common-than-tho/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:14:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/life-beyond-earth-may-be-more-common-than-tho/</guid><description>Published in the peer-reviewed The Astrophysical Journal, the research focuses on tidally locked planets, worlds that always show the same face to their star.</description></item><item><title>Physicist Believes He Has Located God. Unfortunately, They Are Around 439 Billion Trillion Kilometers Away - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicist-believes-he-has-located-god-unfortu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicist-believes-he-has-located-god-unfortu/</guid><description>Turns out God was hanging out in space all along.</description></item><item><title>Astronauts Give Crucial Clue About NASA’s Emergency Space Evacuation - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-give-crucial-clue-about-nasas-emer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:01:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-give-crucial-clue-about-nasas-emer/</guid><description>A NASA astronaut has revealed a tantalizing clue about what went down during the first medical evacuation in the space station&amp;rsquo;s history.</description></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope discovers what remains after two stars collide and explode as a red nova - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-discovers-what-rem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-discovers-what-rem/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Until now, it was unknown what type of star would remain after the merger.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Watch comet 3I/ATLAS race toward interstellar space in free livestream tonight - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-comet-3i-atlas-race-toward-interstellar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/watch-comet-3i-atlas-race-toward-interstellar/</guid><description>3I/ATLAS is the third interstellar visitor ever to visit the solar system having been formed around a distant star.</description></item><item><title>The Chinese satellites SpaceX says were on collision course with Starlink - South China Morning Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-chinese-satellites-spacex-says-were-on-co/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-chinese-satellites-spacex-says-were-on-co/</guid><description>As orbits become more crowded and littered with debris, the US operator is having to move its devices to dodge damage.</description></item><item><title>ISS astronaut spots Artemis 2 moon rocket on the launch pad from space (photo) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/iss-astronaut-spots-artemis-2-moon-rocket-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/iss-astronaut-spots-artemis-2-moon-rocket-on/</guid><description>A NASA astronaut on the ISS captured the Space Launch System rocket for Artemis 2, a mission that aims to bring four astronauts around the moon as soon as Feb. 6.</description></item><item><title>Skimming Satellites: On The Edge Of The Atmosphere - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/skimming-satellites-on-the-edge-of-the-atmosp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/skimming-satellites-on-the-edge-of-the-atmosp/</guid><description>There’s little about building spacecraft that anyone would call simple. But there’s at least one element of designing a vehicle that will operate outside the Earth’s atmosphere th…</description></item><item><title>Scientists solve 66 million-year-old mystery of how Earth's greenhouse age ended - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-solve-66-million-year-old-mystery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:54:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-solve-66-million-year-old-mystery/</guid><description>A 66 million-year-old mystery behind how our planet transformed from a tropical greenhouse to the ice-capped world of today has been unraveled by scientists. Their new study has revealed that Earth&amp;rsquo;s massive drop in temperature after the dinosaurs went extinc…</description></item><item><title>A Giant Star in Andromeda Just Vanished, Scientists Have No Idea Where It Went - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-giant-star-in-andromeda-just-vanished-scien/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-giant-star-in-andromeda-just-vanished-scien/</guid><description>A star 13 times the mass of the Sun just vanished. Here&amp;rsquo;s what could be hiding in its place.</description></item><item><title>NASA AI Model That Found 370 Exoplanets Now Digs Into TESS Data - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-ai-model-that-found-370-exoplanets-now-d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-ai-model-that-found-370-exoplanets-now-d/</guid><description>Trained on data from NASA&amp;rsquo;s exoplanet-hunting missions, the open-source ExoMiner++ deep learning model uses an advanced algorithm to validate new planets.</description></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope Captures the Stunning Demise of a Star in the Helix Nebula - The Debrief</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-captures-the-stunn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-space-telescope-captures-the-stunn/</guid><description>The James Webb Space Telescope has captured the clearest infrared observation of the Helix Nebula ever, displaying the death of a star.</description></item><item><title>Peptides, the Building Blocks of Life, Could Form on Interstellar Dust - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/peptides-the-building-blocks-of-life-could-fo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/peptides-the-building-blocks-of-life-could-fo/</guid><description>A new paper published in Nature Astronomy here, reports tantalizing results from laboratory experiments which demonstrate that the building…</description></item><item><title>Californians have been using far less water than suppliers estimated — what does this mean for the state? - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/californians-have-been-using-far-less-water-t/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:24:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/californians-have-been-using-far-less-water-t/</guid><description>Flawed assumptions about water demand mean suppliers in California overestimated future demand by an average of 74% over 20 years — positive news for the drought-embattled state.</description></item><item><title>Scientists may be approaching a 'fundamental breakthrough in cosmology and particle physics', if dark matter and 'ghost particles' can interact - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-be-approaching-a-fundamental-b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-may-be-approaching-a-fundamental-b/</guid><description>Astronomers found evidence that dark matter and neutrinos may interact, hinting at a &amp;ldquo;fundamental breakthrough&amp;rdquo; that challenges our understanding of how the universe evolved.</description></item><item><title>Wobbling exoplanet hints at a hidden exomoon so massive it could redefine the word 'moon' altogether - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/wobbling-exoplanet-hints-at-a-hidden-exomoon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/wobbling-exoplanet-hints-at-a-hidden-exomoon/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;In our solar system, the most massive moon is Ganymede, which is still extremely small compared to what we are inferring here.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>The First Great Forests Were Neither Fungus Nor Plant, But Lifeforms Without Living Descendants - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-first-great-forests-were-neither-fungus-n/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-first-great-forests-were-neither-fungus-n/</guid><description>Once these were the largest and most dominant living things on land, but their greatness did not ensure survival.</description></item><item><title>Scientist claims to have found the 'exact location of Heaven' with mind-blowing theory - UNILAD</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientist-claims-to-have-found-the-exact-loca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientist-claims-to-have-found-the-exact-loca/</guid><description>Former Harvard lecturer Dr Michael Guillen shared his in-depth theory about Heaven&amp;rsquo;s location and why we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been able to reach it</description></item><item><title>Night sky tonight: See the moon shine next to Saturn after sunset on Jan. 22 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/night-sky-tonight-see-the-moon-shine-next-to/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:23:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/night-sky-tonight-see-the-moon-shine-next-to/</guid><description>The night sky is full of wonder. Here&amp;rsquo;s what to look out for tonight.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious Giants Could Be a Whole New Kind of Life That No Longer Exists - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-giants-could-be-a-whole-new-kind-o/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 03:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-giants-could-be-a-whole-new-kind-o/</guid><description>Ever since their discovery more than 165 years ago, massive fossilized structures left by an organism known as Prototaxites have proven impossible to categorize.</description></item><item><title>'We can handle any kind of difficult situation': Crew-11 astronauts say 1st medical evacuation from ISS had a silver lining - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-can-handle-any-kind-of-difficult-situation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/we-can-handle-any-kind-of-difficult-situation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;This is actually a very, very good experience for the future of human spaceflight.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Life on Earth May Have Started With a Frozen Poison - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/life-on-earth-may-have-started-with-a-frozen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:48:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/life-on-earth-may-have-started-with-a-frozen/</guid><description>A chemical infamous for its toxicity may have played a surprising role in launching life on Earth.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis II Mission to Fly Legacy Keepsakes with Astronaut Crew - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-mission-to-fly-legacy-keepsa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:48:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-mission-to-fly-legacy-keepsa/</guid><description>As America approaches its 250th anniversary of declaring independence, NASA’s Artemis II mission will carry a host of mementos that reflect the nation’s long</description></item><item><title>Massive cloud with metallic winds discovered orbiting mystery object - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-cloud-with-metallic-winds-discovered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:17:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-cloud-with-metallic-winds-discovered/</guid><description>Sweeping winds of vaporized metals have been found in a massive cloud that dimmed the light of a star for nearly nine months. This discovery, made with the Gemini South telescope in Chile, one half of the International Gemini Observatory, offers a rare glimps…</description></item><item><title>'Eye of God' nebula looks like a cosmic lava lamp in new James Webb Space Telescope image - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eye-of-god-nebula-looks-like-a-cosmic-lava-la/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/eye-of-god-nebula-looks-like-a-cosmic-lava-la/</guid><description>It may be one of the most iconic sights in the night sky, but astronomers have never seen the Helix Nebula like this before.</description></item><item><title>Meet the marten: An updated look at a rare, adorable carnivore - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-marten-an-updated-look-at-a-rare-ado/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:52:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/meet-the-marten-an-updated-look-at-a-rare-ado/</guid><description>Oregon State University researchers have painted a clearer picture of the coastal marten, a secretive, ferret-sized forest carnivore renowned for its cuteness but nearly driven to extinction by human activity in the 20th century.</description></item><item><title>2.8 Days to Disaster: Low Earth Orbit Could Collapse Without Warning - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/28-days-to-disaster-low-earth-orbit-could-col/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/28-days-to-disaster-low-earth-orbit-could-col/</guid><description>A new analysis suggests modern satellite networks could suffer catastrophic collisions within days of losing control during a major solar storm. The phrase “House of Cards” is often associated today with a Netflix political drama, but its original meaning ref…</description></item><item><title>Astronauts say space station's ultrasound machine was critical during medical crisis - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-say-space-stations-ultrasound-mach/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:19:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-say-space-stations-ultrasound-mach/</guid><description>The astronauts evacuated last week from the International Space Station say a portable ultrasound machine came in “super handy” during the medical crisis&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Are your memories illusions? New study disentangles the Boltzmann brain paradox - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-your-memories-illusions-new-study-disenta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-your-memories-illusions-new-study-disenta/</guid><description>In a recent paper, SFI Professor David Wolpert, SFI Fractal Faculty member Carlo Rovelli, and physicist Jordan Scharnhorst examine a longstanding, paradoxical thought experiment in statistical physics and cosmology known as the &amp;ldquo;Boltzmann brain&amp;rdquo; hypothesis—th…</description></item><item><title>Glamping with the stars: These 7 retreats are perfect for night-sky watching - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/glamping-with-the-stars-these-7-retreats-are/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:19:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/glamping-with-the-stars-these-7-retreats-are/</guid><description>Bask in modern luxury while taking in the cosmos at these astrotourism escapes.</description></item><item><title>2026’s Meteor Showers Could Be the Best in Decades, Here’s When to Watch - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026s-meteor-showers-could-be-the-best-in-dec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/2026s-meteor-showers-could-be-the-best-in-dec/</guid><description>Don’t put your telescope away just yet. 2026 is bringing a lineup of meteor showers that might be worth losing a little sleep over.</description></item><item><title>Astronomy Days 2026 postponed - WRAL</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-days-2026-postponed-wral/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:37:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomy-days-2026-postponed-wral/</guid><description>Winter weather has forced the annual 2-day event which draws thousands to the North Carolina Museum of Natural Sciences to be rescheduled to January 31 and February 1.</description></item><item><title>Unified framework sorts spacetime fluctuations for quantum-gravity experiments - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unified-framework-sorts-spacetime-fluctuation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:22:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/unified-framework-sorts-spacetime-fluctuation/</guid><description>A team of researchers led by the University of Warwick has developed the first unified framework for detecting &amp;ldquo;spacetime fluctuations&amp;rdquo;—tiny, random distortions in the fabric of spacetime that appear in many attempts to unite quantum physics and gravity.</description></item><item><title>Massive black hole mystery unlocked by researchers - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-black-hole-mystery-unlocked-by-resear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:16:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/massive-black-hole-mystery-unlocked-by-resear/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s one of astronomy&amp;rsquo;s great mysteries: how did black holes get so big, so massive, so quickly. An answer to this cosmic conundrum has now been provided by researchers at Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Maynooth University (MU) and reported today in Nature Astronomy.</description></item><item><title>A Deep Sea Expedition Will Soon Confirm if 'Dark Oxygen' Exists - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-deep-sea-expedition-will-soon-confirm-if-da/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:03:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-deep-sea-expedition-will-soon-confirm-if-da/</guid><description>A team of scientists announced Tuesday they have developed new deep-sea landers specifically to test their contentious discovery that metallic rocks at the bottom of the ocean are producing &amp;ldquo;dark oxygen&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow’s “Full Moon” Phase of 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tomorrows-full-moon-phase-of-3i-atlas-avi-l/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:49:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/tomorrows-full-moon-phase-of-3i-atlas-avi-l/</guid><description>In a new paper that was just accepted for publication yesterday (and posted as a preprint here), I reported with Mauro Barbieri that…</description></item><item><title>Ageing promotes microglial accumulation of slow-degrading synaptic proteins - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ageing-promotes-microglial-accumulation-of-sl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ageing-promotes-microglial-accumulation-of-sl/</guid><description>Newly developed mouse models that enable cell-specific analyses of proteostasis dynamics across the lifespan of the mice reveal key aspects of neuronal proteostasis with ageing.</description></item><item><title>Gravity Solved? This Wild New Idea Might Explain the Entire Universe in One Shot - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravity-solved-this-wild-new-idea-might-expla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gravity-solved-this-wild-new-idea-might-expla/</guid><description>Scientists propose one idea to explain it all from gravity to dark matter.</description></item><item><title>Schrödinger’s cat just got bigger: quantum physicists create largest ever ‘superposition’ - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/schr%C3%B6dingers-cat-just-got-bigger-quantum-phys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/schr%C3%B6dingers-cat-just-got-bigger-quantum-phys/</guid><description>Record-breaking experiment shows that a cluster of thousands of atoms can act like a wave as well as a particle.</description></item><item><title>Temporal tissue dynamics from a spatial snapshot - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/temporal-tissue-dynamics-from-a-spatial-snaps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/temporal-tissue-dynamics-from-a-spatial-snaps/</guid><description>One-shot tissue dynamics reconstruction can infer changes in tissue composition over time, from single-time-point spatial proteomics of human cancers.</description></item><item><title>Symmetry, microscopy and spectroscopy signatures of altermagnetism - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/symmetry-microscopy-and-spectroscopy-signatur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:42:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/symmetry-microscopy-and-spectroscopy-signatur/</guid><description>The symmetry, microscopy and spectroscopy signatures of altermagnetism are reviewed, and compared with traditional ferromagnetism and Néel antiferromagnetism, and magnetic phases with symmetry-protected compensated non-collinear spin orders.</description></item><item><title>Enormous freshwater reservoir discovered off the East Coast may be 20,000 years old and big enough to supply NYC for 800 years - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/enormous-freshwater-reservoir-discovered-off/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:24:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/enormous-freshwater-reservoir-discovered-off/</guid><description>An expedition off the coast of Massachusetts has confirmed the existence of a freshwater reservoir beneath the seafloor. Now, scientists are starting to understand when and how it formed.</description></item><item><title>Four camera-type eyes in the earliest vertebrates from the Cambrian Period - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-camera-type-eyes-in-the-earliest-vertebr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/four-camera-type-eyes-in-the-earliest-vertebr/</guid><description>Early vertebrates, particularly myllokunmingids, possessed four camera-type eyes (a pair of lateral eyes and pineal and parapineal organs), which indicates that these structures functioned in image formation, in support of the hypothe…</description></item><item><title>Afar fossil shows broad distribution and versatility of Paranthropus - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/afar-fossil-shows-broad-distribution-and-vers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:08:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/afar-fossil-shows-broad-distribution-and-vers/</guid><description>With its attribution to Paranthropus, a 2.6-million-year-old partial mandible expands the range of the genus into the Afar region of Ethiopia and adds to our understanding of hominin evolution in eastern Africa.</description></item><item><title>Bird retinas function without oxygen—solving a centuries-old biological mystery - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bird-retinas-function-without-oxygensolving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/bird-retinas-function-without-oxygensolving/</guid><description>Neural tissue normally dies quickly without oxygen. Yet bird retinas—among the most energy-demanding tissues in the animal kingdom—function permanently without it. This may be relevant in future treatment of stroke patients.</description></item><item><title>NASA Webb Finds Young Sun-Like Star Forging, Spewing Common Crystals - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-finds-young-sun-like-star-forging-s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-webb-finds-young-sun-like-star-forging-s/</guid><description>Astronomers have long sought evidence to explain why comets at the outskirts of our own solar system contain crystalline silicates, since crystals require</description></item><item><title>How Animals Build a Sense of Direction - Quanta Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-animals-build-a-sense-of-direction-quanta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-animals-build-a-sense-of-direction-quanta/</guid><description>Researchers documented the activity of neurons that shape directional navigation as bats explored a remote island off the coast of Tanzania.</description></item><item><title>These Snapshots of the Moment a Star Exploded Will Fill You With Cosmic Dread - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/these-snapshots-of-the-moment-a-star-exploded/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:11:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/these-snapshots-of-the-moment-a-star-exploded/</guid><description>A pair of incredible images show the very moment that two different stars exploded, an incredible display that&amp;rsquo;s melting our minds.</description></item><item><title>NASA to end support for planetary science groups - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-to-end-support-for-planetary-science-gro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:24:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-to-end-support-for-planetary-science-gro/</guid><description>NASA is ending financial support for several planetary science groups as part of a broader drawdown of the agency’s advisory structure.</description></item><item><title>This Everyday Speech Pattern Is a Clear Sign Your Brain Is Starting to Shut Down - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-everyday-speech-pattern-is-a-clear-sign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-everyday-speech-pattern-is-a-clear-sign/</guid><description>A hidden speech pattern may reveal early brain decline, years before memory loss. Scientists have uncovered a surprising verbal clue linked to cognitive aging, and it’s something most people ignore every day.</description></item><item><title>A Cycle Deep Within Earth's Crust May Affect Climate More Than We Thought - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-cycle-deep-within-earths-crust-may-affect-c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:01:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-cycle-deep-within-earths-crust-may-affect-c/</guid><description>Our planet has experienced dramatic climate shifts throughout its history, oscillating between freezing &amp;ldquo;icehouse&amp;rdquo; periods and warm &amp;ldquo;greenhouse&amp;rdquo; states.</description></item><item><title>The Strength and Fitness Benchmarks Men Should be Hitting in Their 50s - Men's Health</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-strength-and-fitness-benchmarks-men-shoul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-strength-and-fitness-benchmarks-men-shoul/</guid><description>These strength and fitness benchmarks outline what healthy men in their 50s can aim for across strength, endurance, power and cardio.</description></item><item><title>Solar flares triggered by cascading magnetic avalanches, new observations reveal - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/solar-flares-triggered-by-cascading-magnetic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/solar-flares-triggered-by-cascading-magnetic/</guid><description>Just as avalanches on snowy mountains start with the movement of a small quantity of snow, the ESA-led Solar Orbiter spacecraft has discovered that a solar flare is triggered by initially weak disturbances that quickly become more violent. This rapidly evolvi…</description></item><item><title>Stanford scientists found a way to regrow cartilage and stop arthritis - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-found-a-way-to-regrow-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:56:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/stanford-scientists-found-a-way-to-regrow-car/</guid><description>Scientists at Stanford Medicine have discovered a treatment that can reverse cartilage loss in aging joints and even prevent arthritis after knee injuries. By blocking a protein linked to aging, the therapy restored healthy, shock-absorbing cartilage in old m…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover a New Quantum State of Matter Once Considered Impossible - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-new-quantum-state-of-ma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:20:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-new-quantum-state-of-ma/</guid><description>A quantum state of matter has appeared in a material where physicists thought it would be impossible, forcing a rethink on the conditions that govern the behaviors of electrons in certain materials.</description></item><item><title>Both astronauts that flew on Boeing’s troubled Starliner mission are now retired - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/both-astronauts-that-flew-on-boeings-troubled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/both-astronauts-that-flew-on-boeings-troubled/</guid><description>Veteran NASA astronaut Suni Williams announced her retirement Tuesday. Her extended mission to orbit due to the troubled Boeing Starliner test flight was her final foray.</description></item><item><title>AI-driven ultrafast spectrometer-on-a-chip advances real-time sensing - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-driven-ultrafast-spectrometer-on-a-chip-ad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/ai-driven-ultrafast-spectrometer-on-a-chip-ad/</guid><description>For decades, the ability to visualize the chemical composition of materials, whether for diagnosing a disease, assessing food quality, or analyzing pollution, depended on large, expensive laboratory instruments called spectrometers. These devices work by taki…</description></item><item><title>Interstellar Hitchhiking on Objects Like 3I/ATLAS - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/interstellar-hitchhiking-on-objects-like-3i-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:24:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/interstellar-hitchhiking-on-objects-like-3i-a/</guid><description>For a technological civilization born on a planet as massive as Earth, the easiest way to engage in high-speed interstellar travel might be…</description></item><item><title>Mysterious polar weather on Jupiter and Saturn could be key to understanding their insides - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-polar-weather-on-jupiter-and-satur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-polar-weather-on-jupiter-and-satur/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone&amp;rsquo;s made this connection between the surface fluid pattern and the interior properties of these planets.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>'Like watching a cosmic volcano erupt': Scientists see monster black hole 'reborn' after 100 million years - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-watching-a-cosmic-volcano-erupt-scientis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/like-watching-a-cosmic-volcano-erupt-scientis/</guid><description>Scientists saw an inactive black hole &amp;lsquo;reawaken&amp;rsquo; from a 100-million-year nap with fire and fury.</description></item><item><title>New NASA Artemis Payloads To Study Moon’s Terrain, Radiation, History - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-nasa-artemis-payloads-to-study-moons-terr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:23:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-nasa-artemis-payloads-to-study-moons-terr/</guid><description>NASA announced Tuesday the selection of three new science investigations that will strengthen humanity’s understanding and exploration of the Moon. As part of</description></item><item><title>Complex building blocks of life form spontaneously in space, research reveals - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/complex-building-blocks-of-life-form-spontane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/complex-building-blocks-of-life-form-spontane/</guid><description>Challenging long-held assumptions, Aarhus University researchers have demonstrated that the protein building blocks essential for life as we know it can form readily in space. This discovery, appearing in Nature Astronomy, significantly raises the statistical…</description></item><item><title>A twitch in time? Quantum collapse models hint at tiny time fluctuations - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-twitch-in-time-quantum-collapse-models-hint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-twitch-in-time-quantum-collapse-models-hint/</guid><description>Quantum mechanics is rich with paradoxes and contradictions. It describes a microscopic world in which particles exist in a superposition of states—being in multiple places and configurations all at once, defined mathematically by what physicists call a &amp;ldquo;wave…</description></item><item><title>4,000 Space Mirrors Could Soon Light Up Your Night, and They’re Coming in 2026 - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4000-space-mirrors-could-soon-light-up-your-n/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/4000-space-mirrors-could-soon-light-up-your-n/</guid><description>A bold new startup plans to launch mirrors into orbit to reflect sunlight onto Earth at night, a move that could outshine the Moon.</description></item><item><title>How to make a super-Earth: The universe's most common planets are whittled down by stellar radiation - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-make-a-super-earth-the-universes-most/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-make-a-super-earth-the-universes-most/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s so exciting is that we&amp;rsquo;re seeing a preview of what will become a very normal planetary system.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Adam Hagen - wctrib.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/adam-hagen-wctribcom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/adam-hagen-wctribcom/</guid><description>Adam Benjamin Hagen, 44, of rural Benton County passed at home Saturday, January 17, 2026 after a valiant battle with cancer.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers Discover Gigantic Iron Bar Running Through Ring Nebula - PetaPixel</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-gigantic-iron-bar-runnin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-discover-gigantic-iron-bar-runnin/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;We definitely need to know more.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>This Black Hole Jet Is So Powerful, It’s Shutting Down an Entire Galaxy - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-black-hole-jet-is-so-powerful-its-shutti/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-black-hole-jet-is-so-powerful-its-shutti/</guid><description>This black hole isn’t just pulling stuff in, it’s blasting material out. And what that means for its galaxy is more serious than anyone expected.</description></item><item><title>What Isaac Roberts Saw Without A Space Telescope - Hackaday</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-isaac-roberts-saw-without-a-space-telesc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-isaac-roberts-saw-without-a-space-telesc/</guid><description>Space telescopes are all the rage, and rightfully so. The images they take are spectacular, and they’ve greatly increased what we know about the universe. Surely, any picture taken of, say, t…</description></item><item><title>NASA Unlocks Golden Age of Innovation, Exploration in Trump’s First Year - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-unlocks-golden-age-of-innovation-explora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-unlocks-golden-age-of-innovation-explora/</guid><description>One year into President Donald J. Trump’s second term, NASA is delivering measurable progress across human spaceflight, science, aeronautics, and cutting-edge</description></item><item><title>While Cleaning Up Flood Damage, Texas Volunteers Saw 15 Dinosaur Tracks Emerge From the Ground - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/while-cleaning-up-flood-damage-texas-voluntee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/while-cleaning-up-flood-damage-texas-voluntee/</guid><description>They thought the area was clear, until giant claw tracks surfaced after the floods.</description></item><item><title>Quote of the Day by Stephen Hawking: 'We are just an advanced breed of monkeys on a minor planet of a very average star. But...' - 19FortyFive</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quote-of-the-day-by-stephen-hawking-we-are-ju/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:08:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quote-of-the-day-by-stephen-hawking-we-are-ju/</guid><description>Stephen Hawking’s 1988 “advanced monkeys” quote argues that understanding the universe—and exploring space—may be humanity’s best path to endure.</description></item><item><title>Astronauts Helicoptered to Hospital After Mystery Evacuation From Space Station - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-helicoptered-to-hospital-after-mys/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:01:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-helicoptered-to-hospital-after-mys/</guid><description>Four astronauts were airlifted to a hospital in San Diego via helicopter after the International Space Station&amp;rsquo;s first medical evacuation.</description></item><item><title>A New Theory Says Gravity May Come From Entropy—Which Could Lead to a Unified Theory of Physics - Yahoo News Canada</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-theory-says-gravity-may-come-from-entro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-theory-says-gravity-may-come-from-entro/</guid><description>A new theory suggests gravity could possibly be the result of entropy—which would mean everything in the universe would fall apart if it all remained&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Discovered How Giant Dinosaurs Grew Necks So Massive They Changed the Way They Walked - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-discovered-how-giant-dinosaur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-discovered-how-giant-dinosaur/</guid><description>What made these dinosaurs so huge? Scientists point to one surprising feature: the neck.</description></item><item><title>Invisible companion leaves evidence trail around supergiant star Betelgeuse - CNN</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/invisible-companion-leaves-evidence-trail-aro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/invisible-companion-leaves-evidence-trail-aro/</guid><description>Optical proof of a tiny companion orbiting supergiant star Betelgeuse is hard to come by. Hubble just spotted new evidence.</description></item><item><title>Are We Trapped in a Cosmic Illusion? Scientists Say the Universe Might Be a Hall of Mirrors - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-we-trapped-in-a-cosmic-illusion-scientist/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-we-trapped-in-a-cosmic-illusion-scientist/</guid><description>Could the shape of the universe be tricking us? A new study suggests the universe could be shaped in a way that creates optical illusions on a cosmic scale.</description></item><item><title>Mars orbiter sees odd etchings in the sand photo of the day for Jan. 20, 2025 - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-orbiter-sees-odd-etchings-in-the-sand-ph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-orbiter-sees-odd-etchings-in-the-sand-ph/</guid><description>Even though the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is thin, wind is still one of Mars' most relentless sculptors.</description></item><item><title>Astronomers Caught a Record-Breaking Stellar Explosion on Camera and It Looks Nothing Like They Expected - ZME Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-caught-a-record-breaking-stellar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:46:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronomers-caught-a-record-breaking-stellar/</guid><description>High-resolution images of exploding stars challenge our understanding of cosmic death and shock physics</description></item><item><title>Comet Wierzchos buzzes the sun later today: But can you see it? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-wierzchos-buzzes-the-sun-later-today-bu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/comet-wierzchos-buzzes-the-sun-later-today-bu/</guid><description>C/2024 E1 (Wierzchos) brightened significantly ahead of its close approach to the sun.</description></item><item><title>New quantum boundary discovered: Spin size determines how the Kondo effect behaves - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-quantum-boundary-discovered-spin-size-det/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-quantum-boundary-discovered-spin-size-det/</guid><description>Collective behavior is an unusual phenomenon in condensed-matter physics. When quantum spins interact together as a system, they produce unique effects not seen in individual particles. Understanding how quantum spins interact to produce this behavior is cent…</description></item><item><title>Redefining Risk: Lessons from Medicine, Money, and Spaceflight - The White Coat Investor</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/redefining-risk-lessons-from-medicine-money-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/redefining-risk-lessons-from-medicine-money-a/</guid><description>Achieving my lifelong goal of going to space was worth the 40 years of work it took to get there. This is how I made it happen.</description></item><item><title>North America’s Greenhouse Hub - NASA Science (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/north-americas-greenhouse-hub-nasa-science-g/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/north-americas-greenhouse-hub-nasa-science-g/</guid><description>The expansion of greenhouses in southern Ontario is changing the appearance of the land surface—and the night sky.</description></item><item><title>World’s slowest science lab experiment is still going and about to turn 100 years old - supercarblondie.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/worlds-slowest-science-lab-experiment-is-stil/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/worlds-slowest-science-lab-experiment-is-stil/</guid><description>The world’s longest continuously running lab experiment has been live for almost 100 years, and it’s not set to end anytime soon</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis II reaches the launch pad and the countdown to the Moon begins - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-reaches-the-launch-pad-and-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-artemis-ii-reaches-the-launch-pad-and-t/</guid><description>NASA’s Artemis II rocket has reached its launch pad after a painstaking overnight crawl across Kennedy Space Center. Engineers are now preparing for crucial fueling and countdown tests ahead of the first crewed Artemis mission. The mission will send four astr…</description></item><item><title>Scripps Memorial Hospital La Jolla received astronauts after splashdown - San Diego Union-Tribune</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scripps-memorial-hospital-la-jolla-received-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:24:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scripps-memorial-hospital-la-jolla-received-a/</guid><description>With its helipad capable of receiving heavy military helicopters, the medical center received the four astronauts aboard the SpaceX capsule that splashed down off the San Diego coast on Thursday</description></item><item><title>The way Earth’s surface moves has a bigger impact on shifting the climate than we knew - The Conversation</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-way-earths-surface-moves-has-a-bigger-imp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-way-earths-surface-moves-has-a-bigger-imp/</guid><description>Earth has experienced many icehouse and greenhouse climates. A new study shows how they connect to plate tectonics.</description></item><item><title>Damaged DSN antenna out of service until May - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/damaged-dsn-antenna-out-of-service-until-may/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/damaged-dsn-antenna-out-of-service-until-may/</guid><description>A key antenna in NASA’s Deep Space Network (DSN) that was damaged last fall is expected to remain offline until May.</description></item><item><title>New Brain Drugs Mimic Psychedelics Without the Hallucinations - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-brain-drugs-mimic-psychedelics-without-th/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-brain-drugs-mimic-psychedelics-without-th/</guid><description>Scientists at UC Davis created a new class of serotonin-targeting molecules using a light-driven chemical method. UC Davis scientists have created a light-based technique that converts amino acids — the building blocks of proteins — into new molecules with ps…</description></item><item><title>An armada of 6,500 Elite Dangerous players just embarked on a three-month expedition to explore the Milky Way, and there's still time to join them - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/an-armada-of-6500-elite-dangerous-players-jus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/an-armada-of-6500-elite-dangerous-players-jus/</guid><description>To explore strange new worlds; to seek out new life and new civilizations; to boldly go where no one has gone before!</description></item><item><title>Polar Storms on Jupiter And Saturn Reveal Deep Atmospheric Differences - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/polar-storms-on-jupiter-and-saturn-reveal-dee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/polar-storms-on-jupiter-and-saturn-reveal-dee/</guid><description>The two largest planets in the Solar System – Jupiter and Saturn – have a lot in common.</description></item><item><title>Physicists uncover hidden magnetic order in the mysterious pseudogap phase - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-uncover-hidden-magnetic-order-in-t/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/physicists-uncover-hidden-magnetic-order-in-t/</guid><description>Physicists have uncovered a link between magnetism and a mysterious phase of matter called the pseudogap, which appears in certain quantum materials just above the temperature at which they become superconducting. The findings could help researchers design ne…</description></item><item><title>Golden Gate method enables fully-synthetic engineering of therapeutically relevant bacteriophages - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/golden-gate-method-enables-fully-synthetic-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/golden-gate-method-enables-fully-synthetic-en/</guid><description>Bacteriophages have been used therapeutically to treat infectious bacterial diseases for over a century. As antibiotic-resistant infections increasingly threaten public health, interest in bacteriophages as therapeutics has seen a resurgence. However, the fie…</description></item><item><title>What deep sea mud is revealing about giant earthquakes along the Pacific Coast - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-deep-sea-mud-is-revealing-about-giant-ea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:44:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-deep-sea-mud-is-revealing-about-giant-ea/</guid><description>Marine turbidites are layers of mud and sand deposited on the deep ocean floor by massive underwater landslides and are often used as a historical record for reconstructing earthquake histories.</description></item><item><title>What the first medical evacuation from the International Space Station tells us about healthcare in space - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-the-first-medical-evacuation-from-the-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-the-first-medical-evacuation-from-the-in/</guid><description>The evacuation was the first such event in the history of the ISS.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Found Space Signals Inside Beach Sand, Here's What They Reveal About Earth's Ancient - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-space-signals-inside-beach-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-found-space-signals-inside-beach-s/</guid><description>Encased within each grain lies a microscopic archive of its exposure to the open sky, a new way of reading the Earth’s surface history.</description></item><item><title>Dinosaurs Were Thriving Until The Very End, New Study Finds - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dinosaurs-were-thriving-until-the-very-end-ne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dinosaurs-were-thriving-until-the-very-end-ne/</guid><description>New research reveals that dinosaurs were thriving across diverse ecosystems until a sudden asteroid impact ended their reign 66 million years ago.</description></item><item><title>First direct evidence of Migdal effect opens new path for dark matter search - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/first-direct-evidence-of-migdal-effect-opens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/first-direct-evidence-of-migdal-effect-opens/</guid><description>In a landmark discovery that bridges nearly a century of theoretical physics, a Chinese research team has successfully captured the first direct evidence of the Migdal effect, a breakthrough with profound implications for probing dark matter—the invisible sub…</description></item><item><title>How to find 4 legendary spacecraft in January's night sky - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-find-4-legendary-spacecraft-in-january/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-to-find-4-legendary-spacecraft-in-january/</guid><description>Along with bonus stargazing targets!</description></item><item><title>Some moral acts matter more than others, study shows - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/some-moral-acts-matter-more-than-others-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:54:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/some-moral-acts-matter-more-than-others-study/</guid><description>Every day, we quietly judge the people around us. Did that co-worker split the credit fairly? Did a neighbor return a lost package? Did someone cut in line or respect the rules?</description></item><item><title>NASA Found a Planet That Rains Glass at 5,400 MPH, And It Looks Like Earth - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-found-a-planet-that-rains-glass-at-5400/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-found-a-planet-that-rains-glass-at-5400/</guid><description>This close orbit subjects the planet to continuous stellar bombardment, turning its atmosphere into a furnace of volatile activity.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Say a Major Quantum Computing Breakthrough Was Not What It Seemed - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-say-a-major-quantum-computing-brea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-say-a-major-quantum-computing-brea/</guid><description>Replication is a cornerstone of science, yet even in the natural sciences, attempts to reproduce results do not always succeed. Quantum computing promises machines that can solve certain problems far beyond today’s computers, but it faces a stubborn obstacle:…</description></item><item><title>Scientists Rebuild Face Of Ancient American After 8,500 Years: The Results Are Jaw-Dropping - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-rebuild-face-of-ancient-american-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-rebuild-face-of-ancient-american-a/</guid><description>A new facial reconstruction of the Kennewick Man reveals the face of one of America’s oldest humans, after 8,500 years buried in mystery.</description></item><item><title>Beta-decay half-life measurements reveal evolution of nuclear shell structure - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beta-decay-half-life-measurements-reveal-evol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/beta-decay-half-life-measurements-reveal-evol/</guid><description>An international team of researchers has systematically measured the β-decay half-lives of 40 nuclei near calcium-54, providing key experimental data for understanding the structure of extremely neutron-rich nuclei.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Found a 97-Million-Year Magnetic Fossil, And It Points to a Lost Ocean Creature - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-found-a-97-million-year-magne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-found-a-97-million-year-magne/</guid><description>A strange set of magnetic fossils from the age of dinosaurs is making scientists wonder: did an extinct marine animal once navigate using Earth’s magnetic field?</description></item><item><title>Reborn black hole seen erupting across 1 million light-years of space like a cosmic volcano - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reborn-black-hole-seen-erupting-across-1-mill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/reborn-black-hole-seen-erupting-across-1-mill/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like watching a cosmic volcano erupt again after ages of calm — except this one is big enough to carve out structures stretching nearly a million light-years across space.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Gold No Longer Inert: Scientists Created a Novel Gold Hydride Under Planetary Core Conditions - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-no-longer-inert-scientists-created-a-nov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/gold-no-longer-inert-scientists-created-a-nov/</guid><description>Gold, long considered untouchable, has revealed a hidden side in a lab experiment that could upend chemistry, energy science, and everything we thought we knew about the periodic table.</description></item><item><title>China previews how powerful its new Xuntian space telescope will be ahead of 2027 launch (video) - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/china-previews-how-powerful-its-new-xuntian-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/china-previews-how-powerful-its-new-xuntian-s/</guid><description>Mock observations test the performance of the Chinese Space Station Telescope as the 2-meter-class observatory moves closer to launch.</description></item><item><title>Are the Three Mini-Jets, Coming Out of 3I/ATLAS at 120 Degree Separation, a Technological Signature? - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-the-three-mini-jets-coming-out-of-3i-atla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/are-the-three-mini-jets-coming-out-of-3i-atla/</guid><description>Shortly after its perihelion passage on October 29, 2025, the interstellar object 3I/ATLAS was imaged by amateur astronomers to have…</description></item><item><title>Observing the positronium beam as a quantum matter wave for the first time - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/observing-the-positronium-beam-as-a-quantum-m/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/observing-the-positronium-beam-as-a-quantum-m/</guid><description>One of the discoveries that fundamentally distinguished the emerging field of quantum physics from classical physics was the observation that matter behaves differently at the smallest scales. A key finding was wave-particle duality, the revelation that parti…</description></item><item><title>Was the Red Planet once blue? New evidence points to an ancient ocean on Mars - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/was-the-red-planet-once-blue-new-evidence-poi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/was-the-red-planet-once-blue-new-evidence-poi/</guid><description>Ancient shoreline features hint that water on Mars once formed a vast ocean.</description></item><item><title>NASA’s Giant Balloons Over Antarctica Just Made A Breakthrough In The Hunt For Dark Matter - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-giant-balloons-over-antarctica-just-mad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-giant-balloons-over-antarctica-just-mad/</guid><description>NASA’s latest Antarctic balloon missions uncover new clues about dark matter and cosmic particles, setting new records in near-space exploration.</description></item><item><title>Outer Space Is a Viscous Fluid, New Paper Claims - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/outer-space-is-a-viscous-fluid-new-paper-clai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/outer-space-is-a-viscous-fluid-new-paper-clai/</guid><description>A paper proposes that outer space acts like viscous fluid, which if true could explain discrepancies in observations of the universe.</description></item><item><title>Remnants of spills on Renaissance-era textbook reveal recipes for 'curing' ailments with lizard heads and human feces - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/remnants-of-spills-on-renaissance-era-textboo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/remnants-of-spills-on-renaissance-era-textboo/</guid><description>A novel biochemical analysis of a Renaissance medical text has successfully recovered centuries-old proteins that might be from lizards and hippos.</description></item><item><title>Sun erupts with powerful X-class flare as huge CME races toward Earth, impact possible within 24 hours - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-erupts-with-powerful-x-class-flare-as-hug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/sun-erupts-with-powerful-x-class-flare-as-hug/</guid><description>Aurora alert! The colossal solar storm could impact and trigger impressive northern lights.</description></item><item><title>Nebra Sky Disc: The world's oldest depiction of astronomical phenomena — and it may depict the Pleiades - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nebra-sky-disc-the-worlds-oldest-depiction-of/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nebra-sky-disc-the-worlds-oldest-depiction-of/</guid><description>The unique bronze-and-gold Nebra Sky Disc appears to represent what the night sky looked like more than three millennia ago.</description></item><item><title>Quantum 'alchemy' made feasible with excitons - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-alchemy-made-feasible-with-excitons-p/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/quantum-alchemy-made-feasible-with-excitons-p/</guid><description>What if you could create new materials just by shining a light at them? To most, this sounds like science fiction or alchemy, but to physicists investigating the burgeoning field of Floquet engineering, this is the goal. With a periodic drive, like light, sci…</description></item><item><title>James Webb telescope reveals sharpest-ever look at the edge of a black hole — and it could solve a major galactic mystery - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-reveals-sharpest-ever-lo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-reveals-sharpest-ever-lo/</guid><description>The James Webb Space Telescope snapped its sharpest image of the area around a black hole, solving a long-standing galactic mystery.</description></item><item><title>Viruses that evolved on the space station and were sent back to Earth were more effective at killing bacteria - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/viruses-that-evolved-on-the-space-station-and/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/viruses-that-evolved-on-the-space-station-and/</guid><description>Near-weightless conditions can mutate genes and alter the physical structures of bacteria and phages, disrupting their normal interactions in ways that could help us treat drug-resistant infections.</description></item><item><title>Experiments bring Enceladus' subsurface ocean into the lab - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experiments-bring-enceladus-subsurface-ocean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/experiments-bring-enceladus-subsurface-ocean/</guid><description>Through new experiments, researchers in Japan and Germany have recreated the chemical conditions found in the subsurface ocean of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon, Enceladus. Published in Icarus, the results show that these conditions can readily produce many of the organic com…</description></item><item><title>Frozen Chemical Once Feared by Scientists May Have Ignited Life on Earth - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-chemical-once-feared-by-scientists-may/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/frozen-chemical-once-feared-by-scientists-may/</guid><description>A frozen chemical thought to be deadly is now revealing unexpected powers, scientists didn’t see this one coming.</description></item><item><title>New Fossil Discovery Could Kick Lucy Out of the Human Family Tree - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fossil-discovery-could-kick-lucy-out-of-t/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-fossil-discovery-could-kick-lucy-out-of-t/</guid><description>Scientists have found fossil bones that could dethrone lucy as our most famous ancestor.</description></item><item><title>Northern Lights Forecast: Aurora Could Be Visible From These 10 States - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-aurora-could-be-visi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:03:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-aurora-could-be-visi/</guid><description>The aurora borealis could be visible from states along the U.S.-Canadian border.</description></item><item><title>What is below Earth, since space is present in every direction? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-below-earth-since-space-is-present-in/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/what-is-below-earth-since-space-is-present-in/</guid><description>Which way is ‘down’ has a different answer depending on where you are on Earth, in the solar system, in our galaxy and beyond.</description></item><item><title>NASA launches Pandora telescope, taking JWST's search for habitable worlds to a new level - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-launches-pandora-telescope-taking-jwsts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-launches-pandora-telescope-taking-jwsts/</guid><description>The findings from Pandora will complement data from the James Webb Space Telescope to give astronomers more insight into stars and planets outside our solar system.</description></item><item><title>New moon of January 2026 brings prime views of Jupiter, Saturn and winter stars tonight - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-moon-of-january-2026-brings-prime-views-o/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-moon-of-january-2026-brings-prime-views-o/</guid><description>With the moon out of the way on Jan. 18, bright Jupiter and Saturn become stand-outs in the January night sky.</description></item><item><title>Mars: Scientists Have Figured Out How Blue The Red Planet Used to Be - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-scientists-have-figured-out-how-blue-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:02:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-scientists-have-figured-out-how-blue-the/</guid><description>Mars is absolutely dripping with evidence that the red planet was once a striking blue, complete with glistening lakes, snaking rivers, and vast oceans.</description></item><item><title>Hubble Telescope watches star blast out jet of hot gas 32 light-years long - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-telescope-watches-star-blast-out-jet-o/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/hubble-telescope-watches-star-blast-out-jet-o/</guid><description>The protostar is launching the longest outburst ever seen at 32 light-years long.</description></item><item><title>James Webb telescope spots 'failed stars' in a breathtaking cluster near Earth — Space photo of the week - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-spots-failed-stars-in-a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/james-webb-telescope-spots-failed-stars-in-a/</guid><description>The James Webb Space Telescope captured a colorful portrait of a nearby stellar cradle, revealing a wealth of insights about countless stars.</description></item><item><title>China's Shenzhou-21 crew continues with science experiments, life in orbit - news.cgtn.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinas-shenzhou-21-crew-continues-with-scienc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:55:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/chinas-shenzhou-21-crew-continues-with-scienc/</guid><description>China&amp;rsquo;s Shenzhou-21 astronauts have steadily advanced scientific experiments in several fields aboard China&amp;rsquo;s space station over the past week.The crew consists of mission commander Zhang Lu and astronauts Wu Fei and Zhang Hongzhang. They have been in</description></item><item><title>The evolutionary upside of same-sex sex among primates - The Washington Post</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-evolutionary-upside-of-same-sex-sex-among/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:03:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-evolutionary-upside-of-same-sex-sex-among/</guid><description>New science suggests why monkeys and other primates engage in same-sex relations</description></item><item><title>A 47-year study reveals when fitness and strength start to fade - ScienceDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-47-year-study-reveals-when-fitness-and-stre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-47-year-study-reveals-when-fitness-and-stre/</guid><description>A long-running Swedish study has followed adults for nearly five decades, uncovering when physical decline truly begins. Fitness and strength start slipping around age 35, then worsen gradually with age. The encouraging twist: adults who began exercising late…</description></item><item><title>NASA's new moon rocket moves to the pad ahead of astronaut launch as early as February - KSL.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-moon-rocket-moves-to-the-pad-ahead/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:26:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-new-moon-rocket-moves-to-the-pad-ahead/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s giant new moon rocket moved to the launch pad Saturday in preparation for astronauts' first lunar fly-around in more than half a century.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Just Rewrote the Story of the Dinosaurs’ Final Days - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-rewrote-the-story-of-the-dino/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:54:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-just-rewrote-the-story-of-the-dino/</guid><description>Fossils reveal dinosaurs were flourishing in diverse ecosystems right up until the asteroid impact ended their reign.</description></item><item><title>Scientists issue warning that hidden 'ice volcanoes' could awaken: 'Talking about chaos' - Yahoo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-issue-warning-that-hidden-ice-volc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-issue-warning-that-hidden-ice-volc/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Awakening after a decade of slumber.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Insects listen to plants 'talking' before deciding where to lay eggs, breakthrough study shows - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/insects-listen-to-plants-talking-before-decid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:39:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/insects-listen-to-plants-talking-before-decid/</guid><description>Female moths avoid laying eggs on stressed plants that emit ultrasonic sounds. Instead, they choose silent, healthy plants.</description></item><item><title>Artemis 2 rocket rollout latest news: Giant NASA moon rocket arrives at launch pad - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-rocket-rollout-latest-news-giant-na/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/artemis-2-rocket-rollout-latest-news-giant-na/</guid><description>Saturday, Jan. 17, 2026: See our latest news and updates on NASA&amp;rsquo;s Artemis 2 moon rocket rollout to the launch pad.</description></item><item><title>Something Hidden Beneath Greenland Is Speeding Up Global Ice Loss - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-hidden-beneath-greenland-is-speedin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/something-hidden-beneath-greenland-is-speedin/</guid><description>A newly discovered feature beneath Greenland’s ice sheet could dramatically reshape predictions for future sea-level rise.</description></item><item><title>A New Census of Dwarf Galaxies Shows More Massive Black Holes than Previously Thought - Universe Today</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-census-of-dwarf-galaxies-shows-more-mas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-new-census-of-dwarf-galaxies-shows-more-mas/</guid><description>A new census of more than 8,000 galaxies finds active black holes rising in frequency with galaxy mass, jumping sharply in galaxies similar in mass to the Milky Way.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious iron 'bar' discovered in famous nebula - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-iron-bar-discovered-in-famous-nebu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-iron-bar-discovered-in-famous-nebu/</guid><description>A mysterious bar-shaped cloud of iron has been discovered inside the iconic Ring Nebula by a European team led by astronomers at University College London (UCL) and Cardiff University.</description></item><item><title>New insights into how the famed Antikythera Mechanism may have worked - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-insights-into-how-the-famed-antikythera-m/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-insights-into-how-the-famed-antikythera-m/</guid><description>New simulations suggest that the Antikythera Mechanism may have jammed within months, as small errors in the spacing.</description></item><item><title>This Breakthrough Image Sensor Lets Scientists See Tiny Details From Far Away - SciTechDaily</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-breakthrough-image-sensor-lets-scientist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:16:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-breakthrough-image-sensor-lets-scientist/</guid><description>A new lens-free imaging system uses software to see finer details from farther away than optical systems ever could before.</description></item><item><title>Northern Lights Forecast: 10 States Could See Aurora Borealis Saturday And Sunday - Forbes</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-10-states-could-see/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:48:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/northern-lights-forecast-10-states-could-see/</guid><description>The Northern Lights could be “quite pleasing to look at” this weekend in parts of the US due to fast solar winds, NOAA says.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover Greenland's 'Achilles heel' that is driving its rapid ice melt - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-greenlands-achilles-heel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-greenlands-achilles-heel/</guid><description>Soft sediments hidden beneath Greenland&amp;rsquo;s ice could accelerate glacier flow, speeding up ice loss and future sea level rise.</description></item><item><title>Scientists discover a plant that appears to have stolen genes from another species - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-plant-that-appears-to-h/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:47:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-plant-that-appears-to-h/</guid><description>A plant named Virectaria stellata has genetic traits foreign to its family, challenging the classic rules of plant inheritance.</description></item><item><title>NASA rolls out Artemis II craft ahead of crewed lunar orbit - NPR</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-rolls-out-artemis-ii-craft-ahead-of-crew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:12:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasa-rolls-out-artemis-ii-craft-ahead-of-crew/</guid><description>Mission Artemis plans to send Americans to the moon for the first time since the Nixon administration.</description></item><item><title>This is SPARDA: A self-destruct, self-defense system in bacteria that could be a new biotech tool - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-is-sparda-a-self-destruct-self-defense-s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/this-is-sparda-a-self-destruct-self-defense-s/</guid><description>A bacterial defense system called SPARDA employs kamikaze-like tactics to protect cells and could be useful in future biotechnologies.</description></item><item><title>Startup company wants to light up the night skies with reflected sunlight - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/startup-company-wants-to-light-up-the-night-s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:40:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/startup-company-wants-to-light-up-the-night-s/</guid><description>A company called Reflect Orbital wants to illuminate the Earth after sunset with orbital sky mirrors, raising alarm bells.</description></item><item><title>Most detailed map yet of Antarctica under the ice - Boing Boing</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-detailed-map-yet-of-antarctica-under-the/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-detailed-map-yet-of-antarctica-under-the/</guid><description>Researchers used satellite data and computer models of glacial movements to create a new map of Antarctica as it rests deep beneath the ice. The high-resolution imagery reveals the frozen…</description></item><item><title>Study finds albumin, the most abundant blood protein, acts as a shield against deadly fungal infections - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/study-finds-albumin-the-most-abundant-blood-p/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/study-finds-albumin-the-most-abundant-blood-p/</guid><description>Scientists at the Institute of Molecular Biology and Biotechnology (IMBB-FORTH) and the University of Crete, together with collaborators from Greece, Europe, the U.S., and India, have discovered a novel role of albumin, the most abundant protein in human bloo…</description></item><item><title>Japan Just Shut Down a Spacecraft That Cheated Death for 10 Years, Here's What It Saw on Venus - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-just-shut-down-a-spacecraft-that-cheate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/japan-just-shut-down-a-spacecraft-that-cheate/</guid><description>It was Japan’s first leap beyond Earth orbit, and it didn’t go as planned.</description></item><item><title>Mysterious Underwater 'Atlantis' Is Like a Lost City in The Ocean - ScienceAlert</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-underwater-atlantis-is-like-a-lost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mysterious-underwater-atlantis-is-like-a-lost/</guid><description>In the shimmering blue waters off Japan&amp;rsquo;s Yonaguni Island lies a geological wonder.</description></item><item><title>1 month until a 'ring of fire' annular solar eclipse puts on a show — mostly for penguins - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1-month-until-a-ring-of-fire-annular-solar-ec/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/1-month-until-a-ring-of-fire-annular-solar-ec/</guid><description>The first solar eclipse of the year will take place on Feb. 17, 2026.</description></item><item><title>Myth of wormholes and the quantum meaning of Einstein-Rosen Bridge - Interesting Engineering</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/myth-of-wormholes-and-the-quantum-meaning-of/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/myth-of-wormholes-and-the-quantum-meaning-of/</guid><description>A new study goes back to the original problem Einstein and Rosen were tackling and reinterprets it using modern ideas from quantum theory—especially how time works at the smallest scales.</description></item><item><title>Science news this week: ISS medical evacuation, Mars Sample Return canceled, and woolly rhino flesh found in permafrost wolf - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/science-news-this-week-iss-medical-evacuation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/science-news-this-week-iss-medical-evacuation/</guid><description>Jan. 17, 2026: Our weekly roundup of the latest science in the news, as well as a few fascinating articles to keep you entertained over the weekend.</description></item><item><title>Astronauts’ Brains Are Being Displaced - Futurism</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-brains-are-being-displaced-futuris/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/astronauts-brains-are-being-displaced-futuris/</guid><description>Researchers found that the brain &amp;ldquo;shifts upward and backward within the skull following spaceflight,&amp;rdquo; a new wrinkle for future space travel.</description></item><item><title>A Yellowstone National Park Caldera Is Uplifting For The First Time In Years - IFLScience</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-yellowstone-national-park-caldera-is-uplift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/a-yellowstone-national-park-caldera-is-uplift/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s an area bigger than Chicago, and it seems to be inflating. So should we worry?</description></item><item><title>Alone in Space, a Chinese Astronaut Heard Something Knock on His Capsule 300 KM Above Earth - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/alone-in-space-a-chinese-astronaut-heard-some/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/alone-in-space-a-chinese-astronaut-heard-some/</guid><description>What Yang Liwei heard during China’s first crewed spaceflight still defies physics, sensors, and every known explanation.</description></item><item><title>Weird Jet Geometry Around 3I/ATLAS in Hubble Images from January 14, 2026 - Avi Loeb – Medium</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weird-jet-geometry-around-3i-atlas-in-hubble/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/weird-jet-geometry-around-3i-atlas-in-hubble/</guid><description>A new set of six images, taken by the Hubble Space Telescope on January 14, 2026, show the brightness map of the glowing halo surrounding…</description></item><item><title>How much of your body could you lose — and still survive? - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-much-of-your-body-could-you-lose-and-st/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-much-of-your-body-could-you-lose-and-st/</guid><description>Five vital organs are essential for life, but survival is more medically complex.</description></item><item><title>‘Over the next hour, it’s dispatched, dismantled and butchered, piece by piece.’ This may be the most savage ambush attack we’ve ever heard - BBC Wildlife Magazine</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/over-the-next-hour-its-dispatched-dismantled/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:49:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/over-the-next-hour-its-dispatched-dismantled/</guid><description>Discover a delicate alliance between shrub, fungus and tiny forest guardians in the Amazonian understorey</description></item><item><title>NASA’s SpaceX Crew-11 to Discuss Space Station Science Mission - NASA (.gov)</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-spacex-crew-11-to-discuss-space-station/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:19:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-spacex-crew-11-to-discuss-space-station/</guid><description>After 167 days in space, the crew members of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-11 mission will hold a news conference at 2:15 p.m. EST, Wednesday, Jan. 21, at the agency’s</description></item><item><title>Crew-11 astronauts arrive in Houston after 1st-ever medical evacuation from ISS - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/crew-11-astronauts-arrive-in-houston-after-1s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/crew-11-astronauts-arrive-in-houston-after-1s/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;All crew members remain stable.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Indra Group writes off damaged SpainSat NG 2 - SpaceNews</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/indra-group-writes-off-damaged-spainsat-ng-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/indra-group-writes-off-damaged-spainsat-ng-2/</guid><description>The operator of a Spanish military communications satellite that suffered a “space particle” strike has written off the spacecraft.</description></item><item><title>Satellites Capture the Hidden World Beneath Antarctica’s Ice - Gizmodo</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellites-capture-the-hidden-world-beneath-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/satellites-capture-the-hidden-world-beneath-a/</guid><description>A new map of the landscape beneath the continent&amp;rsquo;s ice sheet reveals a previously undiscovered terrain.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Reveal Why Humans Lost Their Fur, And It’s Not What You Think - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-humans-lost-their-fur-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-reveal-why-humans-lost-their-fur-a/</guid><description>Scientists uncover the genetic “off switches” that made humans lose their fur.</description></item><item><title>Liquid gears could challenge 5,000 years of mechanical engineering - TechSpot</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/liquid-gears-could-challenge-5000-years-of-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/liquid-gears-could-challenge-5000-years-of-me/</guid><description>The study, published January 13 in Physical Review Letters, replaces the metal or plastic cogs of conventional gears with controlled flows of liquid. In their experiments, NYU&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Scientists Uncover Hidden Earthquake Threat Lurking Beneath Northern California’s Fault Zone - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-hidden-earthquake-threat-l/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-uncover-hidden-earthquake-threat-l/</guid><description>Tiny, nearly undetectable earthquakes beneath Northern California are offering scientists new insights into the complex tectonic processes at play in the region’s most dangerous fault zones.</description></item><item><title>Neutralizing extracellular electron transport disarms antibiotic-resistant bacteria, restores healing in chronic wounds - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/neutralizing-extracellular-electron-transport/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/neutralizing-extracellular-electron-transport/</guid><description>An international team of scientists, led by Nanyang Technological University, Singapore (NTU Singapore), has discovered a new method that could speed up the healing of chronic wounds infected by antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</description></item><item><title>Mars Has A Massive Impact On Earth’s Climate, New Study Suggests - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-has-a-massive-impact-on-earths-climate-n/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/mars-has-a-massive-impact-on-earths-climate-n/</guid><description>New research reveals that Mars’ gravity quietly stabilizes Earth’s climate.</description></item><item><title>Imaging technique captures ultrafast electron and atom dynamics in chemical reactions - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-technique-captures-ultrafast-electron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:20:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/imaging-technique-captures-ultrafast-electron/</guid><description>During chemical reactions, atoms in the reacting substances break their bonds and re-arrange, forming different chemical products. This process entails the movement of both electrons (i.e., negatively charged particles) and nuclei (i.e., the positively charge…</description></item><item><title>Why Mars is Actively Manufacturing Poison - Universe Today</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-mars-is-actively-manufacturing-poison-uni/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/why-mars-is-actively-manufacturing-poison-uni/</guid><description>Chemistry on other worlds varies widely from that on Earth. Much of Earth’s chemistry is driven by well-understood processes, which typically involve water and heat in some form. Mars lacks both of those features, which makes how some of its chemicals formed …</description></item><item><title>85 Remarkably Preserved Human Footprints Have Emerged on a Moroccan Beach - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/85-remarkably-preserved-human-footprints-have/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/85-remarkably-preserved-human-footprints-have/</guid><description>While exploring a quiet beach in northern Morocco, a team of scientists spotted what looked like ancient human footprints in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover a Hidden World Thriving with Life in Earth’s Driest Desert - Indian Defence Review</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-hidden-world-thriving-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-a-hidden-world-thriving-w/</guid><description>Scientists have uncovered a thriving ecosystem beneath the Atacama Desert&amp;rsquo;s surface.</description></item><item><title>NASA's Mars Sample Return is dead, leaving China to retrieve signs of life from the Red Planet - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-mars-sample-return-is-dead-leaving-chin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/nasas-mars-sample-return-is-dead-leaving-chin/</guid><description>NASA&amp;rsquo;s plans for Mars sample return are effectively cancelled as part of a bill approved by the U.S. Congress, ending efforts to collect Perseverance rover samples that could contain evidence of alien life.</description></item><item><title>3D-printed low-voltage-driven ciliary hydrogel microactuators - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/3d-printed-low-voltage-driven-ciliary-hydroge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:54:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/3d-printed-low-voltage-driven-ciliary-hydroge/</guid><description>3D-printed gel microcilia arrays printed by two-photon polymerization and composed of a soft acrylic acid-co-acrylamide hydrogel with a nanometre-scale network structure are shown to respond to low-voltage electrical stimuli within milliseconds, ena…</description></item><item><title>In the stomach of a mummified wolf pup, scientists find DNA from a woolly rhinoceros - NBC News</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-the-stomach-of-a-mummified-wolf-pup-scient/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:36:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/in-the-stomach-of-a-mummified-wolf-pup-scient/</guid><description>Inside the stomach of an ancient wolf puppy found entombed in Siberian permafrost, scientists discovered meat from a woolly rhinoceros — and sequenced its genome.</description></item><item><title>SpaceX breaks pad turnaround record at Cape Canaveral with midday Starlink launch - Spaceflight Now</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-breaks-pad-turnaround-record-at-cape-c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:27:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/spacex-breaks-pad-turnaround-record-at-cape-c/</guid><description>None</description></item><item><title>Detailed map reveals groundwater levels across the U.S. - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/detailed-map-reveals-groundwater-levels-acros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:21:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/detailed-map-reveals-groundwater-levels-acros/</guid><description>How much fresh water is in the United States? It&amp;rsquo;s a tough question, since most of the water is underground, accessible at varying depths. In previous decades, it&amp;rsquo;s been answered indirectly from data on rainfall and evaporation. Knowing how much groundwater i…</description></item><item><title>Jupiter's hidden depths: Simulation suggests planet holds 1.5 times more oxygen than the sun - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-hidden-depths-simulation-suggests-pl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:36:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/jupiters-hidden-depths-simulation-suggests-pl/</guid><description>Spectacular clouds swirl across the surface of Jupiter. These clouds contain water, just like Earth&amp;rsquo;s, but are much denser on the gas giant—so thick that no spacecraft has been able to measure exactly what lies beneath.</description></item><item><title>Dominant contribution of Asgard archaea to eukaryogenesis - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dominant-contribution-of-asgard-archaea-to-eu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/dominant-contribution-of-asgard-archaea-to-eu/</guid><description>A survey of the reconstructed gene set of the last eukaryotic common ancestor shows a consistent link between Asgard archaea and the origin of numerous, functionally diverse eukaryotic genes, demonstrating the dominant Asgard contribution to eukaryogenes…</description></item><item><title>Retraction Note: Antibodies against endogenous retroviruses promote lung cancer immunotherapy - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/retraction-note-antibodies-against-endogenous/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/retraction-note-antibodies-against-endogenous/</guid><description>Nature - Retraction Note: Antibodies against endogenous retroviruses promote lung cancer immunotherapy</description></item><item><title>Little red dots as young supermassive black holes in dense ionized cocoons - Nature</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/little-red-dots-as-young-supermassive-black-h/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:06:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/little-red-dots-as-young-supermassive-black-h/</guid><description>The highest-quality JWST spectra reveal that little red dots are young supermassive black holes shrouded in dense cocoons of ionized gas, where electron scattering, not Doppler motions, broadens their spectral lines.</description></item><item><title>How Mars' ancient lakes grew shields of ice to stay warm as the Red Planet froze - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-mars-ancient-lakes-grew-shields-of-ice-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/how-mars-ancient-lakes-grew-shields-of-ice-to/</guid><description>The findings potentially solve the paradox of how liquid water seems to have persisted on Mars even when the climate grew too cold.</description></item><item><title>New Image of the Milky Way Reveals Massive Hidden Structures, What’s Out There? - The Daily Galaxy</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-image-of-the-milky-way-reveals-massive-hi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-image-of-the-milky-way-reveals-massive-hi/</guid><description>This new map of the galaxy is so detailed it’ll make your head spin.</description></item><item><title>New state of matter discovered in a quantum material - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-state-of-matter-discovered-in-a-quantum-m/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/new-state-of-matter-discovered-in-a-quantum-m/</guid><description>At TU Wien, researchers have discovered a state in a quantum material that had previously been considered impossible. The definition of topological states should be generalized.</description></item><item><title>Video captures a baby hummingbird behaving like a poisonous caterpillar to fool predators - Earth.com</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/video-captures-a-baby-hummingbird-behaving-li/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/video-captures-a-baby-hummingbird-behaving-li/</guid><description>A white-necked jacobin hummingbird chick surprises scientists, scaring away wasps by mimicking a poisonous caterpillar.</description></item><item><title>The universe should be packed with tiny galaxies — so where are they? - Space</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-universe-should-be-packed-with-tiny-galax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/the-universe-should-be-packed-with-tiny-galax/</guid><description>There may not be as nearly as many small galaxies in the early universe as astronomers predict there should be, which has big implications for the story of how our universe grew up.</description></item><item><title>T. rex grew up slowly: New study reveals 'king of dinosaurs' kept growing until age 40 - Phys.org</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/t-rex-grew-up-slowly-new-study-reveals-king-o/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/t-rex-grew-up-slowly-new-study-reveals-king-o/</guid><description>For decades, scientists have been counting annual growth rings—similar to tree rings—inside fossilized leg bones of Tyrannosaurus rex to estimate how old the giant carnivores were when they died and how quickly they grew to adulthood. The best estimates from …</description></item><item><title>Most complete Homo habilis skeleton ever found dates to more than 2 million years ago and retains 'Lucy'-like features - Live Science</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-complete-homo-habilis-skeleton-ever-foun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/most-complete-homo-habilis-skeleton-ever-foun/</guid><description>Scientists have revealed the most complete skeleton yet of our 2 million-year-old ancestor Homo habilis.</description></item><item><title>Scientists Discover Bizarre Form Of Water That’s Both Solid And Liquid - Study Finds</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-bizarre-form-of-water-tha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/scientists-discover-bizarre-form-of-water-tha/</guid><description>Scientists discover water that&amp;rsquo;s solid and liquid. Superionic ice found in lab could explain Uranus and Neptune&amp;rsquo;s bizarre magnetic fields.</description></item><item><title>When does the Nasa Moon mission launch and who are the Artemis II crew? - BBC</title><link>https://newsround.github.io/posts/when-does-the-nasa-moon-mission-launch-and-wh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:13:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newsround.github.io/posts/when-does-the-nasa-moon-mission-launch-and-wh/</guid><description>The first crewed Moon mission in 50 years could launch in February, preparing the way for a future landing.</description></item></channel></rss>